<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.61,0.166,0.325,0.367,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>All Fools' Day nt Canyon Ferry.
C'aayoti
Ferry,
At iho Canyon Ferry House). Iiepb by.
our old friend Cnnt. StalTord. is wont lo
meet occasionally tho Jolly bnrhelors of
mo Hujaeeni mines, wuu sot nroumi lltu
bnr.qunfl' their bovorog'cs nnil bewail lliclr
sad and lonoly lives of bachelorhood.
On Saturday evening, April 1st, whllo a
party of thoso dUcousnlato chap wero
engaged In Iho pastime mentioned. above,
a spanking team was drivHti. to tho par
lor door, by I. il. Tyler, ami by his side
sat n blooming and buxom lemule, who
wns politely, handed out of thu vehicle
nnd shown to tho parlor. A buz of nil
miration went up from tho crowd, nml
Mn Tyler wns interviewed ns to tho pn
ternlty and prdlgreo of tho lovely strnn
gor. These Inquiries wero snttuflcd by
thu stntntm nt that Mr. Stafford bail dls-
chnruetl his ittnlo cook, anu tho truly was
nn interesting widow, who lintl consen
ted to superintend tho cuisine affairs of
the household. Tho crowd otilotl v dron
ped olf their cabins, donned their "bllr-d."
shirts, shaved cl nu, nml dropped back
to the hotel, ono after nitothar, each ono
with it pnliiifntlng heart, nnd n quiet
chuckle to lil'tisell that ha- was looking
supremely smooth, and would recelrc
tho first introduction nnd smiles of the
widow. As they entered, Mr. Tyler
led their, one by one nnd presented them
to their fancied Idol, until the room wns
crowded with rivals, Captain Stafford,
wllh his eye on Iho knot-holo, tinted tho
happy countenances of tho baeholors,
nnd Iho witching smiles of tho widow,
whllo Tyler did tho nmlnblc. Tho
Judge of thu district, n happy, Jolly
bachelor, but, unfortunately, very thin
haired, borrowed n wig for tlio occnlon,
nnd appeared befose thv widow, with
his ours pinned back, nnd looking upon
tho minors with tho lofty contempt
which he felt bis position would give
him over bis rivals lo tho lair willow's
eyes. Tho guests having been all Intro
duced, Joo Stnirer, finally summoned
courngo to tako a sent by her sldo nml
engaged her in conversation but what
was his horror upon discovering tho
fair female gently raised her whlto skirts
nml shovo her hand Into tho pocket of n
greasy pair of buckskin brcechos, which
wero hidden by flowing garments, and
from which she hauled n plug of tobac
co, and pasFcd It to her admirer with a
winning smile, nnd tho polite invitation
of "Juo tuko n chaw Joo fell bnek iu
amazement, nml exclaimed, "Buys, if
this y'ar isn't Jim Fulsom iu pottlconts,
I'm a cnyuso." The April fool sell wns
then seen through, and Tyler had to
bent n hasty retreat, whllo thu supposed
widow niHilo her exit through tho bnek
door nnil hroko for tlic bush lo cscnpo
the wrnth of thu crowd. Tho Jtttlgo
now hicks only thirteen hnlrs of being
halt! headed, owing to the wrathful man
ner iu which hn ran his lingers through
bis thin locks, when ho learned that the
lovely widow was none olhor than Jim
Fulsnm, a smooth-faced miner, rigged
out for tho occasion. Helena Gazette.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=april+pranks+fools</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>NEWS OF THE DAT.
-Lord de Grey and Ripon bas been re-elect?
ed Grand Master of Free Masonry In England.
-'?BitU Bun" Bussell ls to accompany tho
Russian force to Khiva for the London Times.
The Russian government ls Bald to have spe?
cially invited "The Thunderer" to send a cor?
respondent.
-Two State elections will be held within a
week. On Wednesday. Rhode Island will
choose now State officials, and on Monday,
April 7| iLhe Connecticut election will take
place?
-By a new French law the sale of liquor lo
drunkard 3 or minors is punished by flue and
Imprisonment, and the cost ot being drnnk
and disorderly In public range] lrom five
francs lor a first offence to 750 francs and dis?
franchisement lor two years.
-Mr. E. N. Davis, a planter ol Mississippi,
has utilized a large portion of hitherto un?
productive land by dividing lt Into a dozen
small, farms and Importing twelve lam liles
lrom North Carolina to cultivate them on
abat-es.
-Miss Susan B. Anthony hos been voling
.ga'ln. The Rochester Union ls authority for
the statement that she voted at the election
In that cly recently, and that two other
"strong-minded women" also cast ballots.
Nobody was bold enough to challenge them.
-A new machine for carving on stone ls at?
tracting the attention of builders and others
in New York. It ls known as the "gear stone
ornamenting and surfacing machine." IC ia
claimed that it will do as mach work In a day 1
as one hundred men, and at a great saving In
coat. 'I
-Boston testifies to the "good side" o?
hnman nature, In the fact that, Bince the big
.blase, macy firms have been surprised at the
payment of debts long since outlawed and for-
gotten. An Instance ls told of the firm of j
which ex-Governor Cia fl lu is the head, who
Uara'Jost received $8000, the balance of a
debt, with Interest, which was settled in bank?
ruptcy many yean ago.
-The "Salary Steal is the na rm the news-
papers ef the North and East have generally
given to the late Increase of the pay of Con- I
gressmen. Among the BOW views given on
this subject by con.?cience-stricken or sens!- 1
tlve members of Congress is lo make capital
ont ol il at home by paying the sum of their
extra salary into the treasury ol the county In y
which they resldp. Not a few have done this,
lt ls said; and they intend to keep their action
a profound secret. The Albany Evening Jour?
nal announces that Congressman W. W.
Wheeler, of the seventeenth district of New
York,han refused his back pay. He drew the t
money, Invested lt in United States bonds and 1
then cancelled the bonds.
-The practice of leaving the gas lighted
In the city stores at night has been generally
adopted as the most effectual means of foiling
burglars. Exposure to the passing glance ot
policeman or passenger is supposed, and In
the generality of cases wisely supposed, to be
a more ample protection than the barred
doors and windows, and the utter darkness ot
old times. A case of bursary recently occnr- 1
red in one ol the most crowded parts of New I
York, however, which shows the futility of I
plans presumably the most secure. There,
ander the full glare of the gas light, before
toe magnificent building of the Young Men's
Christian Association, while an entertainment
waa going on and hacks were crowded belore
the door, a hack drove ap unnoticed, o? 1
course, among so many others, and a party of 1
men alighted; went boldly up lo the entrance
of-one ot the stores facing the street; entered 1
by means ellher of lalse keys or by quickly I
picking the look, abd-In the full blaze of the I
constantly burning gas selected what plunder 1
they desired, and drove ol. They were seen
by a number of persons, but so confident and
at ease were they that everybody supposed
they had a right to be there, and nobody at-
tempted to disturb them.
-The last scheme o? organized benevolence
ls the New York Diet Kitchen. Its objects is
to co-operate with the dispensaries in taking
care of the sick' poor. Any physician who has i
visited among the poor will testify that many, 1
very many, die who might be saved If nour- 1
lshlng food could be procured for them. In
the midst of a civilized community, where
thousands of dollars are dispensed each
month in charities, these people perish of J
whatweocuid aimost call starvation. They
are succored whon their wanta are made t
known to the benevolent, but this only hap- t
pens in Isolated, casen. The physician does 1
what he can, but his means are not sufficient j
to give food to his poorer patients ns well as 1
medicine, for il is usually the younger and j
les? wealthy of the profession who attend
these cases. Therelore this New York Diet 1
Kitchen has ample scope for Its exertions, 1
and ls a blessed charity. The association win 1
entaollsh in each of the dispensary districts 1
one or more "diet kitchens," from which, on 1
the r?quisition of the visiting physician,
property prepared food will be issued at such
times and in such quantities as may be sped-
fled.
-Frederick Greer, of New York, Is one of 1
those literary Bohemians who get up blogra-
ph les ol those who are emulous ol immortality e
of a more substantial kind iban Is given by
the prese. He was engaged in this Grub street
work when the great crash came which over?
whelmed Tweed and otners In a common min.
Unfortunately, be bad then the flattering bio?
graphy of the great ring-master in band. To
his pecuniary IOSB, however, Tweed was far
less Inclined to biographic honors ina i when
the work uas undertaken, and the courtly
and insinuating Greer first approached bim
OD the subject. He refused to pay tor the
tame that had trickled down from the pen of
the latter. Now Jay Gould proves recalci?
trant. His biography has been done to order
in the very best style. He contracted to take
ten copies of the book at one hundred and
fifty dollars per copy, which shows what a
genius, hitherto hld In obscurity, Mr. Greer
ls. Bo blgb did the latter rate his ability that
even this was not satisfactory. He alleges
that Jay Gould ordered more copies, and he,
consequently, wanta more pay. They have
bad a little suit about lt, aod Jay Gould offers
to compromise.
April Fool.
The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
aod as impossible to determine as the birth?
day of the first fool who marred Nature's
original design of intellectual Man. We
trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
its birth ba files research. We are forced to
admit its existence, without being able to
assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer?
tainly carried its memory in all their con?
quests. Its observance was long cherished
among numer?os nations. Abandoned to
the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
refinement, Momus seems to revenge him?
self by selecting the most elevated and dig?
nified objects for bis practical jokes. Nor
man, cor nation, nor things visible, nor
things invisible can elude bis satire. Nature
herself seems convulsed with his sly sport.
Her groans over a fallen race turn into in?
voluntary, hysterical laughter at the bidding
of this giant Harlequin, on whose kingdom
tbe Ban never sets.
The most pathetic scenes provoke the
wildest mirth. We see men of bonor and
repaie taking advantage of National schemes
to secare private emolument; dividends the
only consideration, the divisor of no conse?
quence. April Fool 1 Divisor of scheme,
plus dividends, laughing at his dupes, and,
thanking Heaven he is not like other men,
proving bis integrity by tbe faith of his
fr ?en dB. April Fool
The rightful Government of Louisiana
using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti?
ling Kellogg platform striking the first
blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
sending representatives to the Union at
large, convinced that her distress must be
of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
balance cac not be determined; giving a
gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of j
bowling it down. April Fool
England's tories and whigs doing their
best to destroy the ablest minister of the
Crown on the question of the Irish Univer?
sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
"cummin" while neglecting the weightier j
matters of tbe law. April Fool
France with Thiers more iban king, shoot?
ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la R?publique 1
"A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
April Fool
Ukraine peasants revolting against an
?utocrat who owns half the Continent of
Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
br the mere chance of being discharged at
heir masters' heads. April Fool
Each nation convinced that "the Par lia
"mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
:ree. April Fool 1
Each sect persuaded that the whole world
viii soon have bat one Faith, and that Faith
ta own especial creed. April Fool 1
Honor, probity, patriotism, troth and
rirtae sb/J! prove'a successful candidate
tgaiost rampaot Vice. April Fool I
All the world surging, restless, doped and
laping, cries: April Fooll
Deep calling onto deep in awfal sport-all
.be waves and waterspouts shoaling in
nocking derision April Fool I And men in
childish rage and impotent wrath yell to
?ach other and the Universe at large: Toa
ire-April Fool 1</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.156,1.024,0.236,0.267,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>ON ALL FOOL'S BAT
i
Brainy Men Ten of First of April
Fancies.
Actor, Artist, BatlrUt, Lawyer, Preacher.
Etc, All Have Something to bar
About This, the Fool
Catcher's Day.
COPTBIOHi; 183 L
H E stage is in
Eomo measure
responsible for
All Fool's day.
So the histo.
rians tell us.
They say it
grew out of an
old Easter
miracle play in
Irhich the sending of Christ from An
bas to Caiaphas and from Pilot to
Herod was the basis of the mediaeval
Jramatist's plot. But I don't think
Hie stage has stuck to its offspring.
We actors are a serious lot of people,
particularly the comedians among us,
for paradoxical as it may seem, acting
Is all work and no play, and conse
quently Jack is a dull boy. We would
"MSTEIt, TXEASE GIVE ME A IIFT. JTLI.
TOU?"
T like to April fool our manager, perhaps,
but we don't April fool ourse'ves, be
cause that would be rather cruel.
I have outgrown the frolicsomenes
of April 1, of course; still I always look
carefully after my coat tails on that
day. And I greatly enjoy the motley
of those who are careless about their
parraental caudals during the Feast of
All Fools. The sight makes me feel
quite a boy again, for we youngsters
used to do that sort of thing in Phila
delphia thirty years ago. 0 yes, I did
It, too. I believe that some of the live
lier children of Philadelphia do it yet,
and have vitality and energy enough
left to laugh at the result, as a comio
paragrapher would say.
The most foolhardy of all the tricks
which I can recall in connection with
this carnival of jeering and nonsense
Is one that I have never seen played
Eince I was old enough to require two
digits to express my age. A bag and
two boys were the ingredients of the
trick, and it never failed to 6core a
great success on a quiet side street.
One boy got into the bag and the other
Stood by it waiting for the victim. The
rest of the boys who were "in on the
ground floor" were hiding in hallways
and doors and behind trucks across
the street. An innocent citizen came
W sauntering along. The boy who had
hold of the neck of the bag stopped
him with a "Say, mister, please give
toe a lift, will yer?" The innocent cit
izen usually acquiesced and took hold
of the bag to land it on the youngster's
shoulder. Just as he got it fairly in
his hands the boy in the bag suddenly
kicked and screamed. Innocent vic
tim, thinking it a bagful of wildcats
or hypnas. let go quickly and ran off
with palpitating heart and hair on end.
while all the boys across the street
pursued him with a villainous chorus
of "April fool 1 April fool! Wash
.your face and go to sclioU" or
something to the same effect. It
Talways seemed to me that the joke
was really on the boy in the bag;
he was sometimes dropped hastily
and heavily and was hurtand occa
sionally the April-fooled citizen gave
him a thrashing besides for being too
funny. But it was an effective trick.
and often an old codger lingered in the
shadow on the opposite pavement to
witness and enjoy the sport. You have
seen a man try to kick a plug hat full
of pig iron over into tho next state
Trell, bis discomfiture was no greater
IT MADE AIM SMD.E.
Good Ola reliOK Ali, hoT it warms ri7
bcart to see them playing their littlo inuoccm
tricks on the Brst or Apnlt Used to do It my
self when I was a toy. But ibey caa't fool me,
though I'm too oU a bird lor fiat.
than that of the man whoso blood was
frozen in his heart by the unexpected
scream emitted by the occupant of the
bag. Laugh? It would make a tomb
stone roll over in a fit of hysterics.
Jonx Drew.
fOMETIlIES IT GIVES PLEASURE TO OTHERS.
It doesn't seem right that the firs
flay of a month so full of pretty things
j is April is should be inseparably con
w nectcd in our minds with empty ard
dilapidated pocketbooks with string
in d-small-boy attachments, di&rep
ntable hats with bricks underneath
them, long streamers hanging from
l nnsuspecting coattails, door bells
rung by invisible hands, and all the
other dear old pleasantries that we
know by heart. And we should prob.
ibly have had a society for the pre
rention of Anril fool iokes Ions aso if
It were not for the pleasure that call
aren gel out of them.
When a certain boy of my acquaint-
fcnee on April Grst. before breakfast,
Informs me that somebody is waiting
ft;' see me in the library, not for the
world would I refuse to go downstairs
and pretend extreme surprise at find
ing nobody there. Nor would any
thing induce me to decline the suspicious-looking,
cotton-filled piece of
candy which is shortly after offered
V.T. a fmnll rrirl I know. I bitA
UlUiD O
End- Hotter SS6? itLISSrularly i
every year, ana Mr. rfat Gooxnvm or
Mr. Francis Wilson would be glad if
he could raise such a shout of laughter
as easily and unfailingly.
Apropos of this train of thought
there is a little picture of mine in Puck,
published some years since, which will
perhaps bear transplanting here, and
which I subjoin.
Fbedeiuck Buitn Oppeb.
"de bazoo" is suggested.
If yer want a good joke on some ot
yer frcn's, give dem de razoo, see?
Dat's de way dey do in Xew York oa
April Fool day.
Yer work it dis way:
Suppose a man owes yer ten dollars
and won't pay yen Go see him and
ask him for it. He ses he ain't got it.
Wipe de floor wid 'him and take all de
cash in his pockets and when he kicks
apologize and se.y yer didn't mean fer
ter hurt him it'b April Tool, see? Den
yer needn't pive him de money back,
'cause he owe s it, yer see? Course yer
don't want ter try de razoo on anyone
not under yer size, see?
Den yer kin pay off all yer old
grudges de same way. Or if yer hun-
gry and ain't got no money walk inter
de restrint, see, and eat all yer kin,
and say it's April Fool, see, and run
out widout payin' nothin'.
Dat's de racket fer April Fool de
razoo. Steve Erodie.
TO LESSEN THE DEVTL'S FOOLS.
I am abked for a sentiment concern
ing April Fool's day and pause in the
whirl and rush of a righteous warfare
to say that in my opinion time is far
too valuable and important a factor
for a moment to be lost in foolish jest
ing or senseless joking. The world,
especially in these days, is in far too
critical and dangerous a position, so
cially and religiously, to allow of a
man with average sense to saj' noth
ing of those who have consecrated
brains to indulge in any other than
profitable and upright intercourse.
It is a personal relief to me to feel
that in our ranks seventeen hundred
officers and sixteen thousand unpaid
local workers will be pushing with
might and main of soul an enterprise
which upholds sincerity and the ne
cessity of lessening the devil's fools.
Ballington Booth.
A CHA3IPI0X FOR THE DAT.
Before stating what jokes seem to
me timely, and enjc&abJe ior this
S&-
WIPE DE FLOOB WID niil."
April Fool's day, I cannot resist th
temptation to say that I think the
spirit of the holiday itself hat always
been singularly misunderstocd. The
day is really to be deemed a pause in
time's serious flight, when folly could
with propriety travesty wisdom, and
set the world smiling. As it is, the
first of April has come to be deemed a
nuisance, wheu its observance is not
don away with entirely. April Fool's
day is sadly in need of soue one to
champion it and xestoi e it to its right
ful place in the calendar. It is not
simply the day on which the boys and
girls may make fools of their elders
with impunity. I suspect that there
was a time when it was regarded
rightly, far away as that time seems
to us now. Then the old people put
aside their serious looks and grew
younger instead of older.
If it takes a wise man to be a fool,
surely April first is the feast day
of the saircs. when thev can act on
Shakcspsare's admonition: "Mingle a
little folly with your wisdom."
As for those jokes which seem to mi
good and appropriate to the dav it
should always be understood that the
element of surprise is the essential
thing. Novelty is wit. Jokes must not
bo cruel pranks, otherwise the day
would ba given up to a general hazing
of everybody. The most successful of
April Fool jokes would be to surprise
one's friends by a change of character.
What a rare joke it would be for the
confirmed miser to bestow a dowry
upon that niece of his who needs only
a little money to marry the lad of her
choice. If all the cranks would put
rside their hobbies for a day, what fun
it would be for the rest of us.
This kind of joke can be carried out
ad finitum and would never fail to bo
successful. Let the tippler remain
sober to-day just as a joke. The skin
flint employer can have a lark with
his clerk by granting that increase of
salary that has been talked about so
long. Let the clergyman I say it
reverently preach a sermon only an
hour long to-day instead of one of
four hours' duration. I am convinced
that the idea would meet with success.
People too old for jokes on April
Fool's day? Xouscnc. Even the gray
heads can have their joke. The repro
bate roue can go to church this morn
ing and explain that it is all a joke on
his part. Many a man is ashamed to do
a good thing because it is so unusual
with him that it would give him un
pleasant prominence. But he can do
it to-day and escape with the admis
sion that it is his April fool joke. I
am glad the day comes on Sunday this
year. B. Gillax.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024442/1896-03-29/ed-1/?sp=17&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.195,0.753,0.368,0.415,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>THE WASHINGTON TIMES hmmu
Part 3
"WASHINGTON, D. C., SUNDAY MORNING, MAliCII 29, 1S0G.
LS THESE MORTALS
AN
DYLL
APRL
WHAT
BE
:,0
lift
I t
I II i fc
a.CE upon a time" in truUi,
quite recently then.' were
fomefislilliat were haul to be
of greatdepth, hothas to t heir
bailiwick and intelligence.
One Would e-neso frnm llilc
description that they were taw-fiMi, that
Is, wise-saw fish, hut they were not. They
were eimpij- hucKeru; yec mey knew It
was April 1'ool'b Day.
On tljat Fame
day a man went
Fooling the Fishes-Bait 3SSa J "J
Without Hooks. sot him down on
the wharf and let
downhisliiicand
bait. The water
was clear and he
could ee the
6uckers blinking
and winking at
each other and
rubbing their
nuouts, against
tlie tempting
bait.
"HeiliinkKhe's
run up against
the highland
suckcr."mid fin
ny No. 1 to. scaly
No. and noo
dle No. :t i early
swallowed the
bait at short
range laughing
at the sucker at
the o'lier nil of
the'ne. But he
fWifdrifJitalong
till the fun grew
hot.imd (hen he
Tilled his pipe
and hauled up
his line.
Nov.h-'reisa
moral 'nthisMo
ry. Th'-re was
no jojK in the
merry li'-l.er-m
a n s b a i r,
wlui h goes to
show that peo
ple who .ue too
wise to "Lite"
very often get
left. e en as the
fish didn't know
a good Uiing
when it was in
dubitably i n
their line.
And on that
same day in the
same generation,
a spinster lady
declined to ojX'ii
a letter, good
forthisdayonlv,
no rain checks. Is
sued, which letter
con tninoda bona
fide healed pro
IKaltj,.Uheand MieMioukl tarry
togetlier at Jeri
cho, or an j place
elM- where there
was good tarry
ing, swooning
and crooning in
the thick after
noon iK-rfiimeof
lot uracil orange
blos.-om. And
the next da j the
died.
Oil the 1st of
April, la-t, a
joung wieacre,
who lives on
New Ilauipclure
aieuuc. received
a letter ,y f.pe.
cial im-sMMiger.
It wab fcuper
bcribedina plain
round hand, and
in the left-hand
corner were the
words "Pmate;
marked down to
10, former val
ue &o." The
letter was re
turned to the
writer, with the
remark on the
margin. "Don't
need any spring
clothes." The
lot terrnerel j con
tained a part
Iiaynient of $20
on a $30 -debt
or honor" which
accrued from
lost borrowed
chips
So when the
bride of only
two Aprils tcle
Kraphed to her
husband In New
i'ork from
"Washington the
thrilling mc-s-fiage.
"Two ana
all's well," lie re
ceived it, "Two
and all swell."
He replied 'Had
eight. -a j self and
feel much swcll
er." She ws a
little -mrpi-ised,
to be sure, and
whei icy grow
up she will tell
the twins about
the mind reading
capaeu y cf a
handsome clerk
of the Oimis Of
fice. These hlMorl
calcaes are not
ed by way of pre
lude to i he slate
ment rhat April
Fools' Day Is
again with us, or
will be on "Wed
nesday next. Af
ter these i-ad ex
amples of mind
read mg, it will
be only t tie more
perplexing to
discover the dif
ference between
looking the gift
horse !u the
mouth and the
gift horse him
self should lie
gallop up to the
door.
One half of the
world will begin
on "Wednesday to,
play pranks on
Uie other half,
and it is an in
teresting day be
cause we have
only two such
days on Uie cal
endar, the other
being Talentine
Day. Election
day Miotild. per
haps, be added,
buttoallofthem
FaUier A braham
undoubtedly re
ferred when he
got off the fa
mous bit or phi
losophy, "You
can fool all of
the people tome
of Uie time, etc.,
etc. otr.
The misfortunes of the day are hke the
premonlUons of fctieezeg. STou know they
are coming, but you can't prevent their
arrival, so It is much better to Miecze
at once, even If your mouth Is full of
turtle soup, than to fight against the in
evitable. It Is better even to take in
the bundle on Uie doorstep than to kick
Ef 55
Vtr
JEm)
Some Old and New Jokes Suggested
The Times for Next Wednesday.
Of Course the Small Boys' WeMried and Proven Schemes Wil
Hold Sway, hut There Is a Chance to Extend Them
into Municipal and National Life
TH SUMS
uoke
by
v d y
f art" and 'Teller." havinsr done -which ha
strode oat of the room. leaviojr the second
fiddle- to play out the score.
It will probably be a bad d7 for king
makers, ho wevcrgooditniay be rorpotitical
fctol makers. In a quiet, coay room In a
Philadelphia hotel there are gathered
together the elect of the Warwlcka
of this day and generation, fore
most among whom are Piatt, Quay and
C I ar krer
"V.
fffj VfLLET vairR
STRlFHi iu v
rti r SL. x pA.
.,mn jr.r.
iA the o rryki ittL -T Ak
Some Ancient and Honorable April Fool Jokes.
Uie little stranger Into the street. There
may be millions awaiting the long-lost
heir before jou die.
The compliments of the season are firstly
due to Uie three destinies of "Washington.
Messrs. Koss, Truesdell and Poweil. Tliej
will do a land-office business on April
Fools' I)a They will be bitting at a Uel
shazzar's feast, and lo' there appears on
Uie wall a strange bcroll in the Kalorama
dialect.
The Attorney for the District and the
interpreter of the clastic law of the local
Medcs and Persians Is called in and he is
promised fine raiment and an amethystine
ring ir he expounds the letters of fire on the
wall. Kefer.'ncc to Uie snap shot of the oc
casion will be found in the margin or tins
page. Of course, tins maj not happen, but
it ought to, which isa much better considera
tion. There is one place in the United States
where eerj thing can happen, proidcd
always it is not something practical even
will enforce the rules and order the gal
leries to be cleared.
Mr. Morrill of Maine Mr. President, I
have lieen llfty jcars in the Senate in the
ambassadorial capacity of a Senator from
Maine, atrl I have ncer jet heard
The Toreign Voice I am a talker my-f-clf.
(Renewed applause from Uie gal
leries.) The President The sergeant-ai-arms will
arrest that obnoxious peiaonage.
The galleries are cleared, and the ser-
whlch to exclude the April Foots Day dis
turbers of the White House peace.
In the mind's ee, without even a warm
application of the Roentgen ray, it is easy
to see the fighters against follv seated at
the table in what the President told the
delegation of Baptist ministers was his
"workshop." Ip a certain sense, tin-, is
true, because It is there lie saws wood. The
President casts aside carefully all tlie
suspected letters and puts all the packagi-v
Iu a tub of water near him on the floor
to kill the microbes and anymcidental dyna
mite. The morning is passed away pleas
antly, and he asks for a cigar.
"What kind, extellenzaZ" queries F. A.
H in one-third Spau'sn and two-thirtls
Iiayard.
"A Duke of Veragua," replies excellenza.
and Fie-Tt!oi!sard-DolIars-a-Year in the
future opens a new Ijok. The rest of this
story is done in black and white pictonally
on this Seventeenth Page. In scene the sec
ond the unfortunate bot-opener la on his
tr
iiiiinwifi ll'ir i5j
4m
April 1 at the District Building:.
A Neat Little April Eiiect in the Senate.
a Joke. To guess the name of that place
is not as hard as guessing the number of
five black beans in a transparent jar. It
is the United States Senate,
In the afternoon of "Wednesday next,
after the morning hour, the Cutian olla
podrida will be in full blast. Senator
Lodge will hae spoken on the letter that
never came to Secretary Olney, Senator
Mills will hae taken Cuba "vi et aimls,"
and Senator Hale will have delivered his
accustomed eulogy on the late Don Canovas
de Quixote. The listening Senate ib suddenly
startled by a thin foreign voice, which
says, "I'm something of a talker mjself."
Applause breaks out in the galleries.
The President of the benatc-If these
demonstrations are repeated the President
vtw n
A Joke on the Republican RiBg-sters
geantr.it-arms and Firsts Assistant Stewart
rush up into the peanut' reservation. They
return and report that the miscreant has
escaped.
The Presldent-The Senate "will be In
order.
Mr. Chandler As I was saying, Mr.
President, I
The Torclgn Voice I am something of a
talker mjself.
Nothing could exceed -the commoUon in
the Senate when its courtesy was thus sat
upon and spat upon by this intruder. It
was the eagle eje of Senator Sherman
of "Our Foreign Relations" Committee
that discovered the intruder, winch was
quietly looking askance at the President
out of its white-winged eye, a beautiful
queen red and gold parrot direct from Bar
celona. "It Is a Spanish spy," declared Mr.
Lodge.
"It should be shot at drum head," as
severated the fiery Tennessean.
"Try it from the clock," said Mr. Mills.
"Willi the Presidential gun," added Mr.
Hill of New 1'ork. i
Suggestions, however, do not kill birds
at long range, and. the pages were on the
qui vive of excitement lo be let loose on
the most consistent talker at that moment
In the Senate. They were eager for the
bird to fly down and light on tlie bald head
of some Senator, like the eaglathat alighted
on the head of the husband of Tanaquii.
But the spy did not move, keeping his
sinister eye on the Vice President, and
evidently getting ready to sing his unwel
come song again.
Mr. Lodge Eutcka, lMr. President: Per
scalam ad avem.
The President Gqod; has the scrgeant-at-arms
a ladder about him?
The sergeant-at-arms at -once procured
Uie ladder on which he climbed into office,
placed it up against the lintels of the' east
door, and reached for ithe parrot, which
was seated on the Senatorial clock a la
Poc's raven.
Did the sergeant-at-arms land the bird?
Not on your negative. The bird had a
string tied to him and. he'-was hauled aver
the parapet, and tle small boy at the oUicr,
end of the string simply hauled In the fes-'
the Spaniard, opened a -gallery door and
went down stairiand .filled himself full of
apple pic.
This may not happen.but It ought to. A
son of one or the surviiors of the Ford's
Theater disaster would be tlie logical perpe
trator of this lecfure by the pariot to the
Senate.
Too mucU .sympathy cannot be -wasted be
tween now and "Wcdnesdaj'onthefeeilngs of
the Chief Magistrate "with respect to his
mail and exprc packages on the day -we
celebrate. Thcrofhavc plrendj' been con
ferences between him anci Fldus Achates
Henrlcus Tiberius on taii; beet manner in. I
rjtt&n.
knees ascrvatmg in shattered sentences to
the accusation or the Potentate of the Poto
mac that he smelt treason in the tainted
gale.
"if third term doesn't go, lese mnjeste
doe-." thunders the man of destiny.
"1 know it doe?, Your Majesty, but by
the saber of my father I knov not who is
the nuereant, unless it be some godless
member of the 1. W. X. M. of the Occi
dental provinces."
"And who are they, caitiff?"
l-eonie who Need Missionaries, Ex
cellcnza." "Then, bj- mj- halidom, they shall have
Uiem galore before the ides or April."
And with that His Mijestj-seized bis tab
lets and wrote deep in the wax"'Colorado."
"North Dakota," "Oklahoma," "Stew-
til
r
Somebody's Little Joke en Groyer.
Little Willie's OrieinaJ
Idea.
U (!L
''r
T'&ryS "U
misfortune "vr K7 ""7 JaB
trying to J "M
doiitwheth- X Nr"V 1 H
there's a V A V l
-"vvr-' "rv.-oB
A-N1
sV: V-
J
f
.r
They are not
afraid of any
sword of Da
mocles.orknlfc up the sleeve
of Crofcer. or
any other gift
of the Greeks.
But they didn't
reckon on tie
.'deus ex ma
chiua" of a
Philadelphia
hotel.
With a rattle
of tfti plates
and a creaking
of woolen cord
a g e, down
comes Mr. Mc-Kinlej-.
stuffed
full of the
"looks that
way," and the
reast and fun
go out with the
lights and
that Is noioke.
The tevsons
of April Fool's
Day are many
and valuablelf
studied practl-callj-.
A man
stiouM not let
his hcue burn
down becaus",
wiseinhisown
conceit, I s
neighbor telLs
him that r.ts
house is on fre.
At the farce
tirnr, if all tl e
night caps and
nightdresses in
Paradise allej
are sprinkled
from the hose
of the small
boy on the roof
who has been
paid to sLai.t
"fire," It enly
goes to show
that there is a
certain degree
of
in
fin i
lire in your
own house by
looking out of L.
the window.
The place to r.
look is in the ir3-'
bamcnt, or
any other In-sidepreclnct-Again
the
nan who pas
s wisely bj- a
silver dollar on
the pavement
feels had when
he looks back J JCTI-i' J
and sees that r
another man 4 t
has parted it up
safely. If it's a
iweketbook the
eae is all t'ic
sadder. Or. If
the man w.'.o
believes that ic
is better t fa'ce
in the baby off
the d. orst p,
takes itardtelL,
hKi wife al.ut
it, maj- r pcu
the bundle to
find in itc ncof
ouroldfriTiis,
the rag labj.
So, agam. the
bnckinthehat
Is inevitable,
but it Is no use
to go home in
that condition.
It. of coarse,
requires a good
deal of forti
tude and saw
teeth to eat a
cotton batting
dumpling, or to
chew, with a
scriptural face
even a small
piece of candy
with a j-anvin-side,
but it is
said that It ha3
been done rath
er than ac
knowledge the
joke, but in "r
nearlv all nf
Uie instances
Uie patients
died as mar
tyrs, like the
Who let: the Z. T
foc eat. nut of 'wil
his breadbas
ket rather thnn
be indicted for I f
dealing the
fox. I I
If you find
It yarn or cot
ton, spit n c ut i ?sgss3
iiiuii. i is vt -5;,
Reach for all I t?it'i SS
the nunev in
sight, ric up
all the pot'et
books, open all
jour icttcrs,
receive all the
visitors in or
out of myster
ious lirdles,
foronth.s par
ticular da it's
the only way
to i o e t h.e
problemsof the
other fool. It
Is somewhat
strange that a
person wl o be
lies esat it is
theucexrcctcd
that always
happens.scoms
to look behind
him when a
small boj- jay
to him confi
dentially: "Mis
ter, jour lorse
hasdroppedhis
tail." it is
human nature
to look back
when he has
turned the cor
ner. There have
beenverymnny
8age tomes
written about
the origin and n HfTTT f
uses of April ,h; rrh7-
Fool's Day.
Som writers
ascribe to it a
Roman, and
others a Greek
origin, it is
more than likely that It began on the day
when Esau tried to pas himself off for
Isaac with their bliud parent. Abraham.
Atu.ia.tia, i.onutr, dtetovrtl tUat the
kLii.iI okC-r lad hair en hi brain and.
tho t o-n. of Esau was launched for all
the rget. They have had hairs on their
brains cer since.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&q=april+fool+pranks&st=text&r=-0.056,-358.211,1.111,717.778,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>THE SAN FRANCISCO CALL, SUNDAY, APRIL 2, 1899.
APRIL CALLED
OUT ALL ITS
ARMY OF FOOLS
The Jester and Victim
Alike Make Merry.
THE MORGUE'S BUSY DAY
McENERNEY AND HIS COUN
TERFEIT PRESENTMENT.
Sad Tale of the Dentist Apprentice
and the Soubrette Who Could
Not Find the Key to the
Curtain.
April dawned bright and beaming and
kept merry throughout its. first day
blithely warbling between laughs, "Al!
fools look alike to me."
In spite of the fin de siecle pessimist
and his prophecy that All Fool's day was
a landmark of the past, the jester was
out In splendid form and landed gudgeons
galore.
The fun began early and lasted late.
A very few new jokes were perpetrated
and all the old ones revived, while the
usual good humor of both jester and vic
tim prevailed during the entire day. The
email boy was not so much in evidence
;is in previous years. Thoughts of Easter
eggs on the morrow, coupled with the ar
duous duties of trying on new suits and
boots and hats, drove for once all
thoughts of mischief from the mind of
the budding lords of creation. The offi
cials at the Morgue were the first to fall
victims to the merriment- of the day.
When the day was but a half hour old
—at 12:30 a. m.— a telephone call, pre
sumably coming from the Receiving Hos
pital, summoned a Deputy Coroner to take
charge of a body at the Hobson House.
"Hurry-up wagon" and Deputy went
quickly to the place, only to find that
April had dawned and that some one un
known wa? taking liberties with dignified
city officials.
In fact, the Morgue, or. rather, the
Morgue's telephone, was the greatest fcuf
fen-r during the day. The bell rang un-
-ceasingly from early morning until mid
i night and all sorts of messages were
voiced- over the line. Heartless wretches
also employes this method of fooling un
suspecting friends.
Tiner-aling-iing.
"Hello! Well—"
"Oh. la that you. Mary? This is Jim.
Say Mr. Wilson wants to speak with you.
Call him up— No. 1947."
•'Hfllo. No. 1947! Ts this Mr. Wilson?"
"No: this is the Morgue."
A bang— that's Mary's telephone— a
enwe— that is the Morgue.
While people were having fun at the
expense of the city the' city was enjoying
Its own pet little April fool joke—repeat
ing the prank over and over a^aln and
hailing each new victim with shouts of
applause and the shrill tooting of horny.
At the junction of Market. Kearny. and
Third streets at regular intervals a box,
neatly packed and stamped, as though
rc-ady for mailing, would glare the guile
less pedestrian straight in the face. Many
a man, woman and child, representing all
sorts and conditions of society, stooped
to pick up the innocent-appearing box.
None got any farther than the attempt.
The shouts of the crowd, many of them
previous victims, scared the parcel-picker
off, and he hastily lost himself in the
throng and waited in his turn for some
one to laugh at.
It was both a costly and hair-raising
April fool experience that Walter Mosier
had. Mosier. a young man possessed with
an ambition to learn dentistry, is em
ployed by Dr. Perkins, a Sixth-street den
tist. Walter's bogs occasionally allows
him to putter around the molars of his
customers who are out of funds.
One of thes? occasions arose Friday and
Mosier was delegated to perform the
charity service. The, victim was a boy
about 12 years of age. He was suffering
from an ulcerated tooth, and Mosier de
cided that the nerve must be killed, so
forthwith he filled the cavity in the
troublesome tooth with enough arsenic
to kill a horse and sent the unfortunate
youth home happy.
When Dr. Perkins came in Mosier, with
the dignity of a full-fledged dentist, told
his employer of his charity work. Then
Dr. Perkins thought of April fool.
"Say, Mosier." said the dentist, with a
serious look on his features. "I've just
received a telephone message to the ef
fect that the arsenic came out of that
boy's tooth and he swallowed it."
"My God!" exclaimed, the would-be
dentist. lf ls he going to die?"
"Well, the doctors are working on him
now, but they don't think they can save
his life."
"Say. Doc, I'm going to get out of town
before this kid dies. I don't want to get
pinched."
"Well." said Dr. Perkins, with a merry
little twinkle in his eye. "You can suit
yourself about that, but I'd advise you to
stay here. They-can't do any more than
charge you with mupder."
"Murder! Ugh! Don't say that. Dr.
Perkins," retorted Mosier, tearfully. "I
didn't mean to do It. I'll go and take
some arsenic myself."
The crestfallen apprentice spent several
moments of contrition and then he made
up his mind to get out of town. He got
50 cents from Perkins and made haste to
the nearest barber-shop, where he Invest
ed it in a haircut and a Bhave. M osier
gave the tonsorial artist orders to cut
}-is hair to the scalp and Bhave his sprout
ing mustache entirely off, hoping thereby
m disguise himself. The badly frightened
youth then returned to the office to learn
further detnils of his mythical victim's
condition. Dr. Simpson told him th« boy
was worse and Mosfer. started to leave the
office. "Wait a minute." called Perkins.
"Where are you going?'
"God knows where I'll go, but I'll never
go to jail for poisoning- that kid," an
swered the youth.
"You go down to the ferry to-morrow
and if the boy dies I'll telephone to you,"
suggested the doctor.
Mosier slipped out to his mother's
home, borrowed 510 and as early as 1
o'clock yesterday morning he arrived
at the ferry thoroughly disguised to
avoid possible detection. He walked up
and down the cheerless and 'desolate
wharves till morning, and then not hear
ing anything from Dr. Perkins bought a
ticket for Sacramento and stole aboard
the boat like a skulking criminal. On
the train he acted for all the world like
a noted forger crossing the line to Can
ada.
ttosiec confided to a friend before he
left that he would commit BUicide rather
than go to jail, which knowledge tuning
to Dr. Perkins made him decide noi to
cfrty the Josh any further. A message
was sent to the frightened youth, and
he returned to the city. Last night he
set about to drown his troubles in the
flowing bowl.
Garret McEnerney fell a victim to a
deeply laid April Fool plot laid for him
by his "close up" friend Jim O'Brien..
The bulky and brainy man of the law
dropped into O'Briens office, commonly
termed the "Cabinet," yesterday noon to
engage the contractor in a little chat.
"Say. Garret." chipped in O'Brien in
an innocent fashion just when the law
yer was i-xplaining to Jim Nealon the
way to make money, "when did you
stand for that bust over in the Palace?"
"What bust?" queried Mr. McEnerney.
"Why. the file they put in the corridor
of the Palace Hotel this morning," said
O'Brien as seriously as if he was talking
business with a moneyed man who want
ed- to spend a "thou or two" in street
work.
"There must be some mistake?" said
McEnerney. "No sculptor ever chiseled
me."
O'Brien is "close up," and his words
had weight with the man who was so
busy dissolving -the injunction against
Chief Lees that he did not stop to think
of April Fool's day.
"Let's go over, Jim, and take a look at
it," said MeEnernty, and .they both start
ed out tho door. O'Brien had no inten
tion of going over with his friend to seek
What he knew to be a myth, so he con
trived to' be excused In a manner that
would not breed suspicion.
The opportunity presented itself when
Judge Lawlor happened along.
"I'm going to take the Judge on -for a
minute," said O'Brien. "You go over and
look at that yourself and I'll wait for
you."
Off went Mr. McEnerney and his April
Fool went down on the arc.hives of the
"Cabnit" as a decided success. Every.
body who dropped into the Cabinet was
sent over to the Palace Hotel to see what
McEnernev had looked for in vain.
"Pete" Dtinworth. the well-known vo
calist, was- the victim of a ghastly April
Fool josh. One of his friends telephoned
to Dunworth's house early yesterday
morning and informed him that an inti
mate friend had died the night before
and was to be buried immediately.
"They, want you to be a pallbearer,
Pete," said th-e wily person at the other
end of the line.
"All right." said the popular tenor, af
ter expressing genuine regret over tae
unexpected death of his friend.
Promptly at 1 o'clock Dunworth, ar
rayed in a black cutaway suit and white
gloves, arrived at the .undertaking par
lors from which the supposed dead friend
was to have been buried.
"Is this where Mr. So and So Is to be
buried from." asked Dunworth, giving
the undertaker the friend's name and ad
dress.
"Why, he 1b not dead," said the under
taker, "who knew the man very well. "I
just ?aw him "at the corner of Sixth and
Mission."
At the Alcazar they revived the old the
atrical joke of the "key of the curtain"
with marked success. Mrs. Willie Dun
phy, the latest addition to the company,
ten minute* before curtain raising at thp
matinee, was sent on a hunt for the "key
to the curtain." "We can't open up."
said Stage Manager Bryant. "We have
lost the key to the curtain." Mrs. Dun
phy. who glitters on the bills as Miss
Howard, searched high and low for the
key and was in a condition bordering on
hVfiterics when the last bars of the or
chestra died away and the curtain was
lifted without a key.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/?sp=4&q=april+fool+pranks</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>Concerning the origin of the name and custom of All fool's day
contributed more to the extermination of
the heathen religion and its priests than
all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
though they were also freely employed.
The continuance of customs— especially
droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
the masses— after the original cause of
them has been removed. Is a very common
occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
firmly believed that "fooling" people on
the Ist of April is simply a perpetuation
of the annual public ridiculing of the old
Druid's and their superstitions.
Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
character, 13 thus claimed for April Fools'
day In a quaint old book of folk-lore
called "Father Time's Flyghtes." pub
lished in London In 1659. "numerous
Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
Fools on the First of April. This is said
to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah
sending ye dove out before ye water had
abated, on ye first day of ye month which
among ye Hebrews answers to our first
of April, and to perpetrate ye memory of
this deliverance it was thought proper
whoever forgot so remarkable a circum
stance to punish them by sending them
upon some fool's errand similar to- the
Ineffectual message upon which ye bird
was sent by ye patriarch."
The French associate with the first of
April precisely the same Ideas as do Enr
llsh speaking nations, but the person Im
posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*.
they style an April Fl3h or Polsson d' -v
ril. In the "Etymology of French pro
verbs," a most curious and delightful
work published In 1356. Billlngton I the
author, gives the following expiation
of the origin of April Fool customs "The
word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and
length of time has almost totall- defaced
the original intention, which w^ as fol
lows: That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
took place about this time o'the year,
and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
and forward to mock and't->rment him.
1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caia
phas to Pilate, from Pilate Herod and
from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
from thence, by which we send about
from one place to anoO«r such persona
aa we think proper subjects of our ridi
cule."
But It Is not only thrjU&hout Great Brit
ain, France and our/own country that
fools are made on U« nrst day of April.
The custom 1- elabrratfly observed
throughout Sweden, aid In Germany an
April fool la called elnen zam April
shlcken." The same custom haa also been
observed in India fr>m time immemorial.
Late in March of hold a great celetratton which they call
the Hull festival, of which the last day
is the greatest aid most general holiday.
During the con.nuance of the Hull, one
of its chief dl^rsions is to send people
on errands ar^ expeditions that are to
end In disapr^ ntment anat the expend of the person sent.
But the cistom of making April fools
has-been traced back to an antiquity even
greater t!** n that of the Hull festival of.
the Hind 9 Tne ancient Persians wer»
accustorr«vernal rruinox. which may occur as early
as ila-^n 22 or as late as April 23. with
elaborv*the Utter the chief was the making of
fool- precisely as we are accustomed to
mate them on April Fools* day.
jjp a quaint volume of poem.l bearing
tH title, "Verses On Several Occasions."
i,.id published In London. 1752, April Foola'
.ay is thus alluded to:
Now April morn b!*r Folly's throas exalts:
Now Dobb calls Nell and lauebs because ah*
halts.
"While Nel! meets Tom and Bays his tall la
loose,
Then laughs In turn and caJTa poor Thoma
"Goose."
In England, from earliest times, th»
ridiculous errands upon which the victim
of an April fool Joke sent have been
called "sleeveless errands." but the origin
and true significance of this term ar»
completely buried in oblivion and no an
tiquary has yet been able to unearth
them. These errands are as numerous as
they are Ingenious. Some of them hava
almost become classics, such, for Instance.
as sending a person to a book store for
the second edition of "Cock Robin" or
the "History of Eve's Mother": sending
some one to a milk dealer for a pint ot
pigeon's milk and to, a shoemaker for an
ounce of strap oil. which, if the shoe
maker has been Initiated Into the Joke,
the Inquirer receives In the shape of a
severe blow from a strap acros3 the shoul
ders. AMY F. STOCKTON.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1902-04-01/ed-1/?sp=3&q=april+fool+pranks</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>April Fool Kept by All
People.
Gigantic Hoax Was a Complete
Success.
"This Is the first of April,
Hunt the gowk another mile."
From time itruneiuorlal thollrstof
April has been celebrated by all sorts of
hoaxes and playing of pranks. Tho
truo origin of April' Fool Is burled lu
tho dust of centuries and our great
est antiquaries seem unable to throw
any light on tho subject. Nearly all
people however, celebrate this day or
its equivalent and the similarity of
the practice and tho coincidence of
dutes establishes without n doubt In
the minds of authorities ihe fact that
It had an early nnd common origin
among mankind.
Nearly all tho peoples on the Conti
nent celebrate April Fool with pranks
and tricks, and even the Hindoos havo
a festival on tho 31st of March, called
Hull, which coincides vjlth our April
Fool.
Ono of the most popular amusements
on April 1, or All Fools day, as it Is
called, Is tho Rending of persons on
fruitless frrands. Unsophisticated
persons are sent to tho bookstores for
a copy of the "History of Eve's Grand,
mother," or to the chemist's shop for
"pigeon's milk," while small boys arc
sometimes sent to the harness shop for
strap oil, when a liberal dose of this
treatment Is usually administered to
the boy.
There Is a story told to the effect
that Francis, Duko of I,oiTaIne, mid
his wife owed their escape from cap
tivity at NanteH to this popular cus
tom. Arrayed as peasants, they were
makiug their way out. of the territory
when they were discovered by a wo
man who knew them. She Immediate
ly hastened to a guard, and told him"
that the Duko was escaping. "April
Fool," said the guard laughingly,
treating the matter as a joke, and
while he laughed the prisoners made
good tlieir escape
Occasionally a gigantic hoax Is per
petrated on tho people as a whole, and
such a one met 'with groat success in
London in I8RO. Some wag distributed
cards, bearing an official looking seal,
which read: "Tower of London Ad
mit the bearer to vlorv the annual core,
raony of the washing of the white lions
on Sunday, Aprij, 1, 1800. It Is par
ticularly requested that no gratuities
be given to wardens or their assistants.
Admitted only nt tho white gate."
This trick was highly successful,
and people swarmed to tho tower to
view tho washing of tho whlto lions.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=april+fools+pranks</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>APRIL FOOL HUNTERS ARE
ON THE JOB TODAY
"All Fools' Day."
Just why the first of April |1§
let apart as an occasion when
very.; wag hoe "j license .to pra'otloa
iewptlon on tils fellow
man and get the laugh «n him no
nne seems ,to know, bat the cus
tom is gen©r«l and o* loss stand
ln«.* And after all i ttia pranks ol
the "April Fool H tinnt«rs s» gen
smlly tharmless.
PW t yoa I are not abta Ito langa
when |g tfhe laugh Is Yon ni MM
lc««p jrou* wtta WMIM to iflj
NSURANCE
CONCERNS
BUMPED
ose Contest to Secure
Eepeal of Hughes Law
m Regulating Their
Business.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=april+foolls+prank&st=text&r=0.111,0.529,0.335,0.379,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>JOKERS ANNIHILATE ARMIES
April-Fool Pranks Play Havoc With
European "War Map.
According io me map wmcu t-roi.
U p Wrench has prepared and kept
I
In the corridor of the third floor of
Academic Hall, European armies have
made radical changes in their ma
neuvers. The French apparently have
given up the war and have fled to the
western coast of France. The Eng
lish have disappeared entirely. All
the German forces of the western
theater are quartered in Paris. In the
east, the Austrian and German forces
are massed in the lowlands of Prus
sia, surrounded by Russian and Ser
vian troops. A few Servians are left
as garrisons along the frontier. One
lone Austrian army corps has escaped
and is now stationed in the middle of
the North Sea.
The havoc Is attributed to some
April Fool prank.
Another Instance of April Fool
thoughtfulness was shown this morn
ing when a member of the Agricul
tural faculty phoned to the county
jail asking "who had left a call for
him."</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058393/1922-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=-0.28,-0.078,1.56,1.56,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>BEDTIME STORIES
By HOWARD R. GARIS

USCLiE Wir.t.n A s LPRIL FOOL
JOKES,
Copyright. 1922, by McClure News
paper Syndicate.
"Oh. Uncle Wlggily! What's that
behind yo.U? I hope it isn't the Fuzzy
Ko!" cried Baby Bunty one morning.
The little rabbit girl had come over
to the hollow stump bungalow to
borrow a cup of flour.
"What's that? The Fuzzy Fox in
here?'" exclaimed the rabbit gen -Ionian,
and ho gave such a Jump that
ho nearly slipped over back ward
April fool!" laughed B... Bunty
"Oh!" exclaimed L'nclo WlggiB, BO
suddenly that his pink nose almost
stopped twinkling. "Oh. so this is the
first of April, is it?"
"Yes, and I caught you first ofj
all!" laughed Baby Bunty.
And so she had, for she had come
I over early to the hollow stump bun
galow on purpose to do this.
"Did I really make you think tho
Fuzzy Fox was there, Fncle Wig
glly?" asked Baby Bunty 'is the bun
nf gentleman snt down to his break
fast.
"You surely did for 3 moment." an
swered the bunny with a lui.Kh. "I
had no Idea this was April Fool Dsjy
But no matter. My turn will come,"
and he carried his glass of water to
the sink, spilling it out.
"Why did you do that"?" asked
Baby Bunty In surprise.
"Because," answered Uncle Wig
gily, "I have known it to happen m
times past that my glass of water on
April Fool morning would be full of
salt. As I don't want to drink salt
water now I lust emntiod mv rlaiu
1 11 fill It myself with fresh water."
"Oh there wasn't any salt in your
glasi suirl Nurse Jane
"No, added Baby Bunty. "I never
thought of that trick. I wish I had
But maybe Oh. Uncla Wlggily! Look
out!" she suddenly crlrd. "Is that a
pin in your chair?" 1
Uncle Wlggily Jumped up as If a
gun had gone off. Hfe looked In his
chair but there was nothing there.
"April Pool!" laughed Baby Bunly
again.
I'ncle Wlggily said nothing but he
sat down rather harfl and ate his
br. ik fast. And when linby Bunty said
"Oh. look out the window and see
who's coming!"
Undo Wlggily nevor looked up
from his morning paler. But some
one was coming along the, path to the
hollow stump bungaliw. They were
Curly and Floppy Twlltytail. tho plg
gle boys. Floppv had a llttlo bas
ket. "Do you want to look In this and
see what there Is?" asked Floppy, ns
ho and his brother camo In after
nrafl.lln U'lnfnr, II...I. r..l 1
'"h Ul. l Ull III'!
mat.
"Well. I can pretty nearly gu
what's In tho basket," said the bunny
gentleman It's some sneezing pow
der or a lot of dried leaves' You can't
April Fool me again."
"Oh. really, we wouldn't do such
thing!'1 grunted Ourl
"I'll open the basket!" cried Baby
Bunty. So she did, and inside was .1
lovely piece of cake that Mrs. Twisty
tall had sent to Uncle Wlgplly.
"April Fool!" grunted tho piggie
boys.
"Well, this Is a proper kind of April 1
T
Fool Joke!" said the bunny as he ate
the cako. which was very good. '''It
seems I can't be sure of anything this
morning." he told Nurse Jane when
tho children had run out and the
bunny was finishing his breakfast.
"You must he very careful." said
Miss Fuzzy Wuzzy
"I will," promised Uncle Wlggily,
and he was. But even at that a num
ber of- April Fool Jokes were played
on him nothing very serious though.
Once Jackie Bow Wow barked:
"Oil. is that 11 hlir hnil I n u..n
coat, Incle Wlggily?'' The bunnv
nearly twisted off his pink noso to
look at his back, but there was no
hole in his coat at all. Another time
Kittle Kat offered Uncle Wlggily
some candy, and when he chewed It,
Why It was sour Instead of sweet!
And Kittle mewed: '.pnl Fool."
"Well. I think it's my turnto play
an April Fool joko on some one,"'
said the bunny gentleman after a
while. "I wonder what I can do?
T want to play a real Joke'
He hopped along a llttlo farther
and, all of a sudden, out from be
hind a bush jumped he Bob Cat.
"Oh. ho!" howled the Bob Cat.
"Your ears look very good to me this
morning!"
"Do they"" asked I'ncle Wlggily.
Well, do you know what dav this
Is?"
"It makes no matter of difference
to me what day this is!" howled the
Bob Cat I on!y want
"Dear me' Look! Look behind
you! Is that a hunter man coming
with his gun?" suddenly asked Uncle
Wlggily, pretending to see something
back of the Bob 'at.
a hunter man with a gun! Oh,
don't tell me that! Don't tell mo
that!" howled the bad animal, and
away he ran as fast as ho could.
"I can't tell you that, for there
Isn't a hunter there!" laughed tho
bunny. "April Fool! April Fool!" And
lo h id played a Joke on the Bob Cat
just In time.
"Ha! Ha!" laughed the bunnv. as
ho hopped safely along. April Fool
Jokes aren't so bad after all'" And
If the pussy willow doesn't cry Jn the
night and want to bo rocked to sleep
in the cat's cradle, I'll tell vou next
about Uncle Wlggily and the .nrll
shower.
no
IF YOU ARE WELL BRED
You will not. if avoidable, call a
person on the phone Just at meal time
You will not listen in on the conver
sation on a party line.
You will not expect, a man who Is
talking to you out in the open to
stand with his hat off
HELPED HER MOTHER
VOM)i:i;iTI,lA
In these days of "rlii." coughs
colds, croup and whooping cough, it
Is well to know that every year ihcro
arc used more bottles of Foley's Honey
and Tar than of any other cough med
in. Mrs. S. L. Hunt. 515 W. 6th
St., Cincinnati. Ohio, writes: "Foley's
Honey and Tar relieved me of a hack
ing cough, tickling in the throat,
wheezing and pains in the ohest. It Is
helping my mother wonderfully."
That's why druggists- recommend Fo
ley's. Advertisement.
HWGS OF THE DUFFS Tu a m r i d
1 he APnl Fgo1 Boomerang BY ALLMAN
r ll DANMV, I UNDERSTAND THE MAW I'M cOIMG To PLAV ,Ul I i ia- H
Jl that rums the drug store APom Jlf- APRa Fool! YpT whatdioI dhm "wanted
In DOVMM AT THE CORNER 15 GNrA DANNY I TOLD HIM THE. "f I HAT HAVE VOU J VOU TELL A ?VH F
A wav A five Pound &ox of i druggist WAS giving mS. THEKEP JJJ. u,J,o CANDY AMD. ME A5KEP
JL CAKDV TO EACH LITTLE BOY )N J AWAV FIVE POUND BOXES) ,V .r T lU ME 5EWT ME" 1
THE NEIGHBORHOOD-YOU'D OF CANDY-HE'S GONE TO f -f I GOT IT TOLD HIM THAT YOU DID
l jl Riht! and he said all right</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1932-04-01/ed-1/?sp=47&q=april+fools+pranks&r=-0.173%2C0.021%2C0.796%2C0.449%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Some Reflections for April 1
BY LYDIA LE BARON WALKER.
APRIL first Is the one day In
year when persons suffer them
selves to be made fools of; no
that they relish it exactly evei
ao. but custom and a sense o
humor carry them through it withou
CT IS ONLY ON APRIL 1 THAT ONI
IS WILLINGLY A FOOL.
genuity deserves appreciation, and 1
may be added that this appreciation i:
seldom withheld. Children, of course
relish April fool's day absurdities, anc
their laughable little pranks are cause;
for adult merriment.
The historic method of fooling per
Ions was to send them on futile errands
Pools’ errands, these were called, anc
the term has become classic. Another
method of foolery was to send mock
gifts. Perhaps a bundle had nothing in
It, although neatly done up. Or should
an article be contained in the package
it was insignificant, or a ludicrous trav
esty of a present. These are the two
outstanding ways in which the fooling
was carried out in ancient times. It ir
from these that a general scheme for
outwitting persons on this special day
In the year has come about.
There is a spirit of merriment in
April fools’ pranks when they do not
savor too much of the obnoxious prac
tical Joke, which is annoying if not
actually unkindly or dangerous. It is
When one makes a fool of one’s self on
»1 ■'1
i this or any other day in the year that
there is cause for disturbance in one's
t own mind. Pew. indeed, are the persons
i who, looking over a past year on any
first day of April, are not aware of a
t certain smarting thought of some such
f times when one has made a fool of
one's self.
It may be that one has been quick
to think ungraciously of another and
has acted on such an idea, only to find
that a benefit accrued to herself, and
her whole judgment was hasty and un
kind. Temper may have been shown
over so simple a thing as a game of
bridge and a whole party may have
been disturbed just because one made
a fool of herself. Not a pleasant re
flection
Ypuths, even adults, who have ex
aminations or tests to pass, sometimes
feel if they cun fool the teacher or
examiner by "bluffing’' their way
through to pass that they have done
a clever thing. It is only when, later
on. they have the chance to profit by
their suppled knowledge, that they
realize it was they, themselves, who
were the real fools It was they, not
the examiners, who failed in their tasks.
I remember meeting a young Ameri
can in Paris who had. from her own
statement, ''bluffed” her way through
French. Her quick ear and eye evident
ly came to her aid in classes, as it was
doing in France, but not so successfully.
She was floundering in the maze of
irregular verbs and French Idioms par
ticularly. She said, "I thought I wes
fooling the teachers when I slid through
my French. Now I find it was myself,
not them, who was fooled.”</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014085/1935-04-09/ed-1/?sp=10&q=april+fools+pranks&r=-0.136%2C0.099%2C0.683%2C0.386%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Gustave Haensclten was
among the radio artists select
ed as the victims of April
Fool’s pranks. For years the
NBC composer-conductor has
fead loach served in his office,
and the menu always consist
ed of a salad, toasted crackers
and milk. Un April 1st the
restaurateur substituted a big
onion smothered with steak,
Ice-cream with pie on it, and
n cup of cream with coffee.
Gas retaliated by giving tlie
waiter the bill.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88063294/1942-03-29/ed-1/?sp=58&q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>April Fool s Day Horseplay Declines
As War-Torn World Shuns Frivolity
By LOUIS SOBOL
TN A world which prows more
serious by the hour, the spirit
of tomfoolery' is fadinp rapidly,
as might be expected.
Even before the war. the day
of the comic valentine was prac
tically over—and they tell me
that the kids in the little coun
try red wooden school houses
which, in most cases, are neither
red nor wooden, no longer place
mice in the teacher’s desk, pep
per in her apple and limburger
cheese in her pocketbook.
Under the circumstances, one
can understand why we no
longer put our heart, soul and
imaginative resources into April
Fool’s Day pranks.
A few of the hardier still
make telephone calls inviting
victims to parties at an address
which turns out to be either a
police station or the city
morgue.
Some send candies to girls
which will break off a tooth
when bitten into or will scorch
the mouth.
Stories Decline, Too
But thpir day, too, is coming
to a close.
Even the good old stories ai-e
fading.
One of the runs- l>eloved was
about the little t»oy who told hi>
mother please to come quickly,
“Father is kissing a strange
woman in his study.” and when
mother and little boy tip-toed
to the studv and mother flung
open the d*>or. the 1 ttle ltoy
rlapped his hands jumped up ar
down jubilantly and shout'd:
“April Fool! It’s not strung*
woman— lt** nursh
There is a iheor> that April 1
marked the ancient pagan feast
of the vernal equinox to cele
brate the passage of winter am;
the return of spring.
Naturally, in those days i*
raised the roof on an a ;occasion as ti :nd w.r,> wrt<
drunk and the c* b brants d
crazy things.
Sophisticated View
A more sophisticated hyp*
thesis is that April fool fog orig
noted in France during the rrugi
of Charles IX when, in obi,
new calendar was adopted mak
ing the beginning of the yea-
January 1 instead of April 1
Ax it was the rusfom of th<
country to exchange visits an*i
gifts on New Years Day.
wags, after the new calendar
PAGE 6
was in effect, invited people to
visit then as before on April J,
or send gifts.
When guests arrived they
found no preparations had been
made for Vhem.
jßr >m?jl* jjftk- W
m IPjf «J***V
fIK
€ipK'
j^TT
(’ARMAN D’ANTONIO is the savage dancer featuted in the musical
comedy, ‘‘Panama Hattie,” beginning its second week at the Cass Monday night.
PHAGE MID SCHE
(Charles Centra "fl
j a
Perhaps I’m too old to keep
close touch with the young—but
it seems to me they no longer
think it worth while to victimize
unsuspecting friends on a whole
sale scale.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062236/1933-04-07/ed-1/?sp=5&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.106,0.111,0.901,0.901,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>UTOPIA CLUB
Mrs. Adelaide Chapman Hawkins
was hostess to the club Friday eve
ning. Those.present were Mesdames
Eva Fuller, Beatrice. Edwards, Ethel
Hall, Lillian Harris, Elsie Jackson,
and Maymo Turner.
Guests of the evening were Messrs.
H. Childs, and .1. Walker. Cards and
sevcial April Fools Day pranks efa
tured the evening.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.089,-0.098,0.521,0.521,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Circus Folk Spurn
April Fool's Day
Pranks of Clowns
"Of Course, I'm No Femin?
ist," Insists the Diminu?
tive Mrs. Doll, Just Wed;
Press Agent Busy as Fixer
April came to New York yesterday
and made a prompt ?.?sit to the circus
in Madison Square Garden. Rut if it
had not been for the clowns it is
doubtful whether the other circus folk
would have recognized (lie yearly
visitor.
For down in the areaways, where
the animals live, it was cold?colder,
circus men said, than it has been for
years when the big show comes to
town. The lion curled up in his. cage
to keep warm, and the rest of the ani?
mals huddled behind the woollen walls
of 1 heir wagons.
If it hadn't been for the clowns
But they, of course, being clowns,
remembered that their day of days had
come, and from morning until night
no spot in Madison ."qua re Garden was
sacred or spared the tricks which they
contrived for celebrating April Fool's
Day. It is said that one of them made
Louise, the giraffe, swallow an alarm
clock, but Louis refused to discuss this
report.
Midget "Doll" No Suffragist
The greatest stir of all was caused
when some clown man circulated the
report that domestic little Mrs. Doll,
the new midget from Ringling's Show,
had turned feminist over night and
was preaching woman's rights from
the platform where she is accustomed
to show her tiny Belf.
"It's a ridiculous libel," Mrs. Doll
asserted when questioned. "I, vote?
Indeed, I'm much too busy. 1 do not
believe in woman's suffrage. And be?
sides"?.Mrs. Doll, just six months a
Inicie, looked at her diminutive husband,
who was sitting just out of earshot
"men. you know, don't like clever
women. Of cours'', we can be clever,
but we must never lei them know
about it."
"What is the thing I like to do best?"
she said. "Dress and dance. 1 have
twelve evening gowns in my hotel
lovely ones, made by my special dress?
maker in Chicago. It's so hard to get
u good dressmaker when one is an odd
size," she confided. "I've kept mine for
four years. Besides clothe:-. 1 love a
goo time, too."
Elephant Yields Glib Tongue
Mrs. Doll is twenty-four years old.
During tho war she knitted many a
muffler for tho soldiers, she admitted
yesterday, and she has acted in several
war benefits. She spent a Reason al
Coney Island several years airo "and
tho subway conductors remembered mc
when I came back this year," she said.
At this point, in tho interview there
was an interruption from t o hi i
area. The only Barnum Bailey
elephant in he show. Albert, who has
n private cache for hay and grain in
the basement, had been robbed of his
private stock. Lute in tho afternoon
the circus, press agent, succeeded in
talking Albert back into good nature.
A large crowd visited the Bhow both
afternoon and evi ning, "They expect
something extra of the clowns/' tho
press agent said. "Hut thank good?
ness, say I, when April Fool's Pay is
over."
Miss BJUss Is "ride To-day
Will Become Wife of Officer at
(?.race Church
Miss "Ruth H. Bliss, daughter of Mr.
and Mrs. Walter Phelps Bliss, will be
married this afternon in the chantry
of Grace Church to Captain Hermann C.
Schwab, U. S. A. Only members of the
two families will be present al the
ceremony, which will be performed by
the Rev. Dr. Charles Lewis Slattery,
assisted by the Rev. 'William G. Thay
cr. of St. Mark's School. The ceremony
will be followed by a small reception
at the home of the bride's parents, G
East Eighty-seventh Street.
Another marriage to-day will bo that
of Miss Gertrude B. Williams, daugh?
ter of Rovcrt Davidson Williams, of
930 West End Avenue, to Captain
George Flory Begoon, Coast Artillery
Gorps, U. S. A., in St. Ambrose Chapel,
Cathedral of St. Johnthe Divine.
Still another bride of to-day wrill be
Miss Dorothy Leith, daughter of Mr.
and Mrs. William Leith, who will
marry Stanley A. Brown in the Hotel
Gotham.
-r?
Mrs. Henry H. McCliire
Wins Suit for Divorce
Jury Exonerates Woman; Finds
Husband Guilty of Miscon?
duct With Servant
The jury in the divorce case of
Henry II. McClure against his wife,
Mrs. Frances C. McClure, returned a
verdict last night exonerating Mrs.
McClure and finding ber husband
guilty of counter charges.
Neil It. White was named as core?
spondent by Mr. McClure. In her
counter suit Mrs. McGlure named a
servant in the McClure home.
In explaining why her husband and
detectives found Mr. White in her
home late at night, Mrs. McClure told
the jury that he had called to see her
husband, and finding her with a severe
headache had gone to the drugstore
for medicine. He went to her bed?
room to give it to her, she said, when
her husband and detectives broke in.
The jury was out for several hours
and returned to the courtroom several
Grnes to ask instructions from Justice
-iohn V. McAvoy. Mrs. McClure and her
mother were in the courtroom when
the verdict was brought in. They were
congratulated heartily by Mr. White,
who also was present.
"Bribe for Senator?
It's April Fool's Day!"
This Is Comment of Walters
at Albany on Story About
Huge Streetcar Offer
Staff Correspondence
ALBANY, April 1.?Senator J. Henry
Wallers, president pro tern, of the Sen?
ate, when asked to-nifjht to comment
on an evening newspaper story which
said that half a million dollars was
offered to an unnamed senator for his
support, of the Martin bill permitting
public service commissions to increase
the rate of fare of street ear lines, not?
withstanding any existing franchises,
contracts, or agreements, said:
"The story does not name any scn
ntor. It is an anonymous story. If
any such bribe were offered it is the
duty of the senator to brine the mat?
ter to tho attention of tho bar of the
Senate."
rs dosed the interview
by observing that this was April Fool's
14th Street, near Third Avenue
Rentpayers' Protection
Bill Passes Assembly
Landlords in New York Must
i Give 1 4Days' Notice to Monthly
Tenants Before Eviction
Staff Correspondence
ALBANY, April 1.?The Assembly to
i day championed the cause of New
York City rent payers by passing the
Fertig bill providing that no monthly
tenant shall be removed on the grounds
of holding over his term unies.-, at least
i Fourteen days' notice is given by the
landlord.</text>
      </result>
  </topic>

#Topic 2
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-women-aviation/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042373/1910-09-01/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Aviation+aviators+women&st=text&r=0.009,0.136,0.872,0.985,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>V«H:-
ii
By CHARLES N. LURIE.
SAID"Well,my
I to friend the woman
hater:
why shouldn't wom
en fly if they wish to do so?'
Said my friend the woman hater:
"No reason In the world. They 'go up
In the air* often enough."
So they, are going up in the air, as
the pictures show, but not In the sense
In which the misogynist used the
words. Aviation for women has reach
ed the point where the Parisian cos
turners are designing special costumes
for the sport or pastime or vocation
or avocation. That means that It Is
fast becoming 'an "institution." One
of the lady aviators is shown In the
picture garbed for a flight
What Shall We Call thsi Lady Flier?
"Lady aviators" brings up another
point. 'What shall we call the women
who are ascending in aeroplanes and
balloons? 8hall we refer to them as
avlatrlces (plural of avlatrix, of which
the masculine Is aviator), or shall we
adopt the suggestion of an English
magazine and refer to the fair fliers as
"aeroine*?" The latter suggestion hits
merit, but the word has one fatal de
fect—It is difficult of pronunciation.
From some mouths it will emerge' with
so close a resemblance to "heroines"
as to be mistaken for that word. Per
haps it is well to suggest a relation
ship between "heroine" and "aero
ine," since the latter Is undoubtedly
worthy of enrollment in the lists of
the former. At this, stage of the flying
game any woman wko' accomplishes a
flight Is surely a heroine.
Up to the date of writing there had
not- been many women aviators.
Italy had the Duchess of Aosta, cousin
by marriage of King Victor Emmanuel.
France^ in some respects the leader In
aviation and in many respects the
world's mentor in "feminism," had only
three prominent lady fliers—Baroness
de la Roche, Incapacitated for an in
definite length of time by very serious
WHEN
the government of
th* United States want*
Information on military
matters to whom does It
turn? To the .same man to whom the
state of Ohio look* for advice and
guidance In regard, to its citizen sol
diers.- And that man I* Major General
Charles William Frederick Dick. Don't
recognize th* name? Well, you are
not to be blamed. When the name of
the senior aenator from Ohio 1* printed
In It* usual form the two middle sec
tions are cut out and th* name pro-
4^^ '»vr
IM
I...:.
Tt
*'C
1
••jk ii MAJOR GENERAL DICK AND STAFF.
ceed* on the main line as Senator
Charles Dick of Ohio. If Dick were
an Englishman he would be known as
Major General th* Honorable Charles
William Frederick Dick. But H* I* not
a Britisher, only a plain—very plal*.
In fact—0)iloan, who sheds luster on th*
title of Unlte*8taU» senator by add
ing to It that of major general In th*
Ohio national guard.
Com* to think of IV major gwMMls
are *caro* ln th* **nat* these day*,
pick I* th* on|y on* at pi«*ent now In
active service, and hte title Is only a
militia on*, after all. Pressing him
injuries dueto a fait lime. Franck.
also "injured JuBt after she had an
nounced her Intention of making a
flight across the English channel, and
Mme. Paulhan, wife of the famous
tiouls. There have been a few others,
but their exploits have attracted lit
tle attention. England has two or
three women fliers In heavier than air
machines. Germany has produced no
women fliers of note—none, that is. In
aeroplanes. The Zeppelin, Parseval
and Gross dirigible balloons have had
female passengers In some of their fa
mous flights. In America we have had
Hiss K»therlne Wright, Mrs. Hart O.
Berg, Mrs. Cortland Field Bishop,
Mrs. Clifford B. Harmon, Mrs. Wil
liam K. Vanderbllt, Jr., and a few
others as passengers with the "man
birds" when they made flights above
the earth. Mrs. Bishop was the first
woman to fly In America. But no
American woman so far as known has
been daring enough to go aloft as an
aviator. That will come In time, no
doubt, and in the meanwhile we may
rest content with the fact that we have
the only genuine, bona fide woman
airship Inventor on earth. She is
worth a separate paragraph.
Only Woman Airship Inventor.
The name of the lady is Miss E.
Lillian Todd, and her postofllce address
is New York. She Is called 'probably
the first woman In the world to de
sign and build an aeroplane" all by
herself. The Todd machine was a col
lapsible or folding aeroplane, and the
fact of Its existence was first made
public two years ago, Since that time
Miss Todd has kept busy designing
and making improvements to her aero
plane. She Is a member of the Aero
Club of America and one of the found
ers of the Junior Aero club, which
aims at teaching the young American
idea how to fly. Miss Todd has the
added distinction 'of being the builder
of her flying machine as well as Its
Inventor. Recently she had the good
fortune to attract the notice of Mrs.
Russell Sage, and It was announced</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-10-16/ed-1/?sp=56&q=dutrieu+helene&st=text&r=-0.056,-358.174,1.111,717.778,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>OIF [FINTEBEST i
MNiE. FRANK, WHO INTENDS TO
ESSAY A FLIGHT ACROSS THE
ENGLISH CHANNEL.
0. WHITHER SO HIGH?
Twentieth Century Woman Is
After Aerial Colrxebs.
In the course of T*n or twenty years it
tnay be as s»>jperf talk about wom
en, who ride lr. machines as it
\pcmld be now to J d forth or. women
*rho rifle in streetcars. In the year 1310.
however, woman aviator is still a nov
elty. The International Aviation Tourna
■tent at Belmont Park will be an cxclu
•tlvely masculine affair, and the heroism
of those women ho have begun to mount
up with wings like eagles occasions
JCTKVJ deal or surprise, though It Is hard
to see why it should be so.
Nobody is surprised when women drive
automobiles, and in the matter of acci
dents, automobiles are up to the wire with
anything- that travels. Women are gener
ally ■where the danter is.
It «at not until last November, hough,
that a woman actually went aloft alone.
•Women had frequently gone as passengers
with aviators of the other sex. but it re
mained for the Baronne Raymonds de
Ijaroche to strike out in a new field as
the first "woman navigator through air cur
rents. This she c.i at Mourmelon. By now
she Is a. veteran at the sport. At the flying
contests held in Egypt last spring no one
was more venturesome than she.
The very first woman who ever flew -was
a Flemish girl. Mile. P. yon Pottelsberphe.
She chanced to be on the field as a spec
tator when Henri Farman was making
one of his first exhibition flights. in Bel
gium. A lightweight passenger was
needed, ana Mile, yon Pottelsberghe vol
•unteerefi.
Not very lons afterward, at Turin. th«
French tnas, Mme. Therese Peltier,
took a flight with L£on Pelagranpe in his
Voisin biplane. Mme. Peltier was very en
thusiastic about the biplane then, and was
V jrolng to learn to drive it. but she never
it did. Probably the tragic death of Dela
franc* gave her a dislike for the fpon_
Th*. im woman in America, to fly was
Mrs. Ralph BL Van aa Man. wife of an
army captain. She has cine, all sorts of
daring thine- she- is said to r* able to ride
any horse that goes, and when one of the
Wrights invited her to go aloft with him
near Washington, last October, she jumped
at the chance. Miss KatßCftae Wright,
elster of the famous brothers, has ascend-
Some Ways of the World
The "silence" treatment at West Point
appears to be nothing to the "melting
stway" act as practised by omen when
they want to Intimate to another woman
Chat ehe is cot of their social set.
"I witnessed the latter treatment this
SBimner," said a woman who has just re
turned irom a. fashionable summer resort.
-and I had the satisfaction or witnessing
also the triumph or the victim ever her per
rwcutors. She was a very rharming' girl
Trho had come to the place because she had
heard it was attractive and because it
-was convenient lor the men of her family.
"She knew some of the eligible young men
of the place, so counted on having a good
time, but she aid not court en the lact
that because she knew these men the belle
of the colony would confer her a deadly
rival, and having been ther* first would
treat tier as an intruder instead, of an ad
dition, and a laßcinating one at that. The
men gave fcer family a dinner, invited tile
"SseJle to meet her. and innocently thought
•they bad done th* right thing-, but they had
snerely added fuel to the flames, and be
-Sore two weeks were lip the newcomer was
aware of what she had to lace. t>ne would
■bravely don hex exquisite Frencn irocks
and Join the •women, ■who bowed gra-clousiy
•.t first, but In naif an hour see would be
left alone, and the little crowd ■would have
collected Just a short distance away. The
never raw her unless there were men
croend. and then "he would come over
•wit* a ssreet smile and a few intima'<> re
marks tr.at eouia not be resented because
of the boys. Finally, the new girl went olt
to visit, ana was gone Tor six weeks or
more. On her return ehe encouni^-red the
old girl, who was with one of the men, ana
■who accordingly showed fome interest, ask
ing whers she bad been. hearing the
name Of the place, she said. 'Oh, I know
Mrs. Blank there. She has often wanted
in* to name a time to visit her, co I think
I'll write and go up. for she gives every one
Fuch a pood time. Perhaps you've heard of
J-.er'' Th** tr.Fwer came sweetly, 'Yes.
I've bast been with her; Mm is ray cousin.
and I told her I had met you here,* The
PARK &TILFORD
Fifth Avenue and T^ecty-MX'h Street And H ranch Stores
We call your attention to our Cand> Department
at this, as well as at our Hrant h Stores.
AH our Chocolates, Bon Bons, Caramels and Candies
are manufactured by ourselves.
Only the Purest and finest Materials used.
PRICES: lh
Chocolates and Bonbon*, .M)
Peswrt Battle, .35 French CsrsmeU, .W)
Pepp*ra>mt Dainties, .35 Chocolate Mellow Mftflto, .45
CboeoJste Cream Royals, .45 French Nougat, 'A-\b. Hot .50
5 CbocolsteMuruichinoCherries
Vanilla Walnut Fudge, Jf per box .40
Chocolate Fudge, .35 large box .80
Deliveries out of town by freight and express.
ttmm Catalogue with COMPLETE Price-Lists i'.ad!\ smt psm
n:lle. helene dutrieu, who
holds the record among
women pilots in distancs
and altitude.
Ed with them, but that was at Pau. and
not in America.
Of course, Mrs. Glenn H. Curtiss has had
trips in her husband's biplanes with him.
She, Is her husband s right hand, by the
way. In his work of constructing biplanes.
She attends to the Business details, being
fortunate enough to have a mother who
manages the house, leaving her free to
help her husband.
Women professionals are appearing in
the flvinff field. HGlene Dutrleu is a bird
woman who has filled engagements to ap
pear at amusement fields in a biplane. She
holds the record amMg women aviators for
distance, and altitude, having made a re
turn night from Ostend, Belgium, to
Bruges with a passenger, a distance of
twenty -eight miles, and gone up thirteen
hundred feet. Mlie. Dutrien has done near
ly everything daring there was to do.
More than a decade ago she won the
world's championship for women in cy
cBBC and no woman has been able to take
from her the hour record. She has done all
sorts of trick riding, and nearly lost her
life "looping the loop," so when she cot a
had fall in a Santos-Dumont "Dragonfly"
it did not leaze her in the least. N T o man.
spectators asid. could have taken it more
atnsrslTr
Mrne. Frank, another French •woman, also
has a record for long flights, and is now
planning to fly across the English Channel.
Miss Gertrude Bacon, a member of the
English Women's Aerial League, who has
been one of Farman's passengers several
times, can compare the different methods of
ajcrial tiavelllng from experience, for she
has tried them all— the spherical balloon.
the dirigible ar.d the aeroplane. For dreamy
delight she chooses the balloon.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-07-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=aeroplane+fly+FLY+flying+Harriet+machine+piloted+Quimby</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>WOMEN WHO FLY
riiotolMwlnl.rvlck, N. V
Mile. Dutrieu, leading French Aviatrix
WHEN women take to aeroplane rac
ing, as it is announced will be done
at the summer meet of the Harvard
Aeronautical Society in Cambridge,
Mass., it will be only a matter of a short
time before the interest in the sport will
be so general that airship contests will
be as common as tennis tourneys ami
golf competitions are today.
Three countries will be represented by
women contestants at Cambridge, with
Mile. Dutrieu, a French airwoman of
considerable expe
rience, in the lead.
Mrs. James V.
Martin will wear
the English col
ors; and Miss
Emily Willard,
who has already
made several as
cents with her
Jand Miss
II y Willard,
has alread)
c several as-
S wit b her
brother at Min
eola, L. 1., is, up to
date, the third
woman entered for
the race.
Mile. Dutrieu is
looked upon as
perhaps the most daring woman aviator
in the world, although several of her own
countrywomen press her closely for sec
ond place. She first began to fly in a
Demoiselle monoplane about two years
ago. She changed to a barman biplane;
and it was in the latter machine that she
made her longest flight, winning the
Coupe Fcmina after making 105 miles,
and remaining in the air for two hours
and 35 minutes.
Photo Edwin Levlck, N.V.
Miss Harriet Quimby,
Journalist and Flier
Mrs. Martin is an Englishwoman who
married a former instructor in the Har
vard Aeronautical Society; but who later
became an in
structor in Gra
hame-Whit c's
School of Aviation
in France. She has
not only ma d
many flights with
her husband in the
machine, belong
y ing to the Harvard
Society, which he
designed; but she
is now flying in
Grahame-W h i t c's
Baby biplane,
which is a small
copy of the Farman machine.
Other influences which will induce
many more women to learn to fly are
the opening of the A. J. Moisant School
of Aviation at Garden City, L. 1., and
Photo Edwin Levlck.N.Y.
Mrs. E. Edwards,
an American Aviatrix
THE FAMILY MAGAZINE.-■ SECTION
the prospect that a Wright machine will
be kept at Belmont Park for the sum
mer, for the instruction of students and
the carrying of passengers. These ad
vantages will make it possible for many
women to become aviators; and will also
give an opportunity to scores of others
who have been longing for a chance to
try the experiment as passengers.
The first woman to try to fly her own
machine was Miss Harriet Quimby, New
York journalist. She is very enthusias
tic over her monoplane, in which she has
already taken several long (lights, with
but one mishap of minor importance.
Other women who have made several
flights alone at Mineola, are Mrs. E.
Edwards and Mrs. Francois Raiche.
Miss Mary Shea, winner of the Bridge
port (Conn.) Post competition, made a
flight of about five miles on May 14,
from the Bridgeport Aerodrome, .out
over Long Island Sound and back.
Mrs. Frank Coffyn, whose husband is
connected with the Wright Company's
instruction camp at Augusta, Ga., flew
30 miles with her husband on March 3,
from Augusta, Ga., to Aiken, S. C. They
left the former place at 7:10, arriving
at their destination at 8:21, just in time
to eat breakfast with some friends.
Most of the time, they traveled at a
height of 500 feet.
Across the water, are many French
women aviators who have won trophies
in various contests. Among these may
be named Mile. Hervieu, who won the
Coupe Ftmina at Pau in 1910, traversing
eighty-seven miles and remaining in the
air two hours and five minutes, and
Baroness Raymonde de Laroche, who
was one of the first airwomen in France.
A list of women flyers would be incom
plete if it did not mention the Hon.
Assheton Harbard, a famous English
balloonist, who has frequently piloted
her own balloon from England across
the Channel into France.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093220/1911-08-03/ed-1/?sp=2&q=aeroplane+air+Aires+event+fly+flying+machine+plane+planes+race+RACE+STUNT&st=text&r=0.683,-0.005,0.5,0.565,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MRS. RUSSELL
SA G E has
ad no u need
herself a pntron of
aviation So Inter
ested is she In the
doings ot the fly
men thai she took a
motor spin to Mine
ola, where the Aero
n a u t i c society
houses a dozen men
and biplanes in a
bis red shed, and
looked over all the
engine driven birds
@19u; by Lazarnlck
MRS. R. BAC.F.
Especially was she Interested In the
big biplane being built by Miss E. I.
Todd, the woman aviator I'he plane
Is a large one, but Mrs. S;ii;e went
over its every detail and showed by
her questions to Louis Adams, an In
ventor who was showing tier round,
that she understood a great deal iilmui
air craft.
"It la very gratifying." snlil Mrs
Sage, speaking of Miss Todd's effort.
MIRfl B r.*ri!A TODD.
"to see women take up these tilings,
and I am always willing to encourage
anything that is done by a woman.
"I have watched Miss Todd's prog
ress with much concern and hope she
will succeed In making a successful
flying machine. If she needs any more
help I am willing to give it to her.
"I am receiving so many letters from
people who want help! Yesterday I
received four letters from ambitious
aviators or aeronauts—which should I
call them? I would be willing to help
any woman to accomplish something
that is worthy, mucb more than the
men."
If Mrs Rage should decide to help
tbe woman aviator:) she would already
discover a flock of them who have en
tered the Held, some of them wives
or sisters of the "man birds" who are
flying and others who are determined
to bo woman birds without waiting for
any mere man to lead the way.
Miss E 1.11 urn Todd of New York
is probably the first woman In the
world to design and build an aeroplane.
This was a collapsible device, which
she first made known to tbe public In
tbe summer of lUOB. /t that time.
MISS K ATFTKRTVK WMOFTT
while giving no detailed description of
the machine, she said it called for a
spread of forty-five feet, with a width
of seven feet. The plane was to stand
six feet in height and to weigh several i
hundred pounds less than any other I
aeroplane of the time. The engine was I
to he of special design and of exceed
ing lightness and strength. j
Miss Todd not only designs her aero
planes, but. being skilled in the use
of tools, is her own model builder.
It is believed that Miss (Catherine
Wright, sister of the Wright brothers,
was the first American woman to make
a flight in an aeroplane. This she did
on Feb. 15, 1909, at I'au, France, wheu
she made an ascent with a brother.
Mr. Wilbur Wright
Women were one of the big features
of the aviation meet at Los Angeles
last January After M. I'aulhati hud
performed some of his startling feats
he took Mine Paulhan in tils machine
and Hew away with her to Hcdondo
Beach and back again, a distance of
thirty tulles The (light lasted thirty
six minutes
To Mm#. Raymondi' do Laroebe. who
Is a I- ronch baroness, belongs the dis
tinetion of Ijeinu itic pioneer woman
avintor of Prnii'-e. althouch seven oil!
or women liavc been licensed ns ulr
pilots by the Prench Aero club Sin
was one ol the tirsi women to take a
practical interest in aviation and soon
after tlit tlrst International eu|> event
at Rheltns purchased a Volsin biplane
and later was an entrant for the prize
of 5.1RH1 francs offered the votnan mak
tac the best time for ten kilometers.
Her efforts at the meet resulted In
one of the most distressing accidents
In aviation She was drl> Ing her bi
plane at a helcht of fifty meters when
she suddenly loot control of the ma
Chine and foil with It to the ground
Eler lep< ami arms were broken and'
her wholp hodv terribly bruised.
Carpet Mills.
The first carpet mill in America was
not established until after the clnsi
of the Revolution. It was in l"!'l at
Philadelphia, that carpet making as an
industry was born In t!i" t'nltcd States
Since then, however. thiT"country lias
become rre-oniinent tn carpet making</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1911-08-06/ed-1/?sp=52&q=HARRIET+QUIMBY</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>M,SS MATILDA MOISANT. SISTER OF THE LATE JOHN MOISANT. WHO IS LEARNING TO FLY A MONOPLANF.
r?-'-'-1
Scorners of the Ground
Three Birdwomen at Mineole, First Americans
of Their Sex to Wing the Blue Deep.
sra m By(
K, Mlaa rtarnV
I
Tueada) at Um Herapatead Plahu h.
beb mta a\ at"
II
twtab
f\
I

r
at thought ha was

tha m
an 1 ln thfl
n the macl
aglrj

aad i
i

:nf.n(f up
ra two
aad 01
I through
?K







I
I
I m

I

oan a*/l



I

raa.



i ed to
iu a rac

Some Scasor
A rei immer day

d and
j-..- i H.3

im tbe




t>
I

I





Add
or two


_

water. lf tl
i


-it tlu*

fr>
ng


Mlaced
X |?a iTfiiare a eicelj s?u
in a biplans tbs asaglafl la dlraetly bark
<>f tbs aperator, and If tbs machlne fall.i
tiier?* a.-*- hundrada of ncnnfls of solid
,,f him. In a mono
plaar. however, I bba dlstaaee
lf ne fallfl he only
?Ot Ct ished

M Qulmby and Miss
rr, a! type.i of air
MlBSftla. hut
ea ln appearan
sHa atid ilarK
ea wlth 1
lUni barma daa

nt .-rnplo
Waekli Mm
a pro
>H,ir n>nt
rasohlls tour
ainc-r
fortable, rotuad aatoar
?he appeara to bi
.1 Ip, aii'i.
ni.nks roas-oouatry

_ for 'prosfl
nj,>ri*
n ana
wouldn en: to
aae waj the avia

i. a*bi ra th? m*n
n flxhlbl

I infei
lha a 4;: id custom
M f <>n inann


"tbsra is one
a auf*
a lt ahe

;b of
Mght from
retura. It ls

g] i
a dda't waat
I

Tl
-even ihe
Btlmea
i

rame,
lt fnr
the excitement of IL I'm
srorld
n Ca Ifora
1
there. all


B, thea nol

lt lB 4

I
John M
i
naa

M .fl M
I
tora oi

t laa
ar.
l
ofly
xablc 'RecipcJ

_

ln the
I




eat until

in tv
tli<- mlxt*



MISS BLANCHE STUART SCOTT. IN
HER BIPLANE.
w j
THE END OF GOSSIP
Women Who Couni Stitches
Can'l Talk Scandal.
A balcyoi
Torh n ara i ni l
I
led from Ihe
fact tl aork??
hairs.
ibeth Barrett Broa

opialoi
?I itnble
orar
But If
a g tha
a ecl attentl n
thtion
muat be counta
j out ri| womai
fou
e can'l loud oi
a thal
m i i
i

ln fi
wai ed almoal
*4lnf .1 t r a woman, that ll
at handa rii-w aa sl}a
tha fl end
Doubtleaa tha dovotl

fact that there 1<
_
ira i
r
V.

BOOl 'he

I

.1

1
MISS HARRIET QUIMBY, THE FIRST AMERICAN WOMAN
TO RECEIVE AN AVIATOR'S LICENSE.
The SeerofucKer Family</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1911-12-15/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Matilda+Moisant</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Miss Moisant, in her aeroplane. She
the sister of John B. Moisant.' the
famous aviator killed in New Orleans,
La., by his machine falling. Miss Moi
sant is ambitious to take her broth
former place in the aviation world.
era
Why a Woman Can Run an
Airship Better Than a Man
By Prof. Rudolph Hensingmuller, of Vienna University.
BECAUSE she
full retina.
has retained the primitive faculty of seeing with he?
Enforced modesty and flirting have caused thia..
BECAUSE she has scattered attention Instead of concentration. Thle
is invaluable to the aviator who must notice many things at once.
BECAUSE she has the faculty of Intuition that quality of the mind
which can take in a number of causes simultaneously and Instantly de
duce a conclusion an essential in successful aviation.
BECAUSE her specific gravity fs Itfss than man's.
BECAUSE she needs less oxygen and tnerefore can better meet the
suffocating rush of air. Altitude effects her less than ft does man.
BECAUSE her sneezes, In man an actual spasm, have been controlled
by ages of polite repression
BECAUSE she feels more quickly warning atmospheric changes.
BECAUSE she loves to speed.
Ww JET Mm Ef 4m JUHF V SSf &rai
mW Bf Mr MW Mr Mr MWmW Wr fi&JBr Mfjti& Mr s& Mr Smw Wm is
F MW Mw MY MY m Mm SB E2& Bz8 5risS&&'& 4"" $m$M Wm&
JJm JIj&sT mm m
lmmmmXBmlkSi&&Kji$s3k!il.-L fWvmWmMmmmmwmWk Tiff! '1 1 T fm 1 H!'T'flrTTffTfipifiHM T1nifr lnrtifffTjnlBHMtWBB A ilftf MeSwSE9HHHsP9K
tomwHmr iijffii wPvimBmHm IHbHbi
a i t..- .x. alKgM&g-. jd. flHransHBKr BBBB'wPBiK akBMHKBiibft
fffrV? SSrA Tn fcy- JWJs Harriet Quinby. m TTS
WOMBN -will rale the air!
They are the naftural avia
tors. -N
History repeats itself. Men by the
score will Have died the death in
the air before aerial navigation is
safe. Then w oraan, the- cautious, the
conservative, the primitive, will step
in and rale.
Why is the air woman's own do
main? The answer is perfectly
'plain to both psychologists and
physiologists.
The periphery, the outer rim of
a woman's retina, Is as sensitive to
objects as is Its centre. A woman
can look- away from you and still
see you.
Her arc of sight is almost twice
that of man's, in whom, as a rale,
the periphery of the retina is ex
tremely blunted to impressions. Try
the experiment of having a woman
look straight ahead and telling you
how much she still can see on each
'Bide of her without directly looking
at the objects.
There is a deep psychological rea
son for this. Primitive man, who,
surrounded by dangers, had to keep
looking on every side at once, had,
it is probable, almost periscopic
sight, such as the birds have. He
could never know what side d&Bgss,
was coming from, and so eves
though looking ahead, his retina,
sensitised to the rims, caught Im
pressions necessary to warn him of
enemies or of game.
Ever since woman has been the
subject of man she has practised
modesty. Sh has been forced to
go along with downcast eyes. And
yet her coqeettry has enforced upon
her the necessity of seeing. The
accomplished flirt has the peripheral
sensitiveness to the maximum but
every woman has it more or less.
Walking with averted eyes for fear
of husband or lover, she still sees
every male and female that goes
by her. She has retained this primi
tive retinal faculty.
By experiments at Harvard and
Vienna and at Paris, a woman's
arc of sight has been, measured.
The accompanying diagram shows
its relation to man's and to the
bird's. Manifestly the sight, which
more closely approaches the peris
copic, is better adapted for flying,
else a blrd would net have de
veloped this sight. A twig moving
far to his right in his field of vision
may be the signal of a hidden
enemy to the bird; in the same way
The Retina of a Woman's Ejre Every Part Sensitive to
Impressions. The Sketch Shows the Faculty in Action.
The Retina of a Man's Eye the Periphery Blunted to Impres-
The Sketch Shows His Necessarily Direct Gaze.
SKms.
JOHEX have entered the con
test for the laurels of the
thy. Miss Harriet Ouinbv.
the first woman aviator to receive
a pilot's Keens from the Aero Club
of America, has eeen followed 6jr
Miss Matilda Moisant, sister of the
unfortunate John B. Moisant. who
lost his life after having made an
enviaolcname for himself in avia
tion. According to Professor Rudolph
Hensingmuller, of Vienna University,
science foresees woman's domination
of the sky.- She will he the better
aviator, because she's the better flirt
On the other hand. Mr. Claud"
Grahame-White, the English aviator
and instructor declares that women
joill never achieve glory in the air
The arguments of these two authori.
Ues are presented in full on this page
WWHiHf
This Diagram
Shows the
Comparative
Arcs of Sight
of Man,
Woman and
Bird.
Woman's
(in the
Centre),
by Reason
of Retinal
Periphery
Sensitiveness,
More Closely
Approaches
The Retina of an Owl's Eye Sensitive Equally in All Parts.
The Black Centre Is the Nerve-Feeding Blood Vessel.
No Place in the Air for Women
By Claude Grahame-White,
I HAVE taught many women to fly and
I regret it My. experience has taught
me that the air is no place for a
woman.
When calamity overtakes my women pu
pils, as sooner or later I fear it will, I
shall feel in a way responsible for their
sodden decease.
I have often taken ray. mother and my
sister in the air as passengers. They un
derstand aviation thoroughly. But I would
never let them fly alone.
The truth Is that women lack qualities
which make for safety in aviation. They
are temperamentally unfitted for the sport
Bravery and courage are not essential
in aviation. Supreme confidence in one's
self a Women may possess the former,
but they generally lack the latter Safety
in an areoplane depends upor absolute
coolness the facultj of rpj.1,1 j jurat-
the Leading English Aviator.
tied," If I may use the word, no matter
what happens. Men sometimes possess this
faculty, but It Is very rare In women.
Professor Hensingmuller may be correct
In his premises, but the conclusions he
draws from them are not sustainable.
Thus women may possesa a greater
range of vision than men, although I have
never heard the proposition advanced be
fore, but that will not make them better
aviators, for a greater range of vision is
not needed. The aviator has all he can do
to look straight ahead, and the power to
see further to the right and left would
prove at all serviceable.
Gusts of wind and currents aTe not vis
ible. As a matter of fact their presence
can usually be felt long before they affect
the planes. Woman's superior vision
would therefore be of no value to her In
that respect
It Is said also that women have greater
tuition than men. That may be so', but I
I.do not think that the kind of Intuition
they possess Jn such abundance would be
of any practical use in aviation.
Diffused attention, too, would be mtre
xof a handicap than an advantage. What
the aviator needs more than anything else
is the ability to concentrate his mind on his
levers.
It is true that women are lighter than
men. It is equally true, however, that
weight will be of no conseouence In the
aeroplane of the f utare, except perhaps that
the greater the weight the more effective
will be the aeroplane. The future aero
plane will be of steel wood and canvas
will be eliminated.
As far as woman's milder manner ot
sneezing Is concerned I cannot see how
that will be of advantage. In view of the
fact that, in my own experience, I have
never found It necessary to sneeze at all
while In the air.
I do not believe that aviation increases
the. tendency to sneeze, nor shouM I con
sider it of the slightest Importance even if
it did. It takes considerably more than a
sneeze to wreck an aeroplane, or even to
disconcert an aviator.
The sense of balance comes to the avia
tor naturally. One elevates or lowers his
planes almost Instinctively, the same as
one turns the handle-bars in bicycling or
varies the stroke in swimming or tennis.
In these instantaneous motions there Is no
time for consideration. Instinct takes the
place of foresight. I do not think that
women are better equipped in this respect
than men. t is rather a matter of experi
ence than natural fitness.
ftls true that with one or two excep
tions women aviators have so far escaped
serious accidents, it must be remembered
however, that their efforts have been con
fined exclusively to aerodrome flights
which is a very different proposition to
cross-country work and the hazardous
achievements undertaken by men.
When the airship becomes absolutely
safe, lis It will, women may make good
aviators, but they will never dominate the
air to the exclusion or iron uiv more than
they have domlna id an., utbei similar
sphere of activity
Mllll-Il Tnnmmi
B" mmm I j""", the
Mr.
Claude Grahame-White, Who Says Women Have No Place in the Air,
Taking up a Feminine Passenger
it may mean danger in a snddea
gust of wind to the aviator.
Diffused attention is the opposite
of concentration. Woman has the
first, man has the second. By dif
fused attention we mean the quality
of mind that can take in a number
of details at once. This is also x
prlmtlve Quality. The savage need
ed it while going through the
woods, and for the same reasons
that be needed peripheral sensi
tiveness of his retina.
Throughout the ages man has
steadily, single-mi&dedly concen
trated upon a particular point
Woman's attention has been di
rected to her. babies, to the care of
them, to her household duties, to
the manifoI task of pleasing her
lord and master, and most of these
things she has had to consider
practically all at once.
The advantages of dtttassd atten.
tJon In flying are obvious. Where
the contour of the grooad, the an
pearance of the sky, the sound of
the motor, the "feeding" of the ma
chine, and a hundred other things,
must be taken into consideration
and weighed all at once. Only dif
fused attention of the most expert
kind can make a perfect aviator.
the birds. Her bones are lighter
and more hollow than those of maa.
Her specific gravity is less
As a rale, her sight is "better
She craves excitement, and has
more nervons endurance than man.
Watch the speed machines at your
parks the toboggans, the slides, eta
See the percentage of women to
men. Once she is assured that a
t5u,Ji,"'VBd lf te Wstkm
of speed, she becomes a speed
maniac It is woman who promote
man to go fast in his autos'SK
take her on the chute-the-chntes.
She has more intuttlon. Intuluoa
is nothing more than the powers
rapidly percelvta a number of
causes and Instantaneously synthe-
Hf A woma cannot do
this in abstract subjects, but to
crete subjects, in her surroundings
SS ""k 5f r faInd te oallow-b?t
JX eaects nunber of things
ed mind of man cannot Intuition
is an essential in aeroplanlng
Her skin and her nervoug system
are. as a rule, more susceptible to
rapid, warning atmospheric changes.
Religion has foreshadowed this by
picturing angels as feminine.
Some aviators have pointed out
that high altitudes and strong winds
create a tendency to sneeze, which
in many cases proves disastrous. It
Is well known that women sneeze In
a milder manner than men.' and Is
thl resnoor therefore, they have
another natural qualification for
aviation which men lack.
Better equipped naturally than
man for this new sphere, she must
eoiuuoB "Wire man out of It,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1913-04-13/ed-1/?sp=21&q=Harriet+Quimby</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>TheO
maha Sunday Bee Magazine Page
Copyright 1(13, bjr tha Star Company, Great Drttaln ntRhta ReaerreO.
m
"WOMEN Will Rule the Air
s f
No. 1 The Skeleton of
the Bat., IlIun(ra(lnK the
QBadrupedil or "All
F"otiru" roaltlon of Firing.
The Primitive Tendency of
of Woman Ttmnrd That
Poaltlon Glrea Her One Ail
rnntnge Over Man In Ilun
nlng? the Aeroplane.
No. 2 The Skeleton of a
Knntcnrno. The Gigantic
I.eapN of Thla Animal Are
Made Poaalhle Largely by
Ita Combination of Up
right nnd All Foura Attl
tude a Poaltlon Into
Which Woman S t n k a
Naturally When Piloting
on Aeroplane.
No. 3 The Skeleton of a
Snnkr. The llrptllr, Al
though It Orliclnally
Sprung: from the Same An
ceator aa the Iilrd, Una a
Compactneaa of Skeletal
Strnoture Which Man
Bharea In a Leaatr Deirree
T hat Abanlutely For
bid It from Flylngr.
'No. 4 The Skeleton of
a lllrd. in I.lshtnraa of
Frame nnd Structure It
More Cloaely Ilearmlilra
the Skeletal Formation
of Women, Whoan Spc
clflc Gravity, the Sclen
.tlata flay, la Leas Than
Mau'a.
No. ft The Skeleton of
n Man. The Jlonra Aro
Heavier and More Com
pact Than That of
Woman. The Cheat la
Larger, Showing the
Need for More Air a
Matter of Importance In
Itartfled Atmoaphtrea,
No. 8 The Skeleton
of a Woman. The
8 1 1 g a t Differences
Between It and That
of the Man Glvea
Her an Eaormoua
Advantage and Pota
Her More on a Level
rrlth the Creaturea
That Fly Naturally,
Better Than Men for Flying Because They Are More Primitive, Not So High
Strung, Feel Pain Less, See More, HavelSJo Concentration, Sneeze Less
Heavily and Are Closer to the QuadrupedsClaims the French Government,
Making
Its Foremost
Woman
Aviator a
Chevalier
to Encourage
Others
Vlllo. Dutrieu, the Daring French
Woman Aviator, Who Has Been
Made a Chevalier pf the Legion of
Honor hy the French Government.
MLLH. HBLENB DUTRIEU, the "Hawk
Girl of Franco," has just been made
a Chevalier of the Legion of Honor
as a reward for her skill as an aviator. Mile.
Dutrieu Is one of few women to receive this
decoration.
France has g,lven it to her because the Bu
reau of War has become convinced that
women make better aviators than men, and
so, In Its struggle to perfect Its aeroplane
Bervlce, wishes to encourage women to enter
that field of action!
The great ambition of the French Is to keep
far ahead of all other nations In aviation.
The belief that the victories of the future
will 'belong to those who aro strongest In
the air has becomo firmly Ingrained in the
national mind. Therefore, France Is spend
ing more than any other nation on this
branch of service and is making extended
and varied researches into the problems and
possibilities of aviation. In the course of
these experiments, not long ago, a series of
tests were made to determine the effects of
altitude and speed on tho human body and to
test the reactions under the conditions of
flvlnit Both men and women were used in
the experiments, and when the results were
tallied It was found that the woman had far
outstripped the men on all Points'
Other experiments were made and the ex
perts in charge, as a result, have come to
the surprising conclusion that woman make
n much better aeroplane drivers than do
men that In the future she will literally rule
thThelr'report of the scientists to the -Var
Department, as cabled from Paris, gives eight
controlling factors for this supremacy:
First Because woman is more primitive
than man.
Second Her nerves are not so delicate,
and so she is less nervous.
Third she feels pain less than man does.
Fourth She needs less oxygen In her
br?fth The arc of her sight Is nearly double
that of man. A
Sixth She has tho faculty of "diffused at
tention," which man ordinarily lacks.
Seventh That her specific gravity Is less
than man's and that the slight differences
in her skeletel structure givo her an enor
mous advantage in the air over her heavier,
more compact mate.
Eighth That her sneeze is less violent.
Tho perfect aviator, says tho report, am
plifying these points, needs not nerve, but
comparative nervolcssnoss. The possession
of what is called "nerve" implies a psycho
logical conflict In which courage is continu
ally overcoming fear. The truly courageous
man is ho who fears something mightily, but
who goos on and fights in spite of his fear.
The man who "never knew what fear Is" Is
not truly courageous, In tho higher sense,
because It does not requlro courage to fight
something of which wo nro not afraid.
The "hlghor courage" is positively detri
mental to tho aviator, tho experimenters say,
because the psychological conflict between
"nerve" and fear uses up energy and koops
the aviator at a tension which does not al
low tho highest efficiency as a flier. Conse
quently, the typo that makes the perfect avi
ator is the one that is nerveless, who has no
conception of fear and faces tho perils of the
air courageously because ho does not recog
nize that there are any perils.
Woman, it was found, has this quality to
a surprising degree. She has It because she
Is still the primitive sex, has doveloped less
than man, not only physlologlqally, but psy
chologically. Back In a far distant age man and
woman were almost equally nerveless. But
man's activities caused him to acquire finer
and more delicate nerves. Ho has steadily
become more nervous and more sensitive to
pain. This incapacitates him for tho con
quest of the air, while woman's lack in these
respects fits her for it.
The comparative Insensibility to pain is
important because many an aviator has
dropped to death because tho stinging cold
of the upper altitudes has caused him, mo
mentarily, to lose control of his machine.
Again, in driving an aeroplane, the avi
ator's position is more nearly quadrupedal
than in any other form of locomotion. The
aviator almost literally flies on all fours. Ho
does this because ho can attain the best
balance in this position. Here the same
prlmltlveness which gives woman the lead
in nervelcssness also comes to her aid. Sho
is of structure more nearly the quadruped
than-1b man. It is more natural and easier
for her to drop on all fours and she can get
about more freely In that posture than man
A Photograph of
the Late Harriet
Quimby, the
Queen of Amer
ican Flying
Women and One
of the Very Few
Women to Lose
Their Lives in
Aviation. She Is
Shown Climbing
Into Her Aero
plane.
airship pilot than the breast of tho Missis
sippi is to the steamboat pilot and Mark
Twain has told of their complexities. The
peripheral sensitiveness of woman enables
her to see these signs whero man's concen-
can. Dr. Havelock Ellis makes the assertion trated sight misses them
that the realization that woman "is still an
atomically a quadruped Is the greatest sur
gical triumph of the nineteenth century." In
this connection he defended woman's use of
the corset, saying that it !s needed to keep
organs designed by nature for a horizontal
position, In a vertical one.
Man having learned what woman haB only
Imperfectly learned, to stand upright, needs
no corset. This quadrupedal tendency, to
gether with the fact that her bones aro
lighter and she has less specific gravity than
man, aids her In flying, as It does in swim
ming. When timidity does not restrain them
women are much better Bwlmmers than men.
The field of woman's sight is larger than
man's. The report states it thus: "The arc
of a woman's vision is nearly twice that of
man." In other words, while man, trained
to concentrate his sight upon one object, sees
with only a limited part, tho centre, of the
retina of his eye, woman, through centuries of
slde-glanclng habits, of looking, so to speak,
out of the tall of her eye, hw kept the faculty
of sight throughout tho periphery of her re
tina. While looking straight ahead she can
see what la happening at either side of her
and for a short distance behind her. This
power she shares with the savage and most
of the lower animals the rabbit and she be
ing about equal in this respect.
The faculty Is enormously valuable In tho
air. Graham-White, among others, has Bald
that it is of the utmost Importance to the
aviator to be able to see every change in the
skies above him and the land about him.
Trees moving in a breeze far to the left may
be a danger signal, which will mean disaster
to the airman it not heeded. So of changes
in clouds. The country under and the air
about are filled with more slcns to the perfect
In tho same way what the late great
psychologist, William James, called her,
"dispersed attention," helps her. Man's ad
vancement has developed in him a tremen
dous power of concentration. This his primi
tive spouse, or sister, lacks. Man concen
trates his attention. Woman scatters hers.
Man thinks of one thing at a time. Woman
tries to think of many things nt the samo
moment and succeeds. Tho span of conscious
ness Is wider in woman even if it Is .shallower.
Consuming less oxygen than man she 1b a
shallower breather she Is loss affecod by
the thin air of high altitudes.
For theao and other reasons cited In tho
remarkable statement by tho distinguished
New York, physician, Dr. A. Monao Lesser,
former chief surgeon of the lied Ctobh In tho
United States, and leader of tho Eed CroBS
forces in Cuba during the war with Spain,
tho French Army Department has ddtermlned
to recruit as many women as possible In Us
flying corps. A spoclal law will hava
to bo passed making them eligible to
army service.
Tho French aro tho most gallant ot
nations. But thoy repudiate the sug
gestion that they aro crowning women
queenB of the nlr to make up for tho
slight put upon them by art, which
never carved or painted a woman an
gel. Their course Is a sternly practical
one, thoy Bay, and Mile. Dutrleu's ele
vation to the ranks of a Chevalier la only
part of a practical campaign.
Dr. Lessor's statement follows:
Why HOME-LOVING Woman is the Best Air Woman
By Dr. A. Monae Lesser.
(Former Chief Surgeon of the Ped Cross
of America.)
THERE is truth in the contention that
woman because of her primitive
qualities may yet rule the air. But
tho type of woman who will do so is the
quiet, stay-at-home woman tho housekeeper,
housewife and mother.
That it should be she, the woman of the
hearth, Instead of the woman ot public ac
tion, is capable of Bclontlflc proof. Since
the dim ages of the world, when men and
women were of equal prlmltlveness, man
has developed far, and a penalty ot his
mighty concentration has been an acute ten
sion of the nervous system and a correspond
ing seusltiveneBs to pain.
If men were called upon to bear the pain
that i'j visited upon women, especially in
maternity, they would suffer doubly, and
many of them would die. Even lesser pains
ordinarily borne by women would send
them running about the house screaming.
They could not enduro what women bear
because women have a greater capacity for
suffering. All this is due to their: greater
nerve tension, which has come with their
greater advanco from prlmltlveness.
Tho greater nerve tension haB produced
a different kind of nerves. Scattered
through the membranes of their bodies are
nerves of a finer, more delicate order. Men
sneeze more violently than women because
in the membrane lining of the noao are a
finer grade of nerves, more delicate, moro
sensitive to intruding dust or to changes of
temperature.
The woman who has developed along
lines of domesticity has little or no such
nervous sensitiveness. Her sensibilities are
coarser, because they have never been de
veloped to the knlfo-llko edge of man's. It
is not, according to some aeronauts Claude
Graham White, I bellevo among them not
nerve, but lack of nervousness, that makes
great aeronauts, Nervousness during an
ascent Is fatal. That state which we term
"nervelessness," tho absence of finely attuned
nerves, is better than courage In an emer
gency. Imperturbability Is a safeguard, and the
woman of low order ot nervousness 1b im
purturbable.
One type of woman should be barred from
the air, and she, unfortunately, la the kind
that would rush Into it. That 1b the worn at.
who Is the opposite of the primitive the
advanced woman.
In the last hundred years a minority of
women has developed enormously in men
tality, and In tho ncuteness of nervous or
ganization that accompanies a high order of
mentality.
This minority of their sex has developed
with men, equally with them, and their
nerves have attenuated to the fineness I
have described. These are sterile women,
women who aro childless, and who have de
veloped almost abnormally their minds
Such as these, laboring under all the disa
bilities of men by the fineness of their
nervous organism, should never be permit
ted to make an ascent.
Take a woman from the nursery, from tho
Ironing table or from beside tho kitchen
range, but not a woman from tho desk or
studio, to make the conquest of the alrl
In such a woman as I first described the
primitive qualities have remained the
"peripheral visual attention" which William
James cites, the "dispersed attention." the
lack of necessity of the violent sneeze. The
other sort is too highly developed, too man
like, too highly strung for successful aer'V
feats,
Mr.. Gavin, an EnglUk Worn,
an 'Aviator to Whom EncIanJ
Will Givo Victoria Crow.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1914-07-07/ed-1/?sp=10&q=air+flight+FLYING+flying+WOMEN+women</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>"FLYING NO JOB FOR WOMEN!" GREATEST
WOMAN FLYER SAYS SO
fi&j i "j ?tvfr' jKLJ IS Mri
"Plying is no job for women and
never will be!
"Nature herself has forbidden
them to risk their lives foolishly in
the air. Through the mother in
stinct in them Nature will hold them
always close to mother earth."
It was one of the most expert of
the world's six licensed birdwomen
who, at my question, thus excluded'
the rest of her sex from participation
in the great air game of which she
herself is a master.
Mrs. Richberg Hornsby of Chicago
is the first and only pupil of Orville
Wright.
"The prettiest flying I ever saw. a
beginner do!" was Wright's exclama
tion, twice repeated, during "Mrs.
Hornsby's trials.
During the flight which has just
won her the license, her plane was</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1914-11-01/ed-1/?sp=51&q=aviators+women&st=text&r=-0.226,-0.073,1.452,1.452,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Fighting Corps From the
Many Charming, Daring
and Skilled Flying
Women of
m England
ifc'i?
and
France
w I7*s*r
Lady Victoria Pery, the Prettiest
of the Bold English Airwomen
A London, Oct. 2.">.
PROPOSAL lias been made to or
ganize a corps of women aviators
to servo with the allied armies of
England and Prance, now lighting the
Germans.
The idea Jsas oeon received with en
thusiasm by many women, who reject the
ancient theory of feiyinine weakness and
declare that their sex is fully as lit to t'aee
peril as the men.
The aviators have proved themselves
one of the most valuable factors in the
war. There is a great need of more of
them, and it* is impossible to train them in
a hurry. This Is one of the strongest
reasons urged in favor of using the many
skilled women aviators in the lighting.
The suggestion has actually appeared in
print that Lady Victoria May Pery, daugh
ter of the Earl of Limerick, i.hould become
chief of a British royal feminine flying
corps.
Lady Victoria is 0*e of the most dashing
jidJ certaluly the prettiest of English
women aviators. She was trained in avia
tion by Graharae White and the late, Gnstav
Hamel. in whoso company she "looped the
loop" in al most daring manner. Mantel
was eventually killed while doing this
trick.
It is not likely, however, that Lady Vic
toria will take the suggestion and join the
fighting aviation corps, for she has gone
to the United States and there become the
bride of Mr. James C. Brady. We have
probably not yet reached the point where
a bride will interrupt, her honeymoon to
go off to the war, aft^r the fashion of the
German submarine captain who left his
bride of the before to steam away and
blow up three British warships.
There are, however, plenty of English
women and French women without en
cumbrances who are ready to fight in the
air corps.
Why should not women serve as military
aviators? They have the courage and the
skill. They have the patriotism. If they
are inferior in weight ahd muscle to men,
these qualities are not of the first im
portance to the aviator. In steadiness and
nerve, which are the essential qualities in
the air, the modern girl claims to be fully
the equal of her brother.
?Is it contrary to the principles of civiliza
tion and humanity to expose gentle women
to physical hardships and the horrors of
war? This argument has largely been dis
posed of in recent discussions. Women are
employed in all sorts of occupations that
shorten and endanger life.
It has now been proved' that in every
war many women have fought, very'cred
itably, In spite of all rules against their par
ticipating. Many women took part in the
last. Balkan war, and it fs already certain
that a considerable number of French
women ere now fighting.
Women are freely risking their lives
with the Red Cross forces and as nurses
in other* organizations at the front. Many
W of these nurses have already been
killed, and there is little doubt that
oth??rK will be. N'o one seems to have
any strong objection to the employ
ment of women nurses at the front.
Tim prejudice is-not-against their
risking their lives, but against their
becoming combatants.
[?*rom all this It appears clear that If
conventional restrictions were removed
there would be a very great number of
effective women combatants.
And if they are to fight, why not in the
air. where their nerve and daring would
be of most value?
One of the most daring of women avia
tors is Mademoiselle Helene Dutrieu. of
France. She was the first woman to per-,
form the loop-the-loop trick, that "death
defying stunt that made men's blood stand
s;ill when they first saw a man do it
.Mademoiselle Dutrieu did it as coolly and
cleverly as any man.
.She is a tall, siender girl with an ex
quisite figure, as supplfc as a bamboo and
as strong as steel.
She,has carried a man passenger very
ot\en. and is therefore well qualified for
war aviation, in which two persons in a
machine are almost a necessity.
Mademoiselle Dutrit?V received the
Legion of Honor decoration for her ex
ploits. She would undoubtedly make a
daring leader of fighting aviators.
Among the many brilliant French air
women arr> Madame Francis, Mademoiselle
Julienne Marehnl, the Baroness Raymonde
do la Roche, Mademoiselle Marvingt- and
Mademoiselle Valentine Duels.
The Baroness Raymonde de la Roche
started flying at Mourmejon and broke her.
arm in oye of her first flights, in Egypt
she flew over the Sphinx and the Pyramids.
At St. Petersburg she .flew over the city
anil was warmly congratulated by the Czar.
She flew over Budapest', in Hungary
In one of her first attempts she came
near having a faial accident, and many
people thought the experience would rob
her of her nerve completely. She was
t arried by the wind over a clump-of trees.
She did her best to avoid them with a swift
turn of the aeroplane rudder, but the ma
chine, rushing through the air at express
train speed, touohed the topmost branches,
and with a whirling crash it came sweep
ing to the ground and was wrecked irre
trievably.
Instantly the spectators rushed to the
spot, expecting to pick up the body of
the aviator, but the Baroness extricated
herself from the debris qtiiie unhurt and
not at all frightened. Indeed, she laughed
at the startled faces about Iter and said
calmly:
"An uncomfortable experience, it is true,
but I rather expected it."
The next day she was in the air again
with a new machine.
Mademoiselle Marvingt began her train
ing with two men, Wnchter and Laffont,
who were subsequently killed. This did
not daunt her, and she went, on and won
a cup for flying women.'
Miss Eleanor Trehawko Davies has the
reputation of being the i\ij>st daring of
English aviatric.es. She has flown across
the 'English Channel several times.\On
one occasion, when crossing with Oust^v
Hamel, she saved them both by working
the second -pressure pump, when he was
partly benumbed with cold, at a height of
$,000 feet.
Phot o at Pa u c T t? s -v y.
Mile. Helene Dutrieu. -Who Looped-the-Loop, One of the
Most Daring of French Aviatrices.
Mrs. C?avin is anotner during Kngiisn
woman whe- has flown across tlie Chan
nel. She practised aviation In tlfe ]>art of
France where the war is now ragiug, ami
could give valuable assistance to thg/avmy.
Miss Spencer Kavanagh has aiso-dis
tinguished herself as an aviator. Miss
Kananagh has also been a sportswoman,
having hunted, broken horses, driven auto
mobiles in races and gone in for athletic
contests. She wished to learn to fly as
soon as it became known that it was a
possible achievement, and went to Pau, de
termined to master the art.
She tises the Bleriot monoplane, which
has been likened to a great dragon fly
when in flight. She has had some bad
accidents and was. laid up with a broken
wrist for a while. She lias learned to con
trol the machine now, and like other avia
tors she takes the dangers as part of the
game.
She is an attractive figure in her neat,
tight, red clotli skirt and flannel blouse,
with red cloth cap fastened under her chin,
after the fashion in which Mile. Dutrieu
wears hers.
Women who are learning to fly are
sometimes taught on a rather peculiar
Mrs. Gavin, an English
Woman, Who Has
Flown Across the Eng
lish Channel to France
and Back.
mechanism, which is arranged to operate
like tiiri aeroplane, but has no wings. It
has ail the controls like au aeroplaue
nud rims about on the ground like
an automobile. Uy permitting the pupil
to absorb the feel of riding in an
aeroplane it "is possible to save her some
bruises, perhaps broken bones ana costly
repairs to the flying machine. Every time
an aeroplane comes into unwilj' >g col'
li.sion witli the ground the owner is poorer
by any sum ranging from $:?0o to $:!,000.
A French scientist. Dr. Babin, has re
The Baroness Iiaymonde de la Roche, One of the French Airwomen Who Wish
to Serve Their Country.
ceutly deinonstrated that woman is better
lilted for flying than man. for these rea
sons
First?Because woman is more primitive
than man.
Second?Her nerves are not so delicate,
and so she. is less nervous.
Third?she feels pain less than man
does.
Fourth?She needs less oxygen in-her
breathing.
Fifth?The arc of Iter sight is nearly
double that of man.
Sixth?She lias the faculty of "diffused
ntteutiou." which', man ordinarily lacks.
Seventh?That her specific gravity is
less than man's, and that the slight differ
ences in her skeletal,structure give Iter ai<
enormous advantage in the tfir over her
.heavier, more compact mate.
Eighth?That her sneeze is less violent.
"The perfect aviator.*' says the doctor's
report, amplifying those points, "needs, not
nerve, but comparative nervelessness. The
possession of what is called 'norvo' implies
a psychological conflict in which courage
is continually overcoming fear. The truly
courageous man is lie who fears something
mightily, but who goes on and fights in
spite of his fear. The man* who 'never
know what fear is' is not truly courageous
in the higher sense, because it does not re
quire courage to fight, something of* which
we ?re not afraid.
"The 'higher courage.' is positively detri
mental to the aviator, because the psy
chological conflict between ?nerve" and fear
uses u|) energy and keeps the aviator at a
tension which does not allow the highest
efficiency as a flier. Consequently tin; type
that uiakes the .perfect aviator is the one
that is nerveless, who has no conception
of fear, and faces the perils of tlic air
courageously because ho does not recog
nize that there are any perils.
?Woman has'this quality to a surprising
degree. She has it because she is still
Hie primitive sex, has doveloped less than,
man, not only physiologically, but psy
chologically. Hack in a far distant ago
man and woman were almost nerveless.
Uut mau'?s activities caused him to acquire
liner and more delicate nerves. He has
steadily become more* nervous and moro
sensitive to pain. This incapacitates liim
for the conquest of tho air. while woman's
?laclt in those respccts Ills lier for it.
'"The comparative insensibility to pain
is important, tor many an aviator has
dropped to deuiu because the stinging eold
of the upper altitudes had- caused him
momentarily to lose control of his machine.
"Again, in driving an aeroplane the avia
tor's ]K>sition is more nearly quadrupedal
Mityi in any other form of locomotion. Q^ke
aviator almost literally Hies on all fours.
He does this because he can attain tho
best, balance in this position. Here^ihe
same primitiveness which gives woman
the lead in uervelessuess also comes, to
'her aid. She is of structure more nearly
the quadruped than is man. It is more
natural and easier tor her to drop on all
fours, and she can get about more freely
in i hat posture than man can."
A fearful prospect is thus sketched lor
ilie ordinary foot soldier tracked by a
hawk-like woman of the air.
Primitive, nerveless, quadrupedal ...in
structure, ignorant of danger and con
temptuous of the other sex, she planes
above him, ready to annihilate him, calmly
ami coldly, with high explosives or blaziug
gasoline! y</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1915-07-18/ed-1/?sp=33&q=aeroplane+Moisant+MOISANT&st=text&r=0.255,0.598,0.401,0.453,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MISS MOISANT ura the next American no.
man after her friend Miss Qiiimby to be
granted a pilot's license. She ascribes her gooil 1
t fortune in her flights to her lucky number 13,
i which is always attached to her machine. She
was taught to fly by her famous brother. Once
she escaped from an angry sheriff by aeroplane.
fust as Brave as Me]
Vk/
T3LAXCI1K STUART SCOTT'S excellent driving was first notice
when, as a motorist, she took a transcontinental trip in one of th
Glidden tours. She learned aviation at the Curtiss school, and made
record in a remarkable cross-country flight to Garden City, Long Islam
i, i in i
J
ttlfl H|
Copyright, li. V. Diuk.
pERNETTA ADAMS MILLER is a young
American pilot of the Moisant school, ana
flies a Bleriot type monoplane. There are now
about fifty women fliers, and their accident rate
has been no higher than that of men aviators.
Vf ATII.DE MOISANT was rescued from this burning
1 machine while flying at Wichita, Texas. This photograph,
the only one made of the accident, was taken by an
amateur.
fl
ie
rpHISu Mrs. Maw
^X J rjjf j"
machine that Mrs.
^ttj?, Hewlett has used a
/e^^. B great deal to demonstrate
her
PELTIER
was
woman
make an as
Dela^^^^HISRIr

fcy
j^V
I wine of his

1 1
IJARHIKT Ql'IMBY, journalist, uiitneuedan
aeroplane race for the first time in 1910.
-1 Two months later she was an efficient pilot. Miss
Quimby was the first American woman to receive
a pilot's license, the first to steer a monoplane.
and the first to cross the English Channel.
She met death in 1912 at Boston.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85059732/1915-08-01/ed-1/?sp=32&q=aeroplane+crowd+death+Grand</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>H?w the Daring
Oi ft J8 First Woman
tfj[ Belgium, Has
Aided in the Guarding of Paris by Night
and Day, and Three Times Was Able to
Give Warning of the Approach of the
Enemy?She Says: "The Man Who Wants
Me Must Catch Me in the Air."
Helena Dutrieu, Just Before Making One of Her
Sensational Flights.
HELENS DUTRIEU, the "Girl
Hawk," upon whom appre
ciative France has bestowed
the decoration of tht> Legion of
Honor, Is surely one of the most
modest of heroines and Is less In
clined to dwell upon the fact that
she has the distinction of being the
first woman air scout In history than
?he Is to discuss generally the use
of the aeroplane In war.' She re
cently -was In this cfluntry In the
interests of the Red Cross, and Is
a sort of Elzevir edition of a flying
woman, being about only five feet
In height, even with the aid of her
dainty French heels, and weighing
about 1X0 pounds. She Is a girl In
vivacity and enthusiasms, and, ac
cording to one Impressionable wom
an visitor, "her mouth Is tilted In
an adorable childish fashion"?the
mouth that playfully uttered the
grim laconism In referring to avia
tion: "It is the sport of those who
would die young."
Mile. Dutrleu's complexion has
the exotic charm of a dead pallor,
which only goes to emphasize her
large and expressive oyei. You
might Justly mistake her for an
artist, a dreamer, poet, musician?
one who has spent the best mo
ments of her life amid intangible
beautiful Imaginings and exquisite
realities. Her well-formed hands,
with their tapering fingers, suggest
pretty sentiment, lace, perfume, ro
mance more than the tense, peril
ous work of guiding an aeroplane
through the blue seas of night high
abqye an anxious city.
An Unofficial Flyer
She Is not regularly enrolled In
the army, and, though she gladly
would die for her country, she has
no desire to become a soldier. That
the government receives her ser
vices unofficially gives her no of
fence at all. She fully agrees with
the Frenchman's point of view on
the sex question.
"He does not want his wife to
fight," she explains. "He will not
permit her life to be endangered.
He will not be responsible for her
death. Not that the French woman
Is not brave. All women are brave
when the lives of their dear ones
are threatened. But especially the
French woman. I think, for she is
more emotional. Ah, people now.
Just because of this war, are be
ginning to understand the character
of the French woman as she really
ts! All the fables of her lightness
In their true colors."
Gave Warning Thrice.
Mile. Dutrleu would make you
believe that some of the perils
through which she passed In times
of peace far overshadow thoso of
the war period, and laughs when
khe quotes a report that her duty
was to cnase away the raiding Ger
man taubes that dropped bombs
upon Paris. "All I did was to fly
up when I suspected that the Ger
man airmen were coming," she ex
plained, "and, then, if I observed
the enemy approaching, return and
report to the men, who immediately
rose to give battle or chase to the
Intruder."
When word was flashed to Paris,
Che boarded her aeroplane and took
to the skies, mounting in spirals
iilsfter and hlghc* until the plane
looked the size of a soaring dragou
fly. Then courageously would she
fly In the direction of the expectod
danger, circling round, rising and
descending with eyes kf-ou to the
Quest and nerves as steady as the
snetal of the mechanism that held
her afloat above the city. from the
streets of which thousands turned
their faces upward to watch, not
for the hostile taubes as much a3
to watch, adinlre and marvel at the
Intrepid "Girl Hawk."
Three times when the Germans
were advancing on Paris did she
give warning of their approach, her
swift monoplane affording her a
long advantage over the enemy.
"There was no danger," she says
simply. But there Is always danger
even the lay public knows, the fact
being emphasized by the peaceful
accident which ended the life of
the young Englishman, the first to
destroy a Zeppelin, who, after tak
ing part In the greatest of aerial
war achievements and escaping as
by a miracle, was dashed to death
when in the act of taking up an
American correspondent for an ex
hibition flight. Keen as are the
eyes of Mile. Dutrieu and skilled as
she is in the operation of her craft,
there was always the possibility of
sudden and unexpected onslaught
from the hostile craft; then there
was the peril which is always at
the elbow of those who adventure
Into the skies.
Bruges Chimed Her Honors.
She had already fallen from a
house during an accident in Odessa
and escaped without serious hurt.
Her monoplane had turned turtle
with her at Issy-les-Mollneaux and
she escaped only with a severe
shaking up, having been saved by
the upper stays of the machine.
She has had many another close
call. Always glad to escape the
discussion of the graver aspects of
the work, especially as it conce'rns
herself. Mile. Dutrieu very soberly
says that she felt one of the great
est elatlons c? her life when she
flew high above the historical belfry
of I-.es Halles at Bruges, celebrated
by Longfellow.
As the people wildly cheered In
the streets, the bells pealed out in
her honor whlJe she circled above
the structure and then flew back to
Ostend, carrying a passenger. But
no greater and yet scarcely justifled
apprehension did she ever reel,
looking into the face of danger and
sudden death, than that which
seized her when, on her arrival at
Ostend, she had to be protected
from a joyously hysterical crowd
bent on kissing and embracing her!
The record of this incident tells
us that: "The mayor and all the
officers of the city led In the shower
of congratulations that fell upon
Mile. Dutrieu. The men became
even more hysterical even than tho
women, gesticulating and shrieking
like mad?stirred to uncontrollable
laughter and tears, stretching their
hands toward her. Thus they
pressed around the girl and the
flying machine. And so she had to
be protected?so many desired to
kiss her."
She was the first woman to fly
Into Belgium. Two officers only
had done so before her. And over
the air lanes that she sailed in her
journey of a new achievement, now
speed swift, sinister things of the
air that spit singing death through
the void and on the earth below, or
drop thunderous destruction as
they pass swiftly through the night.
"Nervous?" she repeated the
query, smiled and was silent for a
moment. "My friend, one must
not be nervous la the upper air, or
one, will never go there again. The
true aviator must be without nerves.'
She'a a Homing Bird.
"Of course, I'd much rather fly
than vote," she continued; "though
you doubtless thluk it would be
well for a woman, having accom
plished the one thing to seek to
achieve the other. A woman may
rty a-id be at the same time a hom
ing bird by Instinct?this the view
as concerns myself, of course. You
"Then courageously would she fly in the direction of the expected danger, circling around, rising
and descending with eyes keen to the quest and nerves as steady as the metal mechanism that
held her afloat above the city."
see, therefore, I am not a suffra
gette. I think woman has all she
can do and all she should do, If she
is a home-maker and a good moth
er. And the French, husband thinks
so, too.
"As for voting, that would be an
Impossible situation in France.
The French women," and her
shapely hands fluttered prettily,
"are too emotional and excitable.
So, too. are our men. It can easily
be seea that they very likely would
become so excited over the issues
that life would be made utterly un
bearable."
The flrst woman air scout became
interested in flying about eight
years ago. and, noting her youthful
appearance now, one estimates that
the must have been a slip of a girl
when the fusillading motor sent th*
earth away from beneath her for
the llrst time. But what matters
the years? Mile. Dutrleu is still a
girl at hc-art nnd the tragedies of
which she has been a witness In
the army ambulance service, though
shadowing her speech and play of
facial expression at tim^s. canno*
Dr. L. Sarasln has succeeded, ac
cording: to La Nature, In making arti
ficial silk from the "slime" of the
seaweed which Is thrown up in im
mense masses on the coasts ot Nor
mandy. Norway, Scotland nnd Can
ada. An English company Is said to
bo exploiting the process, for which
a isrreat future Is prcdlctcd.
I i
Grand Admiral Princo Henry of
Prussia, the brother of the Kaiser,
who was the first royal nlrman, and
learned to fly when he was 49. hu3
become the flrst royal motion picture
operator.
Von Moltke, the grreat German gen
eral, would never begin a battle on
a Friday.
Helena Dutrieu, as She Looks in Street Garb.
divest her of that quality that
caused a sporting writer recently
to refer to her as "the captivating,
sky-flight kid."
Sky-flight scout, of course, would
have been a formal improvement;
but there is a certain element of
admiration and tribute in the sport

ing sharp's characterization?tho
very elements that have caused her
to receive many offers of marriage
and elicit this characteristic re
sponse from the first woman air
scout:
"The man who wants me mast
catch me In the air!"</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025316/1911-09-14/ed-1/?sp=8&q=female+aviators</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>SPORT OF AVIA IION
GETS WON
NUMEROUS FEMALE AVIATORS
ARE ENTERING FIELD FOR
MERLY HELD BY MEN.
New York, Sept. 13.-Although both
the Wright and C:urtiss schools
steadfastly refuse to teach feminine
pupils at any price, women are grad
ually forcing their way into the hIaz
ardous game of aviation and follow
ers of the sport are discussing with
interest today the report that Mrs.
Ralph Johnstone of Kansas City,
whose husband met death at Denver,
is soon coming to New York to master
the craft that widowed her. It is
understood she will take lessons at
the aviation colony on Long island
with a view to becoming a licensed
pirofessional aviator.
Today there are only two licensed
women aviators in this country-Miss
Matilda Molsant and Miss Harriet
Quilhby-hoth of whom are now on
Long Island. Blanchl Scott has made!
some noteworthy flights in Ohio, but
as yet has not obtained a license.
Miles Molsant, it will he recalled, took
up' aviation after the tragic death of
her brother, John Molsant, at New
Orleans, and in this respect her career
parallels Mrs. Johnstene's.
Flrance leads the world with more
than half a dozen prominent feminine
aviators and death has alfeady claimed
one of' them, Mine. Denise Moors.
'while the iiaroness Laroche, a flyer of
note, has been seriously injured. Only
yesterday in Prance Helena Datrap
flew more than 136 miles, estabhshlnlg
a record In the competition for the
WOml en's cup.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062169/1925-12-09/ed-1/?sp=3&q=female+aviators&st=text&r=0.151,0.209,0.288,0.326,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Miss Kibe Shigepo, one of the few
female aviators of Japan, has asked
the government to aid her plan for
a flying school for women.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1916-12-08/ed-1/?sp=11&q=female+aviators&st=text&r=0.006,0.377,0.131,0.148,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016758/1912-03-21/ed-1/?sp=4&q=female+aviators&st=text&r=-0.308,-0.081,1.616,1.616,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Mr. Bryan says he is not available.
Still, with a little repairing, it seems
that he might be able to run some yet.
Irish Standard.
William's mainspring appears to be
in good order, and the only thing
necessary, perhaps, to place him in
first-olass running condition is a lib
eral application of campaign oil to
the bearings of his other machinery.
A bill providing that free boxes be
furnished patrons of non-delivery
postoffices has been introduced in
eongress and it should become a law.
The fact that there is free delivery in
the larger cities and ID the rural dis
tricts shows plainly that persons liv
ing in small places are being discrim
inated againstit is a governmental
extortion which should be removed.
The "parachute" gown, which is no
more or less than a revivification of
the old-fashioned crinoline, or hoop
skirt, has made its appearance in
Chicago, and modistes say it will he
generally adopted in the course of a
year. As a safety device in this age
of airships it should prove a boon to
female aviators, who, in case of acci
dent, could jump from the machine
into space and sail gracefully to
earth.</text>
      </result>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-kidnapping-ellen-stone</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071197/1901-09-07/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>AMERICAN WOMEN IN HANDS OF
LAWLESS TURKS
Believed that No III Treatment Is In
tended Captors Are After Ransom
Sultans Prompt Action
Washington September p flic stn te de
partment has recelveif litfofiuitton fioiii
tbe United Btntes legltlontnt Coiutantlno
pie eoncertilng the prf reports of tho
rapftlio of an American missionary by
bilgauds
The tllspatcb I from Minister LcUhmun
nd reports that brigands Captured MIs
Stojie nn AtncrlWU Inlsslonalyi who was
traveling with a lady companion In tho
Mia et Snionlcn The department adds
that the matter has received the umiicdlutc
null earnest attention of Minister Lclsh
liunii
IIISPOJITHD TO MISSION IIOAKD
Bottoii Miss September 0 liie Atnerl
can board of foreign missions his iccelved
a chblegrnut from ltev 4 II House one
of the inlsslo nnrles nt Halnnlci lu Maee
dotiln Haying Brigands took Miss Stone
mnl companion between llnnslin and OJou
inanla
These plnces me situated about ln miles
noitheast of Salonlca In a country long
fnnllllnr to the inlsslnnnrles of the Ameri
can board Miss Illicit II Stone Is olio
of the tiled missionaries of the bonnl
having been lu thlf mission since 1878 It
hns been a part of her duty to tour among
the people with n Bible woman as ntteuil
nntt Miss Stone was bom In Itoshury and
herhome Is In Chelsea wheie her hint her
it sides Vow of her brothers nie In busi
ness in this city
A nilsslonniy now In Boston from Bul
gnila Is confident that no III treatment
will be jjlven these ladles but thinks It
simply a case dn which ransom Is fought
foe vby the robbers
SIMPAXS PUOMPT ACTION
Constantinople September li A dispatch
frorii Salonlca says that one of the ladles
carried off from Vilayet by btlgauds Is n
Miss Stone
The Millnn Iminedlatelv upon benilne of
thesflbduellon nf Miss Stone nnd her com
panion peremptorily ordeied the Villi of
Salonlca to secure their release nnd to cx
eicfte every care for their comfoivt and
safety</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1901-09-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom&r=0.091%2C0.621%2C0.521%2C0.294%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MISSIONARY
HEARn FROM
Miss Stone Abducted Writes
to Friend Telling of Her
Plight
CONSTANTINOPLE Thursday Sept
6ne Mr Ilojkell n missionary at
Bamakov IlulRarli has received a let
ter from Miss Helen II titone the
American missionary who woe carried
off by brigands Sept 5 In the district ot
Djumabala
It does not reveal the whereabout or
Miss Stone but nays alto Is In Rood
health and has ben well treated by the
brigands especially In the earlier stages
of abduction
Ixittcrly In consequence of the vigor
Otis pursuit of Turkish troops she has
been subjected to privations
Mis Stone adds that the brigands de
mand ransom of KOM Turkish pounds
Tho opinion Is expressed In Constanti
nople that tho DulRaroMaccdonlan
Committee was actively concerned In
the abduction of the missionary</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071197/1901-09-29/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>SS STONES IMPRISONMENT
She Is Still Held for Ransom by the Turk
ish Brigands
Paris September A Paris newsrjnper
corUBpoudent semis word to the Tlgaro
on the start of which he 1 employed that
ho has just returned from a rlslt to Mls
Ellen M Sloue of the American Hoard of
foreign Missions who Is held by bri
gands In a mountainous region of Turkey
The correspondent wire thnt he suc
ceeded u locating Miss Stone lit an almost
Innciptwtblo mountain dctlle The chief
of tho outlaws permitted tltu corrcpnnd
cut to see Mlhs Stone mid tnlk with her
Ulna Stouo told her lsltor Hint Rite hnd
bten treated with excoedlng courtesy ever
since her capture Two brigands wcie de
tailed to act ns her personal Bervant pro
Idlng her with good food and Miowlug
In r ecry attention The brigands had In
Mructlons to obey her merest wnlm nnd
to show with what degrr M f consideration
hhe was treats bv told Hlip ncWKjiapor
man that burfng e tausted irtS t tlio
UlniN for Iter Lodak fdifhad sulrt thnt she
wlclitHl she bail mote TJi e fenlrowns re
pealed to tho eJilef of Hip brigands who
nt once posted a cornier off to Constant
iwjile to secure u hitpply for her This
meant 11 week of sleidy traveling by mnlis
over dungproiis and rocUv mountain paths
The leader of the brig nuts told the cor
espondint that tiniest a rauKom of trjO0K
w in fortUeomlng nlthln thirty day MUh
Stone would eltiicr be put to death or com
polled to marry one of the bandits It Is
believed
word
that the bandit nil keep bis
The situation recalls the capture by these
same brlgncds In the same region six
years ago of Mine Gerard de Trlncvllle
a beautiful Prench heiress who Is now a
Carmelite nun Through the dishonesty of
a Turkish official by whom tho ransom was
negotiated the money failed to reach tho
bandits The lovely French girl wan there
upon forced to become tho wlfo of a mem
ber of the outlaw gune She was rescued
seven mouths later In a battle In which
ber father killed her bandit husband
Boston Oeptember 2S The American
board of commissioners of foreign missions
will resist the demand of S 110000 ransom
for the releuse of Miss Helen M Stone of
Chelsea Mass the American mlslsonary
now held by ltulgarlnii brigands
When shown a Htatetuent by Dr Cresan
New York secretary of the American
boutd that the ransom would be a danger
ous precedent llev Dr Jiulson Smith sec
rcturj of the Amtrlcan bojrd expressed
bis hearty approbation ihe board would
ueter consider Mich a proposition he
said the rescuo of Miss Stone Is In the
hands of the got eminent We have had
nilsslonnilea In Turkey for two generations
but never a ease like this Should wo
oITi r a ransom missionaries would never be
sife from capture</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1901-10-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom&st=text&r=0.49,0.365,0.41,0.463,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>TO SECURE MISS MISSSTONES MISSSTONES MISSSTONES
STONES RELEASE RELEASEUnited
United States Taking an Active ActiveInterest ActiveInterest ActiveInterest
Interest Interestr InterestWILL InterestWILL InterestWILL
r
WILL NOT PAY THE RANSOM RANSOMWAR RANSOMWAR RANSOMWAB
WAR n FLEET EI7E WAY VISIT THE THEBULGARIAN THEJ3ULGARJAN T TBUWABIAN
BULGARIAN PORTS FORTSt
t
Constantinople Oct 3 3American 3Americanrepresentatives American Americanrepresentatives
representatives have secured evidence evidenceproving evidenceproving evidenceproving
proving the complicity of members of ofthe ofthe ofthe
the Macedonia committee at Sofia in inthe Inthe inthe
the kidnaping of the American mis missionary mlssionar missionary
sionary sionar Miss Helen Stone and her hercompanion hercompanion hercompanion
companion Mme Tsilka and the as assurances ass assurances
surances s rances given by the Bulgarian gov government gover goverarnent
ernment er ment relative to the measures to be betaken I Itaken
taken against the abductors show that thatthe thatthe thatthe I
the gravity of the affair is appreciated appreciatedat I
at Sofia The departure of the United UnitedStates UnitedStntes UnitedStates
States consul general at Constantino Constantinople Constantinople
ple C M L Dickinson for the Bulgariancapital Bulgarian Bulgariancapital Bulgariancapital
capital is expected to result in in increased increased increased
creased activity activityWell activityYeU activityWell
Well informed people in Constanti Constantinople Constantinople Constantiflopledoubt
nople flopledoubt doubt that the release of Miss MissStone MissStone 1Iss 1IssStone
Stone and her companion will be ef effected effected cffected
fected by the payment of a ransom ransomThe ransomThe ransomThe
The Ottoman government would have havedifficulty havedltnculty havedifficulty
difficulty in finding the amount de demanded demanded domanded
manded while the missionaries point pointout pointout pointout
out that the American board of foreign foreignmissions foreignmissions foreignmisslpns
missions has made a practice of re refusing refusing refusing
fusing to pay ransoms on the ground groundthat groundthat groundthat I
that It would create a precedent and andbe andb andbe
be b fatal to mission enterprises else elsewhere elsewhere elsewhere
where whereLondon whereLondon whereLondon
I
London Oct 4 4The The United States Statesgovernment StateRgovernment Statesgovernment
government is determined to exact full fullrevenge fullrevenge fullrevenge
revenge upon everyone concerned concernedsays concernedsayS concernedsays
says the Constantinople correspondent correspondentof
of the Dally J afly Telegraph and if any an anthing
thing happens to Miss Stone it will not
hesitate to ask permission to bring a
fleet through the Dardanelles to get getat getnt getat
at Bulgarian ports on the Black sea seaand seannd seaand
and to force the Btar1an Btjijarian Bl arian government
to act against the Macedonian commit</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1901-10-05/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Board of Foreign Missions Appeal to Raise 1
1 10000 Demanded by Bandits Meets with fl
Ready Response and Whole Amount MustiiJ
Be Raised by Monday Noon I
7
d
The Christian people of America are coining eage l
to the rescue of Miss Ellen M Stone of Chelsea Masstr
missionary held by Bulgarian brigands for 110 000 ransom i t
If that amount is n tat hand by Tuesday next she willjjbei j
put to death i
The United States Government has been helpless itii the
face of the threatened tragedy Turkish and Bulgarian
troops have vainly hunted the bandits Each day ithat
passed brought Miss Stone nearer to death a1n
Finally the American Board of Foreign Missions Jeq n
upon the people of the ni States to raise the amount oi m
ransom by Monday noon That done Miss Stone woultf
bes v dThree hours after he banking house of Peaho 1
Kidder Go was opened at Boston today 17808 had been
I
received and the moneywas still coming in</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1901-10-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>President in Close Touch with State Department
Which Has Indirect Communication with Bandits
and Is Working to Have Time for Payment
of Ransom Extended
It scorns impossible that the ransom of 110000 if raised in this country can reach tho Bulgarian
hrigumlH who hold her captive in time to save tho life of Miss Ellen if Stone who is threatenedJTOtli1 1
death tomorrow ili
Tho Stnto Drpartmcnt hovvivor kin indirect communication with tho bandits hopeful that
tho time for payment may bo extended for a few day 8 o that the total amount may bo raised Up to
1 oclock this afternoon more than 50000 had been received hy tho trustees in Boston
The Stout Department says that the peril of the missionary is graver than cvc
m
FLOOD OF LETTERS SENT t
TO PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT I
iljg
WASHINGTON Oct iIt Is not
probable that the kidnappers of Miss
Stone will enforce their ultimatum
tomorrow although that was the
1
date named as the last day of grace
In her case I
The danger Is by no means averted
however and tho most that can be
said now Is that there Is a likelihood
MONEY COMING IN STEADILY J
TO MAKE UP NHTR MiI
tSewtst to 1110 tvvalnK WorU I
BOSTON Oct i1hc heartbefts
of Christian America for the safety
of Miss Ellen M Stone hold foV nin
som by Bulgarian brigands are bcliiK
counted In gold today In the offices
cl Kldder Pcahody to Co Iloaton
where during the first two hours this
morning nearly 30000 w added 0
tho ransom fund
At 1 oclock this afternoon the
clerical force nt work on the tabula
tion of the ransom money had not
boon able to keep pace with the In
pouring tonlrllmtoiiH As nearly an
could Iw reckoned at that time the
total amount had reached a little
more than JSOOOO
That was far short of the amount
LOSES HIS FICHT
FOR 2000000
GEORGE KEMP JB ALLOWED
ONLY 80000 A YEAR
Court lrnr tip AnililBtmn Vrut
Fnnd left lir Old Ure
Man
Under a decision handed down hy Jus
tlce ritigcrnll this afternoon In the
litigation over the irtoi loft amblgu
oinly In n trust fund by Uiorgr Kimp
who died In 1KM the semi nor Kemp
Jr who unprovided for In bile fathers
will gt tJ CA a ir from a trimt fund
cnvitcKl by the exrculorn fails In his f
fort to secure control of the fJWW
The state of tin elder IComp who
was of the old drug firm if Uinmin A
Kemp aniountrd to ioW There
were a widow and four children
The i at itr was divided by tin will Into
five mual part Each of three chil
dren rprlviM oiipflfth The other two
nfth were Ion IntrlLt for thin widow
giving her permliwlon to tirovlilc for the
son George nn clue san fit
rh ixeculorii cr Mted n trust fund of
WoW to jHeld nn Income of Jito n ji ir
for Oeorn Kemp Jr
The widow died loivlng a will dividing
the twofifths loft In trust to her minus
tile IKAOCO equally among tho four chll
drin
Klwnrd Ktmp brother and executor
of ttie senior O lrlo Kemp brought nn
action to have tho will of Oforxo Kemp
sr conotrued on the point of whether
his wlitow hail the power to will to
Joorm or to create a trust fund for his
benefit to extend beand her lifetime
Justice Kltrsernld says George Kemp
Jr cannot share In the twofUms of lute
fathers estate but that tho StfoOOO trust I
tunclIII valid that he macontlnue
to enjoy hIlncomooC 9000 a year
t
of securing a short extension by the
brigands of the time allowed for the
payment of tho ransom
Thc State Department Is busying
Itrelf earnestly In this direction evl
driitly acting under the belief that
In the course of two or three days the
charitable people of the United
States will mnkc up the fund neces
I
sary to secure Miss Stones release
I e I
lacking 60000 of wLnt the ban
dits demanded an tho price of Miss
Stones life The mcney was still
coming III and though It was cvi
dcnt that the J 110000 uoulil not
he rained In time tit friends of Miss
Stone were hopeful of an extension of
the time MI by her captors They
hud sale that If the money was not
pall by noon tomorrow she would
surely be put to death
The State Dpartmcnt at Washing
ton was In p occlpt of Information
that com I need It that thlh vas no
Idle threat And no It was told to
t he men who started the popular
movement to rave the missionary
Tho inlilvs wore kept busy all this
forenoon In an endeavor to get the
ClRliN TOMBS
FOR NU REASON
REMARKABLE PETITION FOR
HABEAS CORPUS WRIT
luitt rr fur Vcrn Slirroiiml Mug
Ie iMB n Sllirrlnii Sited
of Affairs
A lawyer representing Miss Vcra
Sherwood applied to Justice Lawrence
nt the Supremo Court tills afternoon
unit gut n writ i t ImbtiH corpus direct
ing Warden login at the Tomb to
I m luce hT III court toni rrow morn
ItlKThn
Thn tltlm uys thut Vrii Slir o nl
Ins l vfn In tin1 Tomb somo wOk that
iht tluer not know what she was ar
rwtoil for thit nil they toll her at tti
Tomb Is thai shv N hrlil for t her Omlll
Jury tint roviral Grand June have
Kit ultliiiut attlng on her cue ami that
she M held ullhuui due Jlrocs jf law
COMING WITH THE TREATY 1
loril Iaiiitrrfiilr Uui tn Arrlit lu
WllxlllllUlMI Vi e I
VVASUINGION Oct 7 Word has
roichnl hero that Lord IMnncefptc the
HrltlMi Anrt iSiili r to ViiihlnKloii will
Suit from KiiKland on Oct M on the
American lino stmmor Hi I uils Hu
will reach vVanhliiKton with the new
can il treaty atxiut Nov 1 Jo that he
and Secretor liny AIII Inno a full
month bofon Coimrii convones In
which to nub ihi UnifhliiR louchos to
the document uhlch has nocn In forma
tion nil aiiniincr to roplico the Clioton
Dulwor treaty nnd the failed Hay
Iauncefoto treiity
Teohnlrally the treaty Is an amend
ment of the lliivlauncofote agreement
which was mmfllled only where II 13
noveviiiry to moot the wishes of the
B nite ascertained by Secretary Hay
through direct consultation with Indivi
dual and roMteocntatlvo Senator
i
j j i
I 0
Mr Mice the Acting Secretary of
State was again at the Whlto House
tnilay In consultation with tho Presi
dent touching Miss Stones case and
It Ic believed that negotiations arc In
progress Indirectly with her captors
Meanwhile White House and tho I fo
State Department DoIng flooded i
by letters and telegrams Imploring
the officials to nave Miss Stone
i
4
time further extended If necessary
so that the Ire amount mar bo
turned In
Dlrfrrriirc In rime
The time In Constantinople Is scrca
lioni later than 1 Boston where
the contributions arc being received
I by KIdder Peabody Co The delays
Incident to cable transmission will be
at least five hours more so that it Is
aboliiti necessary that the entire
amount be Ir hand or pledged by the
close of banking hours this evening
Thc United States Government has
admitted Its litter Inability to effect
the release of the captured missionary</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-10-09/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>that we have no funds that could be used for
this purpose. The Government was restrained
from paying the money by constitutional lim
itation, and the American Board seemed equally
restrained from payins a ransom.
Sympathy of the President.
The solicitude of the committee was such
and their purpose to do everything was so
strong that they sent a deputation consisting
of the president and one of its secretaries to
Washington to meet President Roosevelt and
the officials of the State Department. This
conference was held last Saturday forenoon
It is Impossible to overstate the sympathy and
Interest of the President, the acting Secretary
of State and other officials.
The conference was lengthy, during whlcn
the Government showed what steps it was
taking and how every power of diplomacy
was being used to effect the release of Miss
Stone. Confidential details were given, which,
of course it would be a breach of trust to give
to the public but the friends of the board and
the whole nation may be assured that every
thing possible is being done to further the
recovery of Miss" Stone. The heart and the
persistence olV the President in this effort were
most significant. The officials assured us that
apparently at the moment the only practicable
method to secure her life was to have the
funds promptly at hand to pay the ransom. It
was evidently the positive conviction of the
Government that this step was the first one
to be taken. But It ought to be clearly under
stood that this Is but one step; that when she
has been released there will be a vigorous at
tempt not only to secure the return of the
money but furthermore, to bring about such
conditions that such an occurrence shall not
be possible In the future. Xo one doubts that
our Government as at present organized will
not drop this matter until the rights of Ameri
can citizenship are established.-
Meanwhile a movement was begun under the
leadership of Miss Stone's family to secure by
popular appeal the amount of the ransom, and
notice had already been sent out that funds
could be sent to Boston.
Under this advice of the Government a meet
ing of the prudential committee was called on
Sunday morning, which was attended by eight
members of the committee and four officers.
The report of the gentlemen sent to Washing
ton was received, and after full deliberation It
was decided that, while we could not recede
from the action of last Friday, the tidings of
the Government made It most evident that the
first thing was to secure Mies Stone's safety,
then, other steps would follow; therefore we
felt that as individuals it was our duty and
privilege to help by all means in our power
the securing of this ransom from the general
public. Communications were sent by" tele
gram, so far as possible, to every part of the
country, even to the Pacific -Coast.
Money in- sums large and small has been
received In answer to this appeal to humanity.
The Government has shown its supreme inter
est in this matter by already becoming the
custodian of this fund, as handed to It by the
firm of Kidder, Peabody Co. This plan not
only shows the Government's interest, but it
forbids any possibility that any part of the
money will be paid over until Miss Stone per
sonally has-been placed In safety In the hands
of the proper authorities.
It will be seen from the above statement that
the board was a"~trolt in Its whole "action from
the beginning and consistent throughout. Its
officers and friends are willing to use every
effort to procure this fund under the "conditions
and limitations given. Any one who had been
present at the conference in Washington would
not hesitate to have full confidence in the Gov
ernment's efforts. The official^ of the board,
having been received Into its confidence, are
willing to trust the Government, and we have
no doubt that the friends of the board will
have confidence in us.
Raising Money. for Ransom.
BOSTON, Oct. 8.— No additional state
ment of money received for the ransom
fund for Miss Stone was given out to
night by Kidder, Peabody Co. after the
one of the late afternoon showing $49,
574 81 in cash and $7000 in unpaid pledges.
This made the total $56,574 61, to- which
will be added in the- morning the sums
received over night. The rush of contrib
utors Is over, because of the general opin
ion that the critical moment has been
MAJORS MUST SERVE
LIFE TERM IN PRISON
Utah Judge Passes Sentence on Young
Man Called the "Boy
Murderer." Y
LOGAN, Utah, Oct. 8.— In the' District
Court to-day Judge Hart sentenced Abe
Majors, popularly known as "the boy
murderer," to life imprisonment for the
killing of Captain Brown, chief of the
Ogden police, three years ago.
J Majors, who is barely out of his teens,
was convicted of the crime and sentenced
to be shot in 1899, but the Supreme Court
granted him a new .trial, which was con
cluded on Saturday.
George J. Gould, Edward H. Harriman,"
Marvin Hughitt, James H. Hyde, Otto H.
Kahn, Charles A. Peabody, Winslow S.
Pierce, Henry H. Rogers, Jacob H. Schiff
and James Stillman.
President- Burt and the other officials
who arrived from the East this morning
will remain over until to-morrow, when
the annual meeting of the stockholders of
the Oregon Short Line will take place.
averted, and that a month's time offers
ample opportunity to add to the fund.
Charles A. Stone, brother of the captive
missionary, wishes activity for the fund
to continue for a few days longer. He
hopes that the cable dispatches indicat
ing that the brigands have granted a
month's time are right, yet he has no per
sonal confirmation of that fact, although
he has repeatedly sent, messages to both
Constantinople and Samokov. He says
that, the idea In the "West that he had
stated that no money is needed because
enough has been given is all wrong. He
is still anxious about getting the total of
$110,000.
Next Saturday will be the twenty-third
anniversary "of Miss Stone's sailing from
Boston for the missionary field in Bul
garia.
Accuses Turkey's Sultan.
KAXSAS CITY, Oct. 8.— Dr. M. Mesro
pian of this city, a physician and a na
tive of Armenia, who has lectured much
in Eastern cities on the atrocities prac
ticed .upon the Armenians by the Turks,
declares that the abduction of Miss Stone,
the American missionary, by brigands in
Bulgaria was the work of the Sultan of
Turkey. He said:
I am sure that it was he who ordered the
brigands to carry off Miss Stone. He ordered
her taken acro3s the Bulgarian border so as
to distract suspicion from himself. It is a
move In retaliation for the enforced payment
of the $90,000 Indemnity that the United States
exacted of him for the burning: of American
missionary buildings. I believe it would be far
better for the Government to send a warship
over there than to pay the ransom. Mission
aries will not be safe after Abdul Hamld has
received, the ransom. Missionaries will be ab
ducted everywhere. The Sultan is determined
to be revenged for the loss of that $90,000 and
the abduction serves a double purpose— the re
turn of the money and the behest of fanaticism.
There is rto crime the Turk would not commit
in the name of his religion.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1901-10-17/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>REFUSES
To Pay Miss Stone's
Ransom.
Prominent Actors In the Story of Miss Stone's Abduction.
N. R. STEIMER
I
D
E
A
D
Consul General Dickinson Claims to
Have Made a Discovery.
Says the Macedonian Committee Instigated and
Planned the Whole Affair.
Constantinople, Oct 17. (Spl.) Con
sul General Dickinson, of the United
States, positively discovered that Miss
Stone was abducted at the instigation
of the Macedonian committee, has re
fused to pay the ransom raised by the
United States and demanded by the
abductors.
If the charges against the committee
are proven, the Turkish government
may be held lesponslble for the safety
nnd the deliverance of Miss Stone
from the abductors who are holding
her for ransom.
Tho fact that the Macedonian com
mittee may be found to be responsi
ble for tho abduction will receive the
Bulgarian government from all re
sponsibility and Involve Turkey In
complications with the United "States
that may menace tho integrity of tho
Umpire.
It was rcpoited n week ago that tho
chairman of the Macedonian commit
tee was short of funds and that ho
liad engineered the iilan that resulted
lu tho capturo of tho American mis
sionary. It Is even Intimated that
other otllclal5; of the Turkish govern
ment may be found to bo Implicated
In the scheme.
AVhen the rcpoit was first comment
ed on, the oltlclals at Washington ex
pressed tho opinion that If tho guilt
of tho lnembcrss of the committee
was pi oven, It would be exceedingly
unwise to pay the lantern, as tho suc
cess of this vcntuie would doubtless
result In other attempts at abduction.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1901-10-22/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>the liberation of Miss Stone. In
formation has been received by the State
Department from St. Petersburg showing
that the Russian authorities are doing
everything in their power to effect the
woman's release. Through their repre
sentatives in Constantinople and Sofia
they have applied diplomatic pressure to
Turkey and Bulgaria, and this has had
much to do with the activity those gov
ernments have displayed. The State De
partment does not know whether Miss
Stone is alive or dead, but is still clinging
to tho theory that the bandits will hold
her until they secure the ransom demand
ed, and it is urging the board of missions
not to relax its efforts to raise the sum
required.
The Turkish Government has for its
CALL BUREAU. 1406 G STREET,
N. W., WASHINGTON, Oct. 21.-
Russia is earnestly co-operating
with the United States to effect
Man and Woman Leave
Ghastly Baggage
With Miner.
Wife of Lawyer Shaw
Charges Him With
Cruelty.
ASKS THE COURT
TO PROTECT HER
TRUNK CONTAINS
BODY OF A GIRL
RUSSIAN AUTHORITIES AIDING
IN THE RESCUE OF MISS STONE
ELOPERS RACE
WITH OFFICERS
Two Youthful Couples
Defy th© Wrath of
Parents.
State Department Does Not Know Whether the Captive Is Alive or
Dead, but Is Still Clinging to the Belief That the Bandits Will
Hold Her Until They Have Secured the Ransom Demanded
Hastening to Reach Seattle
Before Law's Minions
Overtake Them.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045366/1901-10-30/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Miss+Stone+missionary+Bulgaria+Turkey+Macedonian+Committee+American+Board+Foreign+Missions+ransom</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>LESSON FOR TURKS
AND BULGARIANS
United States Naval Demonstration
in the Dardanelles May Be Pre-
cipitated Any Moment
Treaty Parties That Control Entrance
to Turkish Waters the Subject
of Secret Conferences.
flew York Sun ffpeo/a/ Bmi*rlom
New York, Oct. 30.—The Journal says,
under date of Washington, Oct 29: The
near future of President Roosevelt's ad
ministration is likely to he signalized hy
a severe lesson to Turkey and perheps
Bulgaria. A demonstration in the Med
iterranean is expected and may be pre
cipitated at any moment by the death of
Miss Stone or any act of barbarity com
mitted against her or the missionary and
Amorican citizens for whom Turkey and
Bulgaria are responsible.
The officials are looking more deeply
into the case than that of the mere safety
of Miss Stone. It Is known that diplomatic
movements of world-wide importance are
pending. The local diplomats say this is
not the time to discuss the movements of
this government.
There have been secret conferences be
tween the president and state department
officials, which affect not only the United
States, Turkey and Bulgaria, but the
treaty powers which virtually control the
passage of a hostile squadron into Turkish
waters.
There is ample reason to be-
lieve that intimations, if not
t positive orders, have already
gone to Rear Admiral Cromwell,
in command of the European
j station, to hold himself in readl-
ness for final action by the state
department.
Here are the United States war vessels
which would be used in a demonstration:
The Chicago and Albany at Leghorn, the
Nashville at Genoa, the Dixie at Ville
franche, and the Monongahela at Ville
franche.
The Buffalo, commander C. T. Hutchin
fion, will be at Maderia on Nov. 3. It is
learned on high authority that this gov
ernment is sounding European powers on
the important question of an approach to
Bulgaria. This could be done only by the
powers waiving the objections to the pas
sage of the Dardenelles.
It is believed that the assent will be ob
tained. France could not get this assent
in her recent trouble with Turkey because
she is a European power and her act
might lead to complications.
JVO TIME TO HAGGLE
Objections to the Conrwe of Conanl
General Dickinaon.
Special to The Journal.
Chicago, Oct. 30.—William E. Curtis, la
a special cablegram from Sofia to the
Record-Herald, published this morning,
says the state department, United States
Consul General Dickinson and the United
States legation at Constantinople are cer
tain to be assailed by a storm of criti
cism when the facts concerning the man
agement of the case of Miss Ellen M.
Stone become known in the United States.
President Roosevelt some weeks ago
sent a characteristic message to Prince
Ferdinand of Bulgaria, warning him that
the American people and the civilized
world would hold him responsible for
Miss Stone's safety. A similar dispatch
should be sent immediately to Consul
General Dickinson ordering him to cease
talking and to act.
Mr. Dickinson's policy is disapproved by
the entire diplomatic corps at Sofia and
by everybody who understands Bulgarian
politic* and is interested in Miss Stone's
welfare. The Bulgarian government is
powerless and determined to avoid re
sponsibility. The bandits dare not make
overtures for fear of compromising the
Macedonian committe.
Consul General Dickinson refused to
send a messenger to Miss Stone, and even
declined to send her a letter of sympathy
and encouragement by the messenger dis
patched to negotiate with the bandits by
M. Bakhetief, Russian diplomatic agent
at Sofia. He refused to spend money to
secure information or open communica
tion with the kidnappers, and daily re
sumed his useless debate with the Bul
garian prime minister.
The consul general asserted that h»
acted under instructions from Spencer
Eddy, secretary of the United States lega
tion at Constantinople. Mr. Dickinson
quarrelled with M. Bakhmeiteff, the Rus
sian diplomatic agent, and rejected the
advice of the experienced ministers of
England, Germany and Austria, who urged
postponement of the diplomatic contro
versy until Miss Stone had been rescued.
Mr. Dickinson should have been or
dered to proceed immediately to Bansko
or Samakov with instructions to open
communication with the bandits at any
cost. If objection was made to the pay
ment of a ransom he should have offered
a reward of $10,000, thus, enabling the
bandits to surrender Miss 'stone without
compromising the Macedonian committee
or the Bulgarian government. Stung by
the criticism his course aroused, Mr,
Dickinson left yesterday for Samakov.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1901-10-15/ed-1/?sp=1&q=ellen+stone+kidnapped+by+turks&r=-0.137,0.082,1.527,0.863,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MORE FUNDS WANTED.
Not Enough Raised To
Ransom Miss Stone.
Fifty Thousand Dollars More Is
Required.
Another Appeal From
American Board.
Situation Has Undergone No
Material Cbange.
New York, October 14,—The Kev.
Charles C. Creegan, district seoretary
for the American Board of Foreign Mis
sions, gave out a letter today, part of
which reads:
“To the American people: The case of
Miss Stone, now in the hands of the Tor
k!sh brigands, has undergone no material
change. In the office of the American
as to the amount of the ransom for Miss
Stone. _
ANOTHER KIDNAPPING.
London, Ootober 16.—"It is announoed
from Bucharest,” say a deepatoh to the
Daily Mall from Vienna, “that Herr
Resenthal, the representative of a Ger
man firm has been kidnapped by Bul
garian brigands at fcjilistria. The
Roumanian government has sent a pro
test to Sofia and the Bulgarian govern
ment has ordered troops to pursue the
brigands.
“It is rumored that the Macedonian
committee has decided to capture everv
foreigner within reach in order to at
tract European attention to the,bad
state of publio tecurity in Macedonia.”
MISS STOKE ALIVE.
All The Officials Will Give Out at
Present.
Washington, Ootober 14.—All thatjcan
be' gained from the Strte Department
officials respecting the case of Miss Stone,
the missionary who is held.by brigands
in Bulgaria, is that she Is alive and that
efforts are being continued for her re
lease. The officials, while declining to
indicate the nature of the measures they
are pursuing to this end, still have
hopes of ultimate success.
ABDUCTORS TURKS.
London, October 16.—The Daily Ex
press has received the following from
Vienna:
"Tedarlff, the driver, who aooompa
nled Miss Stone when she was kidnapped,
has arrived at Sofia. He says her captives
are "Turks. The Bulgarian police, who
MISS ELLEN M. STONE.
board and among her Immediate friends
the greatest anx’ety prevails, Our gov
ernment at Washington has not raodlliea
the opinion, uttered by President Roose
velt, that there Is but one thing to do
and that is to raise the sum demanded
tor her ransom as quickly as possible.
Of this sum f (30,000 has already been sub
scribed, far the larger part of it in Bos
ton and in the Immediate vicinity.
A multitude of her neighbors In
every condition of life, have poured their
gifts into the Boston office for her
deliverance, but it is not sufficient. Fifty
thousand dollars more are required.
Wa appeal now to those among us who,
by the blessing of God have larger
financial abilities, to supplement the
contributions of their neighbors, that the
necessary sum may be reached.
“An answer is anxiously awaited
at the office of the American board, 1C5
East 22nd street, New York, where
subscriptions to the undersigned will
be received.
(Signed)
“O. C. Creegan, DIstriot Secretary,
“Henry A. Stimson, Recording Secre
tary.
Dr. Creegan said that the board had
received assurances from the United
States government in the past few days
that the only thing that could be done
was to raise the money necessary for the
payment of the ransom.
TROOPS CALLED OFF.
When It Was Learned Miss Stone’s
Life Was in Danger.
Constantinople, October 14,— It trans
pired tbat the Turkish commander had
completed dispositions to surround Mis3
Ellen M. Stone’s captors at noon on Sat
urday last but Spencer Eddy, secretary
of the U. S. legation, received intorma
tion that further activity would result
in the deathlot Miss Stone. At 3 o’clock
Saturday morning he proceeded to the
residence of the minister of foreign
affairs, Tewflk Pasha, and demanded
the immediate retirement of the Turkish
troops. This was oarrled out and the
Bulgarian forces followed suit.
Mr. Eddy’s aotion has the unanimous
approval of the members of the diplo
matic corps, who are convinced that
efforts to liberate Miss Stone by force
will infallibly result in her murder.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016025/1901-10-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=ellen+stone+kidnapped+by+turks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Ransom Miss Stone.
Vienna. October 18.—According to the
Poiitlsche oorrespondenz, M. SaratoiT.
Bnigarian :ninister of the interior and
ad interim minister of foreign aifairs,ad
dressed a note to Mr. Dickinson, United
States consul general in Constantinople
a few days ago in which after complain
ing that the consul general had expressed
dissatisfaction with the measures the
Bnigarian government'had'taken against
the kidnappers of M'ss Stone he
strongly protested against his govern
ment being held responsible for a crime
committed on Turkish territory and de
clared that in order to guard itself
against unmerited accusation the Bul
garian governmtnt had resolved shouid
the robber band tiy to cross the Bul
garian frontier or succeed in stealing in
to Bulgaria, to have it mercilessly pur
sued and annihilated by Bulgarian troops.
"We will not enter into any negoti
ations whatever for paying ransom,"
said M. SaratoH, "as we do not want
precedents established for many robbers
infesting the neighborhood to turn to
Bulgaria whenever this seems to be to
their advantage. We are ilrmly determined
to make an example whioh will deter
robbers from repeating such speculations.
"It will then no longer be possible to
aocuse Bulgaria of harboring secret
committees which organize bands for
kidnapping foreigners in Turkey and re
moving them to Bulgaria, there especially
to enjoy the ransom they expect."
WHAT LETTER MEANS
Proof That Bntgnrta Is Shielding Mac
edonian Committee.
London, Ootober 19 —Commenting up
on the statement of the Politsohe Cor
respondenz, regarding the letter from
M. Saratoif, the Bulgarian minister,
to Mr. Dickinson, the Vienna corre
spondent of the Standard says:
"It may be regarded as convincing
proof that Bulgaria is shielding the
Macedonian committee and that the
Sofia correspondents cf the Poiitsche
Correspondenz, the Pesetezr Lloyd and
other papers, were correct when declar
ing that Macedonians disguised as Turks
had kidnapped Miss Stone and that a
regular came is being played by Bul
garian troops on one side and Turkish
troops on the pother: eaoh side trying to
smuggle prisoners over the border In
order that the raDsom paid by senti
mental Americans may be recovered as
the Bulgarians wish,front Tnrkey, and,
as the Turks wish, from Bulgaria, and
that the prisoners, but for tins farce,
could be produced at any moment.
"The right course now is not to pay
ransom but to hold Bulgaria responsible
for every hair of Miss Stone's head.
Those who knew the facta see no reason
to anticipate any danger to her life."
TO RELEASE MISS STONE.
Four Thousand Bulgarian Troops En
gaged io EBTort.
London, October 19.—"Fonr thousand
Bulgarian and Turkish troops have been
occupied In the eCort to obtain Miss
Stone's release," says a despatch from
Solla to the Morning Leader. It is be
lieved here that her release would have
been eHeoted but tor Mr. Dickinson's
refusal to offer her captors more than an
ordinary pour boire. Mr. Dickinson's
extraordinary aotion is regarded as snioi
dah A large sum must be paid to the
brigands as otherw ise Miss {Stone's llte
wili be sacrificed. If Mr. Dickinson
desires vengeance on the orlgands the
woman must be ransomed first."
AN ABSURD STORY.
London, October 10.—"An extraordi
nary version ot the Stone abduction
comes today from Constantinople," says
a despatch from Vienna to the Dally
Telegraph.
"It Is declared ^ln Turkish official cir
cles that Miss Mtone sympathizes with
the Macedonian committee and herself
agreed to the kidnapping so that the ran
som would be paid to the committee.
Comment upon this story is quite su
perfluous."
MISS STONE IN DANGER.
London, October 18.—The Globe this
afternoon, says it fears that the safety of
Miss Ellen M. Stone is serlous!y compro
mised by the attitude of Consul General
Dickinson in refusing to pay the ransom,
and in demanding that Bulgaria arrest
the leaders of the Macedonian committee
as the real authors of missionary abduc
tions The paper stye the situation con
tains all the factors of a grave interna
tional complication and threatens to as
sume importance far beyond the personal
ity of any individual missionary.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1903-09-19/ed-1/?sp=2&q=ellen+stone+kidnapped+by+turks&st=text&r=0.152,0.111,0.318,0.359,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>AMERICANS VOLUNTEER
To Help the Macedonians Fight the
Cruel Turks.
Chicago. Sept. 18.—Many members of
the Illinois militia have volunteered
their services to Macedonia in the war
against the Turks, according to a state
ment made by the local Macedonian
ccm rnittee.
There was a lively meeting of Mace
donians, last night, in the Second Bap
tist church. G. M. Tsilka, whose wife
was kidnapped with Miss Ellen M.
Stone, stirred the audience with an
account of the barbaric practices of
thf- Turks and he related instances of
unprovoked cruelty of which he had
been a witness. He denied the reports
that the brigands who captured Miss
Stone and Madame Tsilka were allied
to or acting under the direction of the
Macedonian revolutionary party.
When the meeting adjourned those
present dropped their contributions
into the folds of the Macedonian flag
as it lay half furled at the door.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1911-03-07/ed-1/?sp=5&q=ellen+stone+kidnapped+by+turks&st=text&r=0.622,0.372,0.336,0.38,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>STRONG APPEALS
FOR THE MISSIONS
Women's Baptist Union in
Session Here.
Strong appeals for foreign and do
mestic missions wre made in addresses
by prominent workers at the quarterly
meeting of the Woman's Baptist Mis
sionary Union yesterday afternoon and
I evening at the Calvary Baptist Church.
Dr. Ellen Stone, the well-known Amer
ican missionary, who, several years ago.
was kidnapped by the Turks and held as
hostage, in an address, contrasted the
conditions of Turkey with the condi
tions as she saw them ten years ago.
She pointed out the marked advance
ment in the laws of that country, which
allowed greater freedom to the Individual
and especially to the women now than
at any other time.
The evening session was in charge of
the young women of the Farther Lights
organization, presided over by Mrs. Will
I iam Allen Wilbur, while the devotional
exercises were conducted by Miss Sadie
Styron.
Rev. Hugh P. Mc?ormlck, who has had
,1 wide experience as a missionary, first
j to Mexico and then to Porto Rico and
I Europe, under the Northern Baptist
board, gave a graphic Account of the
I Protestant missions in Europe.
Supper was served earlier in the even-
ing, following the close of the afternoon
session, which was conducted by Mrs.
Charles G. Gould, president of the union,
when addresses were made on mission
work in Mexico and among the Southern
white mountaineers.
Rev. W. E. Brown, of the Southern
Baptist Convention, made an earnest ap
peal for the mountain schools. Rev. Mr.
McCormick told of the advancement of
the mission work in Mexico.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-11-07/ed-1/?sp=3&q=ellen+stone+kidnapped+by+turks&st=text&r=0.306,0.318,0.256,0.289,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MISS ELLEN M. STONE.
'ihe laplure !u tin wilds of Miuedonln uf the Amcrluiii mtsuloniry. lll
nileu M, Stone, and the kiiIim iin nt 1t iuiiikIx foi riuimun mnde li her Inltfaiid
raptom luxe imiscil tho whole Cliil-lliin wmld. 'I IiIh pUtme Is fiiun a photo,
criiph wlihli Ml Stone li.nl taken dining a Kit to liu- home In Chelsea,
Mjh., fOM'i.il jtntH n.
time, to riceho complete, satisfaction.
Wo hac acted ory considerately to
ward Turkey, hoping tip to the last
mommt, that she would carry out her
ingagements, and It Is onlj not, when
wc find that there Is no serious Indi
cation of lur doing so, that we hae
rrlmtantly rcsohtd to put stronger
prcssuie to biar, In the shape of a na
nl demonstration. It Is now two
months since the French Ambassador
M. Constans, lift Constantinople. Ills
depirturo failed to produce the desired
effeit. On the contrarj, cwn the Tu
hlnl iiiestlon, which was settled b) the
Kultan'H Irade, remain unadjustid The
Internal situation In tho Turkish Um
pire ditirrcil us for some time from
taking drastic measures to enforce our
dimands Hut the dlgoll) of Krauce
could not permit the prcmnt stato of
affairs to he prolonged Indefinitely
We slncirel) hope the Sultan will fully
appreciate tho fact that we cannot any
longer lie trifled with, and" rclleic us
fiom taking further steps to safeguard
our Interests
Ihe ofllclal was asked whjt would
happen In the eent pf the French
piuiiiiiuii ueuiK uruercu to seize me
customs nnd If the Turkish author!-
tlet resisted, and he r piled:
'That Is a xery unllkel) contingency
tint If It oocura I suppose wc shall hac
to bomlnrd that port. We do not want
bloodshed, and I do not hellevo ther
will be nny occasion for It."
New York. Oct. 31. Americans arc
preparing a reception for Miss Stono
upon her release, mjs a Soflla corres
pondent of the Journal and Advertiser.
The Russian Minister, M. UakhmetcfC.
expects a letter soon from Miss Stone,
und the hrlgande through the einoy
sent last Friday. It Is btllcxcd that
Miss Stono will be able to be present
at I'hlllppolls on Noembcr 8 at tho
dedication of tho new American church
there. After that she will doubtless go
ORDERED TO PHILIPPINES.
Washington. Oct. 31. Oenernl Miles
has recommended that the Klcu'iith
California nnd the Twenty eighth In
lantry bo sent to tho Philippines.
These leglments are to take the
place of regiments to be brougnt
home, which hae been senlnc
the brlg-inds.</text>
      </result>
  </topic>
</topics>