<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.61,0.166,0.325,0.367,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>All Fools' Day nt Canyon Ferry.
C'aayoti
Ferry,
At iho Canyon Ferry House). Iiepb by.
our old friend Cnnt. StalTord. is wont lo
meet occasionally tho Jolly bnrhelors of
mo Hujaeeni mines, wuu sot nroumi lltu
bnr.qunfl' their bovorog'cs nnil bewail lliclr
sad and lonoly lives of bachelorhood.
On Saturday evening, April 1st, whllo a
party of thoso dUcousnlato chap wero
engaged In Iho pastime mentioned. above,
a spanking team was drivHti. to tho par
lor door, by I. il. Tyler, ami by his side
sat n blooming and buxom lemule, who
wns politely, handed out of thu vehicle
nnd shown to tho parlor. A buz of nil
miration went up from tho crowd, nml
Mn Tyler wns interviewed ns to tho pn
ternlty and prdlgreo of tho lovely strnn
gor. These Inquiries wero snttuflcd by
thu stntntm nt that Mr. Stafford bail dls-
chnruetl his ittnlo cook, anu tho truly was
nn interesting widow, who lintl consen
ted to superintend tho cuisine affairs of
the household. Tho crowd otilotl v dron
ped olf their cabins, donned their "bllr-d."
shirts, shaved cl nu, nml dropped back
to the hotel, ono after nitothar, each ono
with it pnliiifntlng heart, nnd n quiet
chuckle to lil'tisell that ha- was looking
supremely smooth, and would recelrc
tho first introduction nnd smiles of the
widow. As they entered, Mr. Tyler
led their, one by one nnd presented them
to their fancied Idol, until the room wns
crowded with rivals, Captain Stafford,
wllh his eye on Iho knot-holo, tinted tho
happy countenances of tho baeholors,
nnd Iho witching smiles of tho widow,
whllo Tyler did tho nmlnblc. Tho
Judge of thu district, n happy, Jolly
bachelor, but, unfortunately, very thin
haired, borrowed n wig for tlio occnlon,
nnd appeared befose thv widow, with
his ours pinned back, nnd looking upon
tho minors with tho lofty contempt
which he felt bis position would give
him over bis rivals lo tho lair willow's
eyes. Tho guests having been all Intro
duced, Joo Stnirer, finally summoned
courngo to tako a sent by her sldo nml
engaged her in conversation but what
was his horror upon discovering tho
fair female gently raised her whlto skirts
nml shovo her hand Into tho pocket of n
greasy pair of buckskin brcechos, which
wero hidden by flowing garments, and
from which she hauled n plug of tobac
co, and pasFcd It to her admirer with a
winning smile, nnd tho polite invitation
of "Juo tuko n chaw Joo fell bnek iu
amazement, nml exclaimed, "Buys, if
this y'ar isn't Jim Fulsom iu pottlconts,
I'm a cnyuso." The April fool sell wns
then seen through, and Tyler had to
bent n hasty retreat, whllo thu supposed
widow niHilo her exit through tho bnek
door nnil hroko for tlic bush lo cscnpo
the wrnth of thu crowd. Tho Jtttlgo
now hicks only thirteen hnlrs of being
halt! headed, owing to the wrathful man
ner iu which hn ran his lingers through
bis thin locks, when ho learned that the
lovely widow was none olhor than Jim
Fulsnm, a smooth-faced miner, rigged
out for tho occasion. Helena Gazette.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=april+pranks+fools</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>NEWS OF THE DAT.
-Lord de Grey and Ripon bas been re-elect?
ed Grand Master of Free Masonry In England.
-'?BitU Bun" Bussell ls to accompany tho
Russian force to Khiva for the London Times.
The Russian government ls Bald to have spe?
cially invited "The Thunderer" to send a cor?
respondent.
-Two State elections will be held within a
week. On Wednesday. Rhode Island will
choose now State officials, and on Monday,
April 7| iLhe Connecticut election will take
place?
-By a new French law the sale of liquor lo
drunkard 3 or minors is punished by flue and
Imprisonment, and the cost ot being drnnk
and disorderly In public range] lrom five
francs lor a first offence to 750 francs and dis?
franchisement lor two years.
-Mr. E. N. Davis, a planter ol Mississippi,
has utilized a large portion of hitherto un?
productive land by dividing lt Into a dozen
small, farms and Importing twelve lam liles
lrom North Carolina to cultivate them on
abat-es.
-Miss Susan B. Anthony hos been voling
.ga'ln. The Rochester Union ls authority for
the statement that she voted at the election
In that cly recently, and that two other
"strong-minded women" also cast ballots.
Nobody was bold enough to challenge them.
-A new machine for carving on stone ls at?
tracting the attention of builders and others
in New York. It ls known as the "gear stone
ornamenting and surfacing machine." IC ia
claimed that it will do as mach work In a day 1
as one hundred men, and at a great saving In
coat. 'I
-Boston testifies to the "good side" o?
hnman nature, In the fact that, Bince the big
.blase, macy firms have been surprised at the
payment of debts long since outlawed and for-
gotten. An Instance ls told of the firm of j
which ex-Governor Cia fl lu is the head, who
Uara'Jost received $8000, the balance of a
debt, with Interest, which was settled in bank?
ruptcy many yean ago.
-The "Salary Steal is the na rm the news-
papers ef the North and East have generally
given to the late Increase of the pay of Con- I
gressmen. Among the BOW views given on
this subject by con.?cience-stricken or sens!- 1
tlve members of Congress is lo make capital
ont ol il at home by paying the sum of their
extra salary into the treasury ol the county In y
which they resldp. Not a few have done this,
lt ls said; and they intend to keep their action
a profound secret. The Albany Evening Jour?
nal announces that Congressman W. W.
Wheeler, of the seventeenth district of New
York,han refused his back pay. He drew the t
money, Invested lt in United States bonds and 1
then cancelled the bonds.
-The practice of leaving the gas lighted
In the city stores at night has been generally
adopted as the most effectual means of foiling
burglars. Exposure to the passing glance ot
policeman or passenger is supposed, and In
the generality of cases wisely supposed, to be
a more ample protection than the barred
doors and windows, and the utter darkness ot
old times. A case of bursary recently occnr- 1
red in one ol the most crowded parts of New I
York, however, which shows the futility of I
plans presumably the most secure. There,
ander the full glare of the gas light, before
toe magnificent building of the Young Men's
Christian Association, while an entertainment
waa going on and hacks were crowded belore
the door, a hack drove ap unnoticed, o? 1
course, among so many others, and a party of 1
men alighted; went boldly up lo the entrance
of-one ot the stores facing the street; entered 1
by means ellher of lalse keys or by quickly I
picking the look, abd-In the full blaze of the I
constantly burning gas selected what plunder 1
they desired, and drove ol. They were seen
by a number of persons, but so confident and
at ease were they that everybody supposed
they had a right to be there, and nobody at-
tempted to disturb them.
-The last scheme o? organized benevolence
ls the New York Diet Kitchen. Its objects is
to co-operate with the dispensaries in taking
care of the sick' poor. Any physician who has i
visited among the poor will testify that many, 1
very many, die who might be saved If nour- 1
lshlng food could be procured for them. In
the midst of a civilized community, where
thousands of dollars are dispensed each
month in charities, these people perish of J
whatweocuid aimost call starvation. They
are succored whon their wanta are made t
known to the benevolent, but this only hap- t
pens in Isolated, casen. The physician does 1
what he can, but his means are not sufficient j
to give food to his poorer patients ns well as 1
medicine, for il is usually the younger and j
les? wealthy of the profession who attend
these cases. Therelore this New York Diet 1
Kitchen has ample scope for Its exertions, 1
and ls a blessed charity. The association win 1
entaollsh in each of the dispensary districts 1
one or more "diet kitchens," from which, on 1
the r?quisition of the visiting physician,
property prepared food will be issued at such
times and in such quantities as may be sped-
fled.
-Frederick Greer, of New York, Is one of 1
those literary Bohemians who get up blogra-
ph les ol those who are emulous ol immortality e
of a more substantial kind iban Is given by
the prese. He was engaged in this Grub street
work when the great crash came which over?
whelmed Tweed and otners In a common min.
Unfortunately, be bad then the flattering bio?
graphy of the great ring-master in band. To
his pecuniary IOSB, however, Tweed was far
less Inclined to biographic honors ina i when
the work uas undertaken, and the courtly
and insinuating Greer first approached bim
OD the subject. He refused to pay tor the
tame that had trickled down from the pen of
the latter. Now Jay Gould proves recalci?
trant. His biography has been done to order
in the very best style. He contracted to take
ten copies of the book at one hundred and
fifty dollars per copy, which shows what a
genius, hitherto hld In obscurity, Mr. Greer
ls. Bo blgb did the latter rate his ability that
even this was not satisfactory. He alleges
that Jay Gould ordered more copies, and he,
consequently, wanta more pay. They have
bad a little suit about lt, aod Jay Gould offers
to compromise.
April Fool.
The origin or "April Fool" ia as remote
aod as impossible to determine as the birth?
day of the first fool who marred Nature's
original design of intellectual Man. We
trace it everywhere; but the Beeret hour of
its birth ba files research. We are forced to
admit its existence, without being able to
assign a cause. The Romans undoubtedly
enjoyed its questionable fun. They cer?
tainly carried its memory in all their con?
quests. Its observance was long cherished
among numer?os nations. Abandoned to
the yalgar in our self-elected age of extreme
refinement, Momus seems to revenge him?
self by selecting the most elevated and dig?
nified objects for bis practical jokes. Nor
man, cor nation, nor things visible, nor
things invisible can elude bis satire. Nature
herself seems convulsed with his sly sport.
Her groans over a fallen race turn into in?
voluntary, hysterical laughter at the bidding
of this giant Harlequin, on whose kingdom
tbe Ban never sets.
The most pathetic scenes provoke the
wildest mirth. We see men of bonor and
repaie taking advantage of National schemes
to secare private emolument; dividends the
only consideration, the divisor of no conse?
quence. April Fool 1 Divisor of scheme,
plus dividends, laughing at his dupes, and,
thanking Heaven he is not like other men,
proving bis integrity by tbe faith of his
fr ?en dB. April Fool
The rightful Government of Louisiana
using itself as a trowel to cement tbe crum ti?
ling Kellogg platform striking the first
blow lo insure its own annihilation. April
Fool I Louisiana issalog addresses and
sending representatives to the Union at
large, convinced that her distress must be
of National in ten ;t. April Fool 1
Amadeos accepting the Spanish Grown'
which bas so loog been unsettled that ils
balance cac not be determined; giving a
gratuitous kick to accelerate ita certain fall.
April Fooll Spanish Cortes insisting OD
the recognition "de facto'? of a republic
which does not exist "de jure;" selling op
a ten-pio Republic for ihe mero sport of j
bowling it down. April Fool
England's tories and whigs doing their
best to destroy the ablest minister of the
Crown on the question of the Irish Univer?
sity; paying tilhes of "mint, annis and
"cummin" while neglecting the weightier j
matters of tbe law. April Fool
France with Thiers more iban king, shoot?
ing itself hoarse wilh "Vive la R?publique 1
"A bas l'Empire I A bas la monarchie I"
April Fool
Ukraine peasants revolting against an
?utocrat who owns half the Continent of
Surope; ramming themselves lalo monars"
br the mere chance of being discharged at
heir masters' heads. April Fool
Each nation convinced that "the Par lia
"mentof Man, and Federation of the world"
s to be convoked ander its own vine and tig
:ree. April Fool 1
Each sect persuaded that the whole world
viii soon have bat one Faith, and that Faith
ta own especial creed. April Fool 1
Honor, probity, patriotism, troth and
rirtae sb/J! prove'a successful candidate
tgaiost rampaot Vice. April Fool I
All the world surging, restless, doped and
laping, cries: April Fooll
Deep calling onto deep in awfal sport-all
.be waves and waterspouts shoaling in
nocking derision April Fool I And men in
childish rage and impotent wrath yell to
?ach other and the Universe at large: Toa
ire-April Fool 1</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.156,1.024,0.236,0.267,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>ON ALL FOOL'S BAT
i
Brainy Men Ten of First of April
Fancies.
Actor, Artist, BatlrUt, Lawyer, Preacher.
Etc, All Have Something to bar
About This, the Fool
Catcher's Day.
COPTBIOHi; 183 L
H E stage is in
Eomo measure
responsible for
All Fool's day.
So the histo.
rians tell us.
They say it
grew out of an
old Easter
miracle play in
Irhich the sending of Christ from An
bas to Caiaphas and from Pilot to
Herod was the basis of the mediaeval
Jramatist's plot. But I don't think
Hie stage has stuck to its offspring.
We actors are a serious lot of people,
particularly the comedians among us,
for paradoxical as it may seem, acting
Is all work and no play, and conse
quently Jack is a dull boy. We would
"MSTEIt, TXEASE GIVE ME A IIFT. JTLI.
TOU?"
T like to April fool our manager, perhaps,
but we don't April fool ourse'ves, be
cause that would be rather cruel.
I have outgrown the frolicsomenes
of April 1, of course; still I always look
carefully after my coat tails on that
day. And I greatly enjoy the motley
of those who are careless about their
parraental caudals during the Feast of
All Fools. The sight makes me feel
quite a boy again, for we youngsters
used to do that sort of thing in Phila
delphia thirty years ago. 0 yes, I did
It, too. I believe that some of the live
lier children of Philadelphia do it yet,
and have vitality and energy enough
left to laugh at the result, as a comio
paragrapher would say.
The most foolhardy of all the tricks
which I can recall in connection with
this carnival of jeering and nonsense
Is one that I have never seen played
Eince I was old enough to require two
digits to express my age. A bag and
two boys were the ingredients of the
trick, and it never failed to 6core a
great success on a quiet side street.
One boy got into the bag and the other
Stood by it waiting for the victim. The
rest of the boys who were "in on the
ground floor" were hiding in hallways
and doors and behind trucks across
the street. An innocent citizen came
W sauntering along. The boy who had
hold of the neck of the bag stopped
him with a "Say, mister, please give
toe a lift, will yer?" The innocent cit
izen usually acquiesced and took hold
of the bag to land it on the youngster's
shoulder. Just as he got it fairly in
his hands the boy in the bag suddenly
kicked and screamed. Innocent vic
tim, thinking it a bagful of wildcats
or hypnas. let go quickly and ran off
with palpitating heart and hair on end.
while all the boys across the street
pursued him with a villainous chorus
of "April fool 1 April fool! Wash
.your face and go to sclioU" or
something to the same effect. It
Talways seemed to me that the joke
was really on the boy in the bag;
he was sometimes dropped hastily
and heavily and was hurtand occa
sionally the April-fooled citizen gave
him a thrashing besides for being too
funny. But it was an effective trick.
and often an old codger lingered in the
shadow on the opposite pavement to
witness and enjoy the sport. You have
seen a man try to kick a plug hat full
of pig iron over into tho next state
Trell, bis discomfiture was no greater
IT MADE AIM SMD.E.
Good Ola reliOK Ali, hoT it warms ri7
bcart to see them playing their littlo inuoccm
tricks on the Brst or Apnlt Used to do It my
self when I was a toy. But ibey caa't fool me,
though I'm too oU a bird lor fiat.
than that of the man whoso blood was
frozen in his heart by the unexpected
scream emitted by the occupant of the
bag. Laugh? It would make a tomb
stone roll over in a fit of hysterics.
Jonx Drew.
fOMETIlIES IT GIVES PLEASURE TO OTHERS.
It doesn't seem right that the firs
flay of a month so full of pretty things
j is April is should be inseparably con
w nectcd in our minds with empty ard
dilapidated pocketbooks with string
in d-small-boy attachments, di&rep
ntable hats with bricks underneath
them, long streamers hanging from
l nnsuspecting coattails, door bells
rung by invisible hands, and all the
other dear old pleasantries that we
know by heart. And we should prob.
ibly have had a society for the pre
rention of Anril fool iokes Ions aso if
It were not for the pleasure that call
aren gel out of them.
When a certain boy of my acquaint-
fcnee on April Grst. before breakfast,
Informs me that somebody is waiting
ft;' see me in the library, not for the
world would I refuse to go downstairs
and pretend extreme surprise at find
ing nobody there. Nor would any
thing induce me to decline the suspicious-looking,
cotton-filled piece of
candy which is shortly after offered
V.T. a fmnll rrirl I know. I bitA
UlUiD O
End- Hotter SS6? itLISSrularly i
every year, ana Mr. rfat Gooxnvm or
Mr. Francis Wilson would be glad if
he could raise such a shout of laughter
as easily and unfailingly.
Apropos of this train of thought
there is a little picture of mine in Puck,
published some years since, which will
perhaps bear transplanting here, and
which I subjoin.
Fbedeiuck Buitn Oppeb.
"de bazoo" is suggested.
If yer want a good joke on some ot
yer frcn's, give dem de razoo, see?
Dat's de way dey do in Xew York oa
April Fool day.
Yer work it dis way:
Suppose a man owes yer ten dollars
and won't pay yen Go see him and
ask him for it. He ses he ain't got it.
Wipe de floor wid 'him and take all de
cash in his pockets and when he kicks
apologize and se.y yer didn't mean fer
ter hurt him it'b April Tool, see? Den
yer needn't pive him de money back,
'cause he owe s it, yer see? Course yer
don't want ter try de razoo on anyone
not under yer size, see?
Den yer kin pay off all yer old
grudges de same way. Or if yer hun-
gry and ain't got no money walk inter
de restrint, see, and eat all yer kin,
and say it's April Fool, see, and run
out widout payin' nothin'.
Dat's de racket fer April Fool de
razoo. Steve Erodie.
TO LESSEN THE DEVTL'S FOOLS.
I am abked for a sentiment concern
ing April Fool's day and pause in the
whirl and rush of a righteous warfare
to say that in my opinion time is far
too valuable and important a factor
for a moment to be lost in foolish jest
ing or senseless joking. The world,
especially in these days, is in far too
critical and dangerous a position, so
cially and religiously, to allow of a
man with average sense to saj' noth
ing of those who have consecrated
brains to indulge in any other than
profitable and upright intercourse.
It is a personal relief to me to feel
that in our ranks seventeen hundred
officers and sixteen thousand unpaid
local workers will be pushing with
might and main of soul an enterprise
which upholds sincerity and the ne
cessity of lessening the devil's fools.
Ballington Booth.
A CHA3IPI0X FOR THE DAT.
Before stating what jokes seem to
me timely, and enjc&abJe ior this
S&-
WIPE DE FLOOB WID niil."
April Fool's day, I cannot resist th
temptation to say that I think the
spirit of the holiday itself hat always
been singularly misunderstocd. The
day is really to be deemed a pause in
time's serious flight, when folly could
with propriety travesty wisdom, and
set the world smiling. As it is, the
first of April has come to be deemed a
nuisance, wheu its observance is not
don away with entirely. April Fool's
day is sadly in need of soue one to
champion it and xestoi e it to its right
ful place in the calendar. It is not
simply the day on which the boys and
girls may make fools of their elders
with impunity. I suspect that there
was a time when it was regarded
rightly, far away as that time seems
to us now. Then the old people put
aside their serious looks and grew
younger instead of older.
If it takes a wise man to be a fool,
surely April first is the feast day
of the saircs. when thev can act on
Shakcspsare's admonition: "Mingle a
little folly with your wisdom."
As for those jokes which seem to mi
good and appropriate to the dav it
should always be understood that the
element of surprise is the essential
thing. Novelty is wit. Jokes must not
bo cruel pranks, otherwise the day
would ba given up to a general hazing
of everybody. The most successful of
April Fool jokes would be to surprise
one's friends by a change of character.
What a rare joke it would be for the
confirmed miser to bestow a dowry
upon that niece of his who needs only
a little money to marry the lad of her
choice. If all the cranks would put
rside their hobbies for a day, what fun
it would be for the rest of us.
This kind of joke can be carried out
ad finitum and would never fail to bo
successful. Let the tippler remain
sober to-day just as a joke. The skin
flint employer can have a lark with
his clerk by granting that increase of
salary that has been talked about so
long. Let the clergyman I say it
reverently preach a sermon only an
hour long to-day instead of one of
four hours' duration. I am convinced
that the idea would meet with success.
People too old for jokes on April
Fool's day? Xouscnc. Even the gray
heads can have their joke. The repro
bate roue can go to church this morn
ing and explain that it is all a joke on
his part. Many a man is ashamed to do
a good thing because it is so unusual
with him that it would give him un
pleasant prominence. But he can do
it to-day and escape with the admis
sion that it is his April fool joke. I
am glad the day comes on Sunday this
year. B. Gillax.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024442/1896-03-29/ed-1/?sp=17&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=0.195,0.753,0.368,0.415,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>THE WASHINGTON TIMES hmmu
Part 3
"WASHINGTON, D. C., SUNDAY MORNING, MAliCII 29, 1S0G.
LS THESE MORTALS
AN
DYLL
APRL
WHAT
BE
:,0
lift
I t
I II i fc
a.CE upon a time" in truUi,
quite recently then.' were
fomefislilliat were haul to be
of greatdepth, hothas to t heir
bailiwick and intelligence.
One Would e-neso frnm llilc
description that they were taw-fiMi, that
Is, wise-saw fish, hut they were not. They
were eimpij- hucKeru; yec mey knew It
was April 1'ool'b Day.
On tljat Fame
day a man went
Fooling the Fishes-Bait 3SSa J "J
Without Hooks. sot him down on
the wharf and let
downhisliiicand
bait. The water
was clear and he
could ee the
6uckers blinking
and winking at
each other and
rubbing their
nuouts, against
tlie tempting
bait.
"HeiliinkKhe's
run up against
the highland
suckcr."mid fin
ny No. 1 to. scaly
No. and noo
dle No. :t i early
swallowed the
bait at short
range laughing
at the sucker at
the o'lier nil of
the'ne. But he
fWifdrifJitalong
till the fun grew
hot.imd (hen he
Tilled his pipe
and hauled up
his line.
Nov.h-'reisa
moral 'nthisMo
ry. Th'-re was
no jojK in the
merry li'-l.er-m
a n s b a i r,
wlui h goes to
show that peo
ple who .ue too
wise to "Lite"
very often get
left. e en as the
fish didn't know
a good Uiing
when it was in
dubitably i n
their line.
And on that
same day in the
same generation,
a spinster lady
declined to ojX'ii
a letter, good
forthisdayonlv,
no rain checks. Is
sued, which letter
con tninoda bona
fide healed pro
IKaltj,.Uheand MieMioukl tarry
togetlier at Jeri
cho, or an j place
elM- where there
was good tarry
ing, swooning
and crooning in
the thick after
noon iK-rfiimeof
lot uracil orange
blos.-om. And
the next da j the
died.
Oil the 1st of
April, la-t, a
joung wieacre,
who lives on
New Ilauipclure
aieuuc. received
a letter ,y f.pe.
cial im-sMMiger.
It wab fcuper
bcribedina plain
round hand, and
in the left-hand
corner were the
words "Pmate;
marked down to
10, former val
ue &o." The
letter was re
turned to the
writer, with the
remark on the
margin. "Don't
need any spring
clothes." The
lot terrnerel j con
tained a part
Iiaynient of $20
on a $30 -debt
or honor" which
accrued from
lost borrowed
chips
So when the
bride of only
two Aprils tcle
Kraphed to her
husband In New
i'ork from
"Washington the
thrilling mc-s-fiage.
"Two ana
all's well," lie re
ceived it, "Two
and all swell."
He replied 'Had
eight. -a j self and
feel much swcll
er." She ws a
little -mrpi-ised,
to be sure, and
whei icy grow
up she will tell
the twins about
the mind reading
capaeu y cf a
handsome clerk
of the Oimis Of
fice. These hlMorl
calcaes are not
ed by way of pre
lude to i he slate
ment rhat April
Fools' Day Is
again with us, or
will be on "Wed
nesday next. Af
ter these i-ad ex
amples of mind
read mg, it will
be only t tie more
perplexing to
discover the dif
ference between
looking the gift
horse !u the
mouth and the
gift horse him
self should lie
gallop up to the
door.
One half of the
world will begin
on "Wednesday to,
play pranks on
Uie other half,
and it is an in
teresting day be
cause we have
only two such
days on Uie cal
endar, the other
being Talentine
Day. Election
day Miotild. per
haps, be added,
buttoallofthem
FaUier A braham
undoubtedly re
ferred when he
got off the fa
mous bit or phi
losophy, "You
can fool all of
the people tome
of Uie time, etc.,
etc. otr.
The misfortunes of the day are hke the
premonlUons of fctieezeg. STou know they
are coming, but you can't prevent their
arrival, so It is much better to Miecze
at once, even If your mouth Is full of
turtle soup, than to fight against the in
evitable. It Is better even to take in
the bundle on Uie doorstep than to kick
Ef 55
Vtr
JEm)
Some Old and New Jokes Suggested
The Times for Next Wednesday.
Of Course the Small Boys' WeMried and Proven Schemes Wil
Hold Sway, hut There Is a Chance to Extend Them
into Municipal and National Life
TH SUMS
uoke
by
v d y
f art" and 'Teller." havinsr done -which ha
strode oat of the room. leaviojr the second
fiddle- to play out the score.
It will probably be a bad d7 for king
makers, ho wevcrgooditniay be rorpotitical
fctol makers. In a quiet, coay room In a
Philadelphia hotel there are gathered
together the elect of the Warwlcka
of this day and generation, fore
most among whom are Piatt, Quay and
C I ar krer
"V.
fffj VfLLET vairR
STRlFHi iu v
rti r SL. x pA.
.,mn jr.r.
iA the o rryki ittL -T Ak
Some Ancient and Honorable April Fool Jokes.
Uie little stranger Into the street. There
may be millions awaiting the long-lost
heir before jou die.
The compliments of the season are firstly
due to Uie three destinies of "Washington.
Messrs. Koss, Truesdell and Poweil. Tliej
will do a land-office business on April
Fools' I)a They will be bitting at a Uel
shazzar's feast, and lo' there appears on
Uie wall a strange bcroll in the Kalorama
dialect.
The Attorney for the District and the
interpreter of the clastic law of the local
Medcs and Persians Is called in and he is
promised fine raiment and an amethystine
ring ir he expounds the letters of fire on the
wall. Kefer.'ncc to Uie snap shot of the oc
casion will be found in the margin or tins
page. Of course, tins maj not happen, but
it ought to, which isa much better considera
tion. There is one place in the United States
where eerj thing can happen, proidcd
always it is not something practical even
will enforce the rules and order the gal
leries to be cleared.
Mr. Morrill of Maine Mr. President, I
have lieen llfty jcars in the Senate in the
ambassadorial capacity of a Senator from
Maine, atrl I have ncer jet heard
The Toreign Voice I am a talker my-f-clf.
(Renewed applause from Uie gal
leries.) The President The sergeant-ai-arms will
arrest that obnoxious peiaonage.
The galleries are cleared, and the ser-
whlch to exclude the April Foots Day dis
turbers of the White House peace.
In the mind's ee, without even a warm
application of the Roentgen ray, it is easy
to see the fighters against follv seated at
the table in what the President told the
delegation of Baptist ministers was his
"workshop." Ip a certain sense, tin-, is
true, because It is there lie saws wood. The
President casts aside carefully all tlie
suspected letters and puts all the packagi-v
Iu a tub of water near him on the floor
to kill the microbes and anymcidental dyna
mite. The morning is passed away pleas
antly, and he asks for a cigar.
"What kind, extellenzaZ" queries F. A.
H in one-third Spau'sn and two-thirtls
Iiayard.
"A Duke of Veragua," replies excellenza.
and Fie-Tt!oi!sard-DolIars-a-Year in the
future opens a new Ijok. The rest of this
story is done in black and white pictonally
on this Seventeenth Page. In scene the sec
ond the unfortunate bot-opener la on his
tr
iiiiinwifi ll'ir i5j
4m
April 1 at the District Building:.
A Neat Little April Eiiect in the Senate.
a Joke. To guess the name of that place
is not as hard as guessing the number of
five black beans in a transparent jar. It
is the United States Senate,
In the afternoon of "Wednesday next,
after the morning hour, the Cutian olla
podrida will be in full blast. Senator
Lodge will hae spoken on the letter that
never came to Secretary Olney, Senator
Mills will hae taken Cuba "vi et aimls,"
and Senator Hale will have delivered his
accustomed eulogy on the late Don Canovas
de Quixote. The listening Senate ib suddenly
startled by a thin foreign voice, which
says, "I'm something of a talker mjself."
Applause breaks out in the galleries.
The President of the benatc-If these
demonstrations are repeated the President
vtw n
A Joke on the Republican RiBg-sters
geantr.it-arms and Firsts Assistant Stewart
rush up into the peanut' reservation. They
return and report that the miscreant has
escaped.
The Presldent-The Senate "will be In
order.
Mr. Chandler As I was saying, Mr.
President, I
The Torclgn Voice I am something of a
talker mjself.
Nothing could exceed -the commoUon in
the Senate when its courtesy was thus sat
upon and spat upon by this intruder. It
was the eagle eje of Senator Sherman
of "Our Foreign Relations" Committee
that discovered the intruder, winch was
quietly looking askance at the President
out of its white-winged eye, a beautiful
queen red and gold parrot direct from Bar
celona. "It Is a Spanish spy," declared Mr.
Lodge.
"It should be shot at drum head," as
severated the fiery Tennessean.
"Try it from the clock," said Mr. Mills.
"Willi the Presidential gun," added Mr.
Hill of New 1'ork. i
Suggestions, however, do not kill birds
at long range, and. the pages were on the
qui vive of excitement lo be let loose on
the most consistent talker at that moment
In the Senate. They were eager for the
bird to fly down and light on tlie bald head
of some Senator, like the eaglathat alighted
on the head of the husband of Tanaquii.
But the spy did not move, keeping his
sinister eye on the Vice President, and
evidently getting ready to sing his unwel
come song again.
Mr. Lodge Eutcka, lMr. President: Per
scalam ad avem.
The President Gqod; has the scrgeant-at-arms
a ladder about him?
The sergeant-at-arms at -once procured
Uie ladder on which he climbed into office,
placed it up against the lintels of the' east
door, and reached for ithe parrot, which
was seated on the Senatorial clock a la
Poc's raven.
Did the sergeant-at-arms land the bird?
Not on your negative. The bird had a
string tied to him and. he'-was hauled aver
the parapet, and tle small boy at the oUicr,
end of the string simply hauled In the fes-'
the Spaniard, opened a -gallery door and
went down stairiand .filled himself full of
apple pic.
This may not happen.but It ought to. A
son of one or the surviiors of the Ford's
Theater disaster would be tlie logical perpe
trator of this lecfure by the pariot to the
Senate.
Too mucU .sympathy cannot be -wasted be
tween now and "Wcdnesdaj'onthefeeilngs of
the Chief Magistrate "with respect to his
mail and exprc packages on the day -we
celebrate. Thcrofhavc plrendj' been con
ferences between him anci Fldus Achates
Henrlcus Tiberius on taii; beet manner in. I
rjtt&n.
knees ascrvatmg in shattered sentences to
the accusation or the Potentate of the Poto
mac that he smelt treason in the tainted
gale.
"if third term doesn't go, lese mnjeste
doe-." thunders the man of destiny.
"1 know it doe?, Your Majesty, but by
the saber of my father I knov not who is
the nuereant, unless it be some godless
member of the 1. W. X. M. of the Occi
dental provinces."
"And who are they, caitiff?"
l-eonie who Need Missionaries, Ex
cellcnza." "Then, bj- mj- halidom, they shall have
Uiem galore before the ides or April."
And with that His Mijestj-seized bis tab
lets and wrote deep in the wax"'Colorado."
"North Dakota," "Oklahoma," "Stew-
til
r
Somebody's Little Joke en Groyer.
Little Willie's OrieinaJ
Idea.
U (!L
''r
T'&ryS "U
misfortune "vr K7 ""7 JaB
trying to J "M
doiitwheth- X Nr"V 1 H
there's a V A V l
-"vvr-' "rv.-oB
A-N1
sV: V-
J
f
.r
They are not
afraid of any
sword of Da
mocles.orknlfc up the sleeve
of Crofcer. or
any other gift
of the Greeks.
But they didn't
reckon on tie
.'deus ex ma
chiua" of a
Philadelphia
hotel.
With a rattle
of tfti plates
and a creaking
of woolen cord
a g e, down
comes Mr. Mc-Kinlej-.
stuffed
full of the
"looks that
way," and the
reast and fun
go out with the
lights and
that Is noioke.
The tevsons
of April Fool's
Day are many
and valuablelf
studied practl-callj-.
A man
stiouM not let
his hcue burn
down becaus",
wiseinhisown
conceit, I s
neighbor telLs
him that r.ts
house is on fre.
At the farce
tirnr, if all tl e
night caps and
nightdresses in
Paradise allej
are sprinkled
from the hose
of the small
boy on the roof
who has been
paid to sLai.t
"fire," It enly
goes to show
that there is a
certain degree
of
in
fin i
lire in your
own house by
looking out of L.
the window.
The place to r.
look is in the ir3-'
bamcnt, or
any other In-sidepreclnct-Again
the
nan who pas
s wisely bj- a
silver dollar on
the pavement
feels had when
he looks back J JCTI-i' J
and sees that r
another man 4 t
has parted it up
safely. If it's a
iweketbook the
eae is all t'ic
sadder. Or. If
the man w.'.o
believes that ic
is better t fa'ce
in the baby off
the d. orst p,
takes itardtelL,
hKi wife al.ut
it, maj- r pcu
the bundle to
find in itc ncof
ouroldfriTiis,
the rag labj.
So, agam. the
bnckinthehat
Is inevitable,
but it Is no use
to go home in
that condition.
It. of coarse,
requires a good
deal of forti
tude and saw
teeth to eat a
cotton batting
dumpling, or to
chew, with a
scriptural face
even a small
piece of candy
with a j-anvin-side,
but it is
said that It ha3
been done rath
er than ac
knowledge the
joke, but in "r
nearlv all nf
Uie instances
Uie patients
died as mar
tyrs, like the
Who let: the Z. T
foc eat. nut of 'wil
his breadbas
ket rather thnn
be indicted for I f
dealing the
fox. I I
If you find
It yarn or cot
ton, spit n c ut i ?sgss3
iiiuii. i is vt -5;,
Reach for all I t?it'i SS
the nunev in
sight, ric up
all the pot'et
books, open all
jour icttcrs,
receive all the
visitors in or
out of myster
ious lirdles,
foronth.s par
ticular da it's
the only way
to i o e t h.e
problemsof the
other fool. It
Is somewhat
strange that a
person wl o be
lies esat it is
theucexrcctcd
that always
happens.scoms
to look behind
him when a
small boj- jay
to him confi
dentially: "Mis
ter, jour lorse
hasdroppedhis
tail." it is
human nature
to look back
when he has
turned the cor
ner. There have
beenverymnny
8age tomes
written about
the origin and n HfTTT f
uses of April ,h; rrh7-
Fool's Day.
Som writers
ascribe to it a
Roman, and
others a Greek
origin, it is
more than likely that It began on the day
when Esau tried to pas himself off for
Isaac with their bliud parent. Abraham.
Atu.ia.tia, i.onutr, dtetovrtl tUat the
kLii.iI okC-r lad hair en hi brain and.
tho t o-n. of Esau was launched for all
the rget. They have had hairs on their
brains cer since.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&q=april+fool+pranks&st=text&r=-0.056,-358.211,1.111,717.778,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>THE SAN FRANCISCO CALL, SUNDAY, APRIL 2, 1899.
APRIL CALLED
OUT ALL ITS
ARMY OF FOOLS
The Jester and Victim
Alike Make Merry.
THE MORGUE'S BUSY DAY
McENERNEY AND HIS COUN
TERFEIT PRESENTMENT.
Sad Tale of the Dentist Apprentice
and the Soubrette Who Could
Not Find the Key to the
Curtain.
April dawned bright and beaming and
kept merry throughout its. first day
blithely warbling between laughs, "Al!
fools look alike to me."
In spite of the fin de siecle pessimist
and his prophecy that All Fool's day was
a landmark of the past, the jester was
out In splendid form and landed gudgeons
galore.
The fun began early and lasted late.
A very few new jokes were perpetrated
and all the old ones revived, while the
usual good humor of both jester and vic
tim prevailed during the entire day. The
email boy was not so much in evidence
;is in previous years. Thoughts of Easter
eggs on the morrow, coupled with the ar
duous duties of trying on new suits and
boots and hats, drove for once all
thoughts of mischief from the mind of
the budding lords of creation. The offi
cials at the Morgue were the first to fall
victims to the merriment- of the day.
When the day was but a half hour old
—at 12:30 a. m.— a telephone call, pre
sumably coming from the Receiving Hos
pital, summoned a Deputy Coroner to take
charge of a body at the Hobson House.
"Hurry-up wagon" and Deputy went
quickly to the place, only to find that
April had dawned and that some one un
known wa? taking liberties with dignified
city officials.
In fact, the Morgue, or. rather, the
Morgue's telephone, was the greatest fcuf
fen-r during the day. The bell rang un-
-ceasingly from early morning until mid
i night and all sorts of messages were
voiced- over the line. Heartless wretches
also employes this method of fooling un
suspecting friends.
Tiner-aling-iing.
"Hello! Well—"
"Oh. la that you. Mary? This is Jim.
Say Mr. Wilson wants to speak with you.
Call him up— No. 1947."
•'Hfllo. No. 1947! Ts this Mr. Wilson?"
"No: this is the Morgue."
A bang— that's Mary's telephone— a
enwe— that is the Morgue.
While people were having fun at the
expense of the city the' city was enjoying
Its own pet little April fool joke—repeat
ing the prank over and over a^aln and
hailing each new victim with shouts of
applause and the shrill tooting of horny.
At the junction of Market. Kearny. and
Third streets at regular intervals a box,
neatly packed and stamped, as though
rc-ady for mailing, would glare the guile
less pedestrian straight in the face. Many
a man, woman and child, representing all
sorts and conditions of society, stooped
to pick up the innocent-appearing box.
None got any farther than the attempt.
The shouts of the crowd, many of them
previous victims, scared the parcel-picker
off, and he hastily lost himself in the
throng and waited in his turn for some
one to laugh at.
It was both a costly and hair-raising
April fool experience that Walter Mosier
had. Mosier. a young man possessed with
an ambition to learn dentistry, is em
ployed by Dr. Perkins, a Sixth-street den
tist. Walter's bogs occasionally allows
him to putter around the molars of his
customers who are out of funds.
One of thes? occasions arose Friday and
Mosier was delegated to perform the
charity service. The, victim was a boy
about 12 years of age. He was suffering
from an ulcerated tooth, and Mosier de
cided that the nerve must be killed, so
forthwith he filled the cavity in the
troublesome tooth with enough arsenic
to kill a horse and sent the unfortunate
youth home happy.
When Dr. Perkins came in Mosier, with
the dignity of a full-fledged dentist, told
his employer of his charity work. Then
Dr. Perkins thought of April fool.
"Say, Mosier." said the dentist, with a
serious look on his features. "I've just
received a telephone message to the ef
fect that the arsenic came out of that
boy's tooth and he swallowed it."
"My God!" exclaimed, the would-be
dentist. lf ls he going to die?"
"Well, the doctors are working on him
now, but they don't think they can save
his life."
"Say. Doc, I'm going to get out of town
before this kid dies. I don't want to get
pinched."
"Well." said Dr. Perkins, with a merry
little twinkle in his eye. "You can suit
yourself about that, but I'd advise you to
stay here. They-can't do any more than
charge you with mupder."
"Murder! Ugh! Don't say that. Dr.
Perkins," retorted Mosier, tearfully. "I
didn't mean to do It. I'll go and take
some arsenic myself."
The crestfallen apprentice spent several
moments of contrition and then he made
up his mind to get out of town. He got
50 cents from Perkins and made haste to
the nearest barber-shop, where he Invest
ed it in a haircut and a Bhave. M osier
gave the tonsorial artist orders to cut
}-is hair to the scalp and Bhave his sprout
ing mustache entirely off, hoping thereby
m disguise himself. The badly frightened
youth then returned to the office to learn
further detnils of his mythical victim's
condition. Dr. Simpson told him th« boy
was worse and Mosfer. started to leave the
office. "Wait a minute." called Perkins.
"Where are you going?'
"God knows where I'll go, but I'll never
go to jail for poisoning- that kid," an
swered the youth.
"You go down to the ferry to-morrow
and if the boy dies I'll telephone to you,"
suggested the doctor.
Mosier slipped out to his mother's
home, borrowed 510 and as early as 1
o'clock yesterday morning he arrived
at the ferry thoroughly disguised to
avoid possible detection. He walked up
and down the cheerless and 'desolate
wharves till morning, and then not hear
ing anything from Dr. Perkins bought a
ticket for Sacramento and stole aboard
the boat like a skulking criminal. On
the train he acted for all the world like
a noted forger crossing the line to Can
ada.
ttosiec confided to a friend before he
left that he would commit BUicide rather
than go to jail, which knowledge tuning
to Dr. Perkins made him decide noi to
cfrty the Josh any further. A message
was sent to the frightened youth, and
he returned to the city. Last night he
set about to drown his troubles in the
flowing bowl.
Garret McEnerney fell a victim to a
deeply laid April Fool plot laid for him
by his "close up" friend Jim O'Brien..
The bulky and brainy man of the law
dropped into O'Briens office, commonly
termed the "Cabinet," yesterday noon to
engage the contractor in a little chat.
"Say. Garret." chipped in O'Brien in
an innocent fashion just when the law
yer was i-xplaining to Jim Nealon the
way to make money, "when did you
stand for that bust over in the Palace?"
"What bust?" queried Mr. McEnerney.
"Why. the file they put in the corridor
of the Palace Hotel this morning," said
O'Brien as seriously as if he was talking
business with a moneyed man who want
ed- to spend a "thou or two" in street
work.
"There must be some mistake?" said
McEnerney. "No sculptor ever chiseled
me."
O'Brien is "close up," and his words
had weight with the man who was so
busy dissolving -the injunction against
Chief Lees that he did not stop to think
of April Fool's day.
"Let's go over, Jim, and take a look at
it," said MeEnernty, and .they both start
ed out tho door. O'Brien had no inten
tion of going over with his friend to seek
What he knew to be a myth, so he con
trived to' be excused In a manner that
would not breed suspicion.
The opportunity presented itself when
Judge Lawlor happened along.
"I'm going to take the Judge on -for a
minute," said O'Brien. "You go over and
look at that yourself and I'll wait for
you."
Off went Mr. McEnerney and his April
Fool went down on the arc.hives of the
"Cabnit" as a decided success. Every.
body who dropped into the Cabinet was
sent over to the Palace Hotel to see what
McEnernev had looked for in vain.
"Pete" Dtinworth. the well-known vo
calist, was- the victim of a ghastly April
Fool josh. One of his friends telephoned
to Dunworth's house early yesterday
morning and informed him that an inti
mate friend had died the night before
and was to be buried immediately.
"They, want you to be a pallbearer,
Pete," said th-e wily person at the other
end of the line.
"All right." said the popular tenor, af
ter expressing genuine regret over tae
unexpected death of his friend.
Promptly at 1 o'clock Dunworth, ar
rayed in a black cutaway suit and white
gloves, arrived at the .undertaking par
lors from which the supposed dead friend
was to have been buried.
"Is this where Mr. So and So Is to be
buried from." asked Dunworth, giving
the undertaker the friend's name and ad
dress.
"Why, he 1b not dead," said the under
taker, "who knew the man very well. "I
just ?aw him "at the corner of Sixth and
Mission."
At the Alcazar they revived the old the
atrical joke of the "key of the curtain"
with marked success. Mrs. Willie Dun
phy, the latest addition to the company,
ten minute* before curtain raising at thp
matinee, was sent on a hunt for the "key
to the curtain." "We can't open up."
said Stage Manager Bryant. "We have
lost the key to the curtain." Mrs. Dun
phy. who glitters on the bills as Miss
Howard, searched high and low for the
key and was in a condition bordering on
hVfiterics when the last bars of the or
chestra died away and the curtain was
lifted without a key.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/?sp=4&q=april+fool+pranks</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>Concerning the origin of the name and custom of All fool's day
contributed more to the extermination of
the heathen religion and its priests than
all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
though they were also freely employed.
The continuance of customs— especially
droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
the masses— after the original cause of
them has been removed. Is a very common
occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
firmly believed that "fooling" people on
the Ist of April is simply a perpetuation
of the annual public ridiculing of the old
Druid's and their superstitions.
Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
character, 13 thus claimed for April Fools'
day In a quaint old book of folk-lore
called "Father Time's Flyghtes." pub
lished in London In 1659. "numerous
Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
Fools on the First of April. This is said
to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah
sending ye dove out before ye water had
abated, on ye first day of ye month which
among ye Hebrews answers to our first
of April, and to perpetrate ye memory of
this deliverance it was thought proper
whoever forgot so remarkable a circum
stance to punish them by sending them
upon some fool's errand similar to- the
Ineffectual message upon which ye bird
was sent by ye patriarch."
The French associate with the first of
April precisely the same Ideas as do Enr
llsh speaking nations, but the person Im
posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*.
they style an April Fl3h or Polsson d' -v
ril. In the "Etymology of French pro
verbs," a most curious and delightful
work published In 1356. Billlngton I the
author, gives the following expiation
of the origin of April Fool customs "The
word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and
length of time has almost totall- defaced
the original intention, which w^ as fol
lows: That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
took place about this time o'the year,
and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
and forward to mock and't->rment him.
1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caia
phas to Pilate, from Pilate Herod and
from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
from thence, by which we send about
from one place to anoO«r such persona
aa we think proper subjects of our ridi
cule."
But It Is not only thrjU&hout Great Brit
ain, France and our/own country that
fools are made on U« nrst day of April.
The custom 1- elabrratfly observed
throughout Sweden, aid In Germany an
April fool la called elnen zam April
shlcken." The same custom haa also been
observed in India fr>m time immemorial.
Late in March of hold a great celetratton which they call
the Hull festival, of which the last day
is the greatest aid most general holiday.
During the con.nuance of the Hull, one
of its chief dl^rsions is to send people
on errands ar^ expeditions that are to
end In disapr^ ntment anat the expend of the person sent.
But the cistom of making April fools
has-been traced back to an antiquity even
greater t!** n that of the Hull festival of.
the Hind 9 Tne ancient Persians wer»
accustorr«vernal rruinox. which may occur as early
as ila-^n 22 or as late as April 23. with
elaborv*the Utter the chief was the making of
fool- precisely as we are accustomed to
mate them on April Fools* day.
jjp a quaint volume of poem.l bearing
tH title, "Verses On Several Occasions."
i,.id published In London. 1752, April Foola'
.ay is thus alluded to:
Now April morn b!*r Folly's throas exalts:
Now Dobb calls Nell and lauebs because ah*
halts.
"While Nel! meets Tom and Bays his tall la
loose,
Then laughs In turn and caJTa poor Thoma
"Goose."
In England, from earliest times, th»
ridiculous errands upon which the victim
of an April fool Joke sent have been
called "sleeveless errands." but the origin
and true significance of this term ar»
completely buried in oblivion and no an
tiquary has yet been able to unearth
them. These errands are as numerous as
they are Ingenious. Some of them hava
almost become classics, such, for Instance.
as sending a person to a book store for
the second edition of "Cock Robin" or
the "History of Eve's Mother": sending
some one to a milk dealer for a pint ot
pigeon's milk and to, a shoemaker for an
ounce of strap oil. which, if the shoe
maker has been Initiated Into the Joke,
the Inquirer receives In the shape of a
severe blow from a strap acros3 the shoul
ders. AMY F. STOCKTON.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1902-04-01/ed-1/?sp=3&q=april+fool+pranks</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>April Fool Kept by All
People.
Gigantic Hoax Was a Complete
Success.
"This Is the first of April,
Hunt the gowk another mile."
From time itruneiuorlal thollrstof
April has been celebrated by all sorts of
hoaxes and playing of pranks. Tho
truo origin of April' Fool Is burled lu
tho dust of centuries and our great
est antiquaries seem unable to throw
any light on tho subject. Nearly all
people however, celebrate this day or
its equivalent and the similarity of
the practice and tho coincidence of
dutes establishes without n doubt In
the minds of authorities ihe fact that
It had an early nnd common origin
among mankind.
Nearly all tho peoples on the Conti
nent celebrate April Fool with pranks
and tricks, and even the Hindoos havo
a festival on tho 31st of March, called
Hull, which coincides vjlth our April
Fool.
Ono of the most popular amusements
on April 1, or All Fools day, as it Is
called, Is tho Rending of persons on
fruitless frrands. Unsophisticated
persons are sent to tho bookstores for
a copy of the "History of Eve's Grand,
mother," or to the chemist's shop for
"pigeon's milk," while small boys arc
sometimes sent to the harness shop for
strap oil, when a liberal dose of this
treatment Is usually administered to
the boy.
There Is a story told to the effect
that Francis, Duko of I,oiTaIne, mid
his wife owed their escape from cap
tivity at NanteH to this popular cus
tom. Arrayed as peasants, they were
makiug their way out. of the territory
when they were discovered by a wo
man who knew them. She Immediate
ly hastened to a guard, and told him"
that the Duko was escaping. "April
Fool," said the guard laughingly,
treating the matter as a joke, and
while he laughed the prisoners made
good tlieir escape
Occasionally a gigantic hoax Is per
petrated on tho people as a whole, and
such a one met 'with groat success in
London in I8RO. Some wag distributed
cards, bearing an official looking seal,
which read: "Tower of London Ad
mit the bearer to vlorv the annual core,
raony of the washing of the white lions
on Sunday, Aprij, 1, 1800. It Is par
ticularly requested that no gratuities
be given to wardens or their assistants.
Admitted only nt tho white gate."
This trick was highly successful,
and people swarmed to tho tower to
view tho washing of tho whlto lions.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1909-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=april+fools+pranks</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>APRIL FOOL HUNTERS ARE
ON THE JOB TODAY
"All Fools' Day."
Just why the first of April |1§
let apart as an occasion when
very.; wag hoe "j license .to pra'otloa
iewptlon on tils fellow
man and get the laugh «n him no
nne seems ,to know, bat the cus
tom is gen©r«l and o* loss stand
ln«.* And after all i ttia pranks ol
the "April Fool H tinnt«rs s» gen
smlly tharmless.
PW t yoa I are not abta Ito langa
when |g tfhe laugh Is Yon ni MM
lc««p jrou* wtta WMIM to iflj
NSURANCE
CONCERNS
BUMPED
ose Contest to Secure
Eepeal of Hughes Law
m Regulating Their
Business.</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=april+foolls+prank&st=text&r=0.111,0.529,0.335,0.379,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>JOKERS ANNIHILATE ARMIES
April-Fool Pranks Play Havoc With
European "War Map.
According io me map wmcu t-roi.
U p Wrench has prepared and kept
I
In the corridor of the third floor of
Academic Hall, European armies have
made radical changes in their ma
neuvers. The French apparently have
given up the war and have fled to the
western coast of France. The Eng
lish have disappeared entirely. All
the German forces of the western
theater are quartered in Paris. In the
east, the Austrian and German forces
are massed in the lowlands of Prus
sia, surrounded by Russian and Ser
vian troops. A few Servians are left
as garrisons along the frontier. One
lone Austrian army corps has escaped
and is now stationed in the middle of
the North Sea.
The havoc Is attributed to some
April Fool prank.
Another Instance of April Fool
thoughtfulness was shown this morn
ing when a member of the Agricul
tural faculty phoned to the county
jail asking "who had left a call for
him."</text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058393/1922-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=april+fools+pranks&st=text&r=-0.28,-0.078,1.56,1.56,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>BEDTIME STORIES
By HOWARD R. GARIS

USCLiE Wir.t.n A s LPRIL FOOL
JOKES,
Copyright. 1922, by McClure News
paper Syndicate.
"Oh. Uncle Wlggily! What's that
behind yo.U? I hope it isn't the Fuzzy
Ko!" cried Baby Bunty one morning.
The little rabbit girl had come over
to the hollow stump bungalow to
borrow a cup of flour.
"What's that? The Fuzzy Fox in
here?'" exclaimed the rabbit gen -Ionian,
and ho gave such a Jump that
ho nearly slipped over back ward
April fool!" laughed B... Bunty
"Oh!" exclaimed L'nclo WlggiB, BO
suddenly that his pink nose almost
stopped twinkling. "Oh. so this is the
first of April, is it?"
"Yes, and I caught you first ofj
all!" laughed Baby Bunty.
And so she had, for she had come
I over early to the hollow stump bun
galow on purpose to do this.
"Did I really make you think tho
Fuzzy Fox was there, Fncle Wig
glly?" asked Baby Bunty 'is the bun
nf gentleman snt down to his break
fast.
"You surely did for 3 moment." an
swered the bunny with a lui.Kh. "I
had no Idea this was April Fool Dsjy
But no matter. My turn will come,"
and he carried his glass of water to
the sink, spilling it out.
"Why did you do that"?" asked
Baby Bunty In surprise.
"Because," answered Uncle Wig
gily, "I have known it to happen m
times past that my glass of water on
April Fool morning would be full of
salt. As I don't want to drink salt
water now I lust emntiod mv rlaiu
1 11 fill It myself with fresh water."
"Oh there wasn't any salt in your
glasi suirl Nurse Jane
"No, added Baby Bunty. "I never
thought of that trick. I wish I had
But maybe Oh. Uncla Wlggily! Look
out!" she suddenly crlrd. "Is that a
pin in your chair?" 1
Uncle Wlggily Jumped up as If a
gun had gone off. Hfe looked In his
chair but there was nothing there.
"April Pool!" laughed Baby Bunly
again.
I'ncle Wlggily said nothing but he
sat down rather harfl and ate his
br. ik fast. And when linby Bunty said
"Oh. look out the window and see
who's coming!"
Undo Wlggily nevor looked up
from his morning paler. But some
one was coming along the, path to the
hollow stump bungaliw. They were
Curly and Floppy Twlltytail. tho plg
gle boys. Floppv had a llttlo bas
ket. "Do you want to look In this and
see what there Is?" asked Floppy, ns
ho and his brother camo In after
nrafl.lln U'lnfnr, II...I. r..l 1
'"h Ul. l Ull III'!
mat.
"Well. I can pretty nearly gu
what's In tho basket," said the bunny
gentleman It's some sneezing pow
der or a lot of dried leaves' You can't
April Fool me again."
"Oh. really, we wouldn't do such
thing!'1 grunted Ourl
"I'll open the basket!" cried Baby
Bunty. So she did, and inside was .1
lovely piece of cake that Mrs. Twisty
tall had sent to Uncle Wlgplly.
"April Fool!" grunted tho piggie
boys.
"Well, this Is a proper kind of April 1
T
Fool Joke!" said the bunny as he ate
the cako. which was very good. '''It
seems I can't be sure of anything this
morning." he told Nurse Jane when
tho children had run out and the
bunny was finishing his breakfast.
"You must he very careful." said
Miss Fuzzy Wuzzy
"I will," promised Uncle Wlggily,
and he was. But even at that a num
ber of- April Fool Jokes were played
on him nothing very serious though.
Once Jackie Bow Wow barked:
"Oil. is that 11 hlir hnil I n u..n
coat, Incle Wlggily?'' The bunnv
nearly twisted off his pink noso to
look at his back, but there was no
hole in his coat at all. Another time
Kittle Kat offered Uncle Wlggily
some candy, and when he chewed It,
Why It was sour Instead of sweet!
And Kittle mewed: '.pnl Fool."
"Well. I think it's my turnto play
an April Fool joko on some one,"'
said the bunny gentleman after a
while. "I wonder what I can do?
T want to play a real Joke'
He hopped along a llttlo farther
and, all of a sudden, out from be
hind a bush jumped he Bob Cat.
"Oh. ho!" howled the Bob Cat.
"Your ears look very good to me this
morning!"
"Do they"" asked I'ncle Wlggily.
Well, do you know what dav this
Is?"
"It makes no matter of difference
to me what day this is!" howled the
Bob Cat I on!y want
"Dear me' Look! Look behind
you! Is that a hunter man coming
with his gun?" suddenly asked Uncle
Wlggily, pretending to see something
back of the Bob 'at.
a hunter man with a gun! Oh,
don't tell me that! Don't tell mo
that!" howled the bad animal, and
away he ran as fast as ho could.
"I can't tell you that, for there
Isn't a hunter there!" laughed tho
bunny. "April Fool! April Fool!" And
lo h id played a Joke on the Bob Cat
just In time.
"Ha! Ha!" laughed the bunnv. as
ho hopped safely along. April Fool
Jokes aren't so bad after all'" And
If the pussy willow doesn't cry Jn the
night and want to bo rocked to sleep
in the cat's cradle, I'll tell vou next
about Uncle Wlggily and the .nrll
shower.
no
IF YOU ARE WELL BRED
You will not. if avoidable, call a
person on the phone Just at meal time
You will not listen in on the conver
sation on a party line.
You will not expect, a man who Is
talking to you out in the open to
stand with his hat off
HELPED HER MOTHER
VOM)i:i;iTI,lA
In these days of "rlii." coughs
colds, croup and whooping cough, it
Is well to know that every year ihcro
arc used more bottles of Foley's Honey
and Tar than of any other cough med
in. Mrs. S. L. Hunt. 515 W. 6th
St., Cincinnati. Ohio, writes: "Foley's
Honey and Tar relieved me of a hack
ing cough, tickling in the throat,
wheezing and pains in the ohest. It Is
helping my mother wonderfully."
That's why druggists- recommend Fo
ley's. Advertisement.
HWGS OF THE DUFFS Tu a m r i d
1 he APnl Fgo1 Boomerang BY ALLMAN
r ll DANMV, I UNDERSTAND THE MAW I'M cOIMG To PLAV ,Ul I i ia- H
Jl that rums the drug store APom Jlf- APRa Fool! YpT whatdioI dhm "wanted
In DOVMM AT THE CORNER 15 GNrA DANNY I TOLD HIM THE. "f I HAT HAVE VOU J VOU TELL A ?VH F
A wav A five Pound &ox of i druggist WAS giving mS. THEKEP JJJ. u,J,o CANDY AMD. ME A5KEP
JL CAKDV TO EACH LITTLE BOY )N J AWAV FIVE POUND BOXES) ,V .r T lU ME 5EWT ME" 1
THE NEIGHBORHOOD-YOU'D OF CANDY-HE'S GONE TO f -f I GOT IT TOLD HIM THAT YOU DID
l jl Riht! and he said all right</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1932-04-01/ed-1/?sp=47&q=april+fools+pranks&r=-0.173%2C0.021%2C0.796%2C0.449%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Some Reflections for April 1
BY LYDIA LE BARON WALKER.
APRIL first Is the one day In
year when persons suffer them
selves to be made fools of; no
that they relish it exactly evei
ao. but custom and a sense o
humor carry them through it withou
CT IS ONLY ON APRIL 1 THAT ONI
IS WILLINGLY A FOOL.
genuity deserves appreciation, and 1
may be added that this appreciation i:
seldom withheld. Children, of course
relish April fool's day absurdities, anc
their laughable little pranks are cause;
for adult merriment.
The historic method of fooling per
Ions was to send them on futile errands
Pools’ errands, these were called, anc
the term has become classic. Another
method of foolery was to send mock
gifts. Perhaps a bundle had nothing in
It, although neatly done up. Or should
an article be contained in the package
it was insignificant, or a ludicrous trav
esty of a present. These are the two
outstanding ways in which the fooling
was carried out in ancient times. It ir
from these that a general scheme for
outwitting persons on this special day
In the year has come about.
There is a spirit of merriment in
April fools’ pranks when they do not
savor too much of the obnoxious prac
tical Joke, which is annoying if not
actually unkindly or dangerous. It is
When one makes a fool of one’s self on
»1 ■'1
i this or any other day in the year that
there is cause for disturbance in one's
t own mind. Pew. indeed, are the persons
i who, looking over a past year on any
first day of April, are not aware of a
t certain smarting thought of some such
f times when one has made a fool of
one's self.
It may be that one has been quick
to think ungraciously of another and
has acted on such an idea, only to find
that a benefit accrued to herself, and
her whole judgment was hasty and un
kind. Temper may have been shown
over so simple a thing as a game of
bridge and a whole party may have
been disturbed just because one made
a fool of herself. Not a pleasant re
flection
Ypuths, even adults, who have ex
aminations or tests to pass, sometimes
feel if they cun fool the teacher or
examiner by "bluffing’' their way
through to pass that they have done
a clever thing. It is only when, later
on. they have the chance to profit by
their suppled knowledge, that they
realize it was they, themselves, who
were the real fools It was they, not
the examiners, who failed in their tasks.
I remember meeting a young Ameri
can in Paris who had. from her own
statement, ''bluffed” her way through
French. Her quick ear and eye evident
ly came to her aid in classes, as it was
doing in France, but not so successfully.
She was floundering in the maze of
irregular verbs and French Idioms par
ticularly. She said, "I thought I wes
fooling the teachers when I slid through
my French. Now I find it was myself,
not them, who was fooled.”</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014085/1935-04-09/ed-1/?sp=10&q=april+fools+pranks&r=-0.136%2C0.099%2C0.683%2C0.386%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Gustave Haensclten was
among the radio artists select
ed as the victims of April
Fool’s pranks. For years the
NBC composer-conductor has
fead loach served in his office,
and the menu always consist
ed of a salad, toasted crackers
and milk. Un April 1st the
restaurateur substituted a big
onion smothered with steak,
Ice-cream with pie on it, and
n cup of cream with coffee.
Gas retaliated by giving tlie
waiter the bill.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88063294/1942-03-29/ed-1/?sp=58&q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>April Fool s Day Horseplay Declines
As War-Torn World Shuns Frivolity
By LOUIS SOBOL
TN A world which prows more
serious by the hour, the spirit
of tomfoolery' is fadinp rapidly,
as might be expected.
Even before the war. the day
of the comic valentine was prac
tically over—and they tell me
that the kids in the little coun
try red wooden school houses
which, in most cases, are neither
red nor wooden, no longer place
mice in the teacher’s desk, pep
per in her apple and limburger
cheese in her pocketbook.
Under the circumstances, one
can understand why we no
longer put our heart, soul and
imaginative resources into April
Fool’s Day pranks.
A few of the hardier still
make telephone calls inviting
victims to parties at an address
which turns out to be either a
police station or the city
morgue.
Some send candies to girls
which will break off a tooth
when bitten into or will scorch
the mouth.
Stories Decline, Too
But thpir day, too, is coming
to a close.
Even the good old stories ai-e
fading.
One of the runs- l>eloved was
about the little t»oy who told hi>
mother please to come quickly,
“Father is kissing a strange
woman in his study.” and when
mother and little boy tip-toed
to the studv and mother flung
open the d*>or. the 1 ttle ltoy
rlapped his hands jumped up ar
down jubilantly and shout'd:
“April Fool! It’s not strung*
woman— lt** nursh
There is a iheor> that April 1
marked the ancient pagan feast
of the vernal equinox to cele
brate the passage of winter am;
the return of spring.
Naturally, in those days i*
raised the roof on an a ;occasion as ti :nd w.r,> wrt<
drunk and the c* b brants d
crazy things.
Sophisticated View
A more sophisticated hyp*
thesis is that April fool fog orig
noted in France during the rrugi
of Charles IX when, in obi,
new calendar was adopted mak
ing the beginning of the yea-
January 1 instead of April 1
Ax it was the rusfom of th<
country to exchange visits an*i
gifts on New Years Day.
wags, after the new calendar
PAGE 6
was in effect, invited people to
visit then as before on April J,
or send gifts.
When guests arrived they
found no preparations had been
made for Vhem.
jßr >m?jl* jjftk- W
m IPjf «J***V
fIK
€ipK'
j^TT
(’ARMAN D’ANTONIO is the savage dancer featuted in the musical
comedy, ‘‘Panama Hattie,” beginning its second week at the Cass Monday night.
PHAGE MID SCHE
(Charles Centra "fl
j a
Perhaps I’m too old to keep
close touch with the young—but
it seems to me they no longer
think it worth while to victimize
unsuspecting friends on a whole
sale scale.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
  </topic>

#Topic 2
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-women-aviation/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042373/1910-09-01/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Aviation+aviators+women&st=text&r=0.009,0.136,0.872,0.985,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>V«H:-
ii
By CHARLES N. LURIE.
SAID"Well,my
I to friend the woman
hater:
why shouldn't wom
en fly if they wish to do so?'
Said my friend the woman hater:
"No reason In the world. They 'go up
In the air* often enough."
So they, are going up in the air, as
the pictures show, but not In the sense
In which the misogynist used the
words. Aviation for women has reach
ed the point where the Parisian cos
turners are designing special costumes
for the sport or pastime or vocation
or avocation. That means that It Is
fast becoming 'an "institution." One
of the lady aviators is shown In the
picture garbed for a flight
What Shall We Call thsi Lady Flier?
"Lady aviators" brings up another
point. 'What shall we call the women
who are ascending in aeroplanes and
balloons? 8hall we refer to them as
avlatrlces (plural of avlatrix, of which
the masculine Is aviator), or shall we
adopt the suggestion of an English
magazine and refer to the fair fliers as
"aeroine*?" The latter suggestion hits
merit, but the word has one fatal de
fect—It is difficult of pronunciation.
From some mouths it will emerge' with
so close a resemblance to "heroines"
as to be mistaken for that word. Per
haps it is well to suggest a relation
ship between "heroine" and "aero
ine," since the latter Is undoubtedly
worthy of enrollment in the lists of
the former. At this, stage of the flying
game any woman wko' accomplishes a
flight Is surely a heroine.
Up to the date of writing there had
not- been many women aviators.
Italy had the Duchess of Aosta, cousin
by marriage of King Victor Emmanuel.
France^ in some respects the leader In
aviation and in many respects the
world's mentor in "feminism," had only
three prominent lady fliers—Baroness
de la Roche, Incapacitated for an in
definite length of time by very serious
WHEN
the government of
th* United States want*
Information on military
matters to whom does It
turn? To the .same man to whom the
state of Ohio look* for advice and
guidance In regard, to its citizen sol
diers.- And that man I* Major General
Charles William Frederick Dick. Don't
recognize th* name? Well, you are
not to be blamed. When the name of
the senior aenator from Ohio 1* printed
In It* usual form the two middle sec
tions are cut out and th* name pro-
4^^ '»vr
IM
I...:.
Tt
*'C
1
••jk ii MAJOR GENERAL DICK AND STAFF.
ceed* on the main line as Senator
Charles Dick of Ohio. If Dick were
an Englishman he would be known as
Major General th* Honorable Charles
William Frederick Dick. But H* I* not
a Britisher, only a plain—very plal*.
In fact—0)iloan, who sheds luster on th*
title of Unlte*8taU» senator by add
ing to It that of major general In th*
Ohio national guard.
Com* to think of IV major gwMMls
are *caro* ln th* **nat* these day*,
pick I* th* on|y on* at pi«*ent now In
active service, and hte title Is only a
militia on*, after all. Pressing him
injuries dueto a fait lime. Franck.
also "injured JuBt after she had an
nounced her Intention of making a
flight across the English channel, and
Mme. Paulhan, wife of the famous
tiouls. There have been a few others,
but their exploits have attracted lit
tle attention. England has two or
three women fliers In heavier than air
machines. Germany has produced no
women fliers of note—none, that is. In
aeroplanes. The Zeppelin, Parseval
and Gross dirigible balloons have had
female passengers In some of their fa
mous flights. In America we have had
Hiss K»therlne Wright, Mrs. Hart O.
Berg, Mrs. Cortland Field Bishop,
Mrs. Clifford B. Harmon, Mrs. Wil
liam K. Vanderbllt, Jr., and a few
others as passengers with the "man
birds" when they made flights above
the earth. Mrs. Bishop was the first
woman to fly In America. But no
American woman so far as known has
been daring enough to go aloft as an
aviator. That will come In time, no
doubt, and in the meanwhile we may
rest content with the fact that we have
the only genuine, bona fide woman
airship Inventor on earth. She is
worth a separate paragraph.
Only Woman Airship Inventor.
The name of the lady is Miss E.
Lillian Todd, and her postofllce address
is New York. She Is called 'probably
the first woman In the world to de
sign and build an aeroplane" all by
herself. The Todd machine was a col
lapsible or folding aeroplane, and the
fact of Its existence was first made
public two years ago, Since that time
Miss Todd has kept busy designing
and making improvements to her aero
plane. She Is a member of the Aero
Club of America and one of the found
ers of the Junior Aero club, which
aims at teaching the young American
idea how to fly. Miss Todd has the
added distinction 'of being the builder
of her flying machine as well as Its
Inventor. Recently she had the good
fortune to attract the notice of Mrs.
Russell Sage, and It was announced</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
  </topic>

#Topic 3
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id> </id>
        <rel> </rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
  </topic>
</topics>